<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 02:45:13 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Mammary intraepithelial lymphocytes promote lactogenesis and offspring fitness</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39954680/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Breastfeeding is an obligatory requirement of mammalian survival. This fundamental process is associated with the adaptation of maternal physiology, including the transformation of the mammary gland into a milk-secreting organ. How maternal immunity contributes to mammary gland remodeling and function remains largely unknown. Here, we show that maternal adaptive immunity plays a critical role in shaping lactogenesis. Specifically, physiological adaptation during pregnancy is associated with...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 11:S0092-8674(25)00097-2. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.028. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Breastfeeding is an obligatory requirement of mammalian survival. This fundamental process is associated with the adaptation of maternal physiology, including the transformation of the mammary gland into a milk-secreting organ. How maternal immunity contributes to mammary gland remodeling and function remains largely unknown. Here, we show that maternal adaptive immunity plays a critical role in shaping lactogenesis. Specifically, physiological adaptation during pregnancy is associated with thymic involution and a paradoxical enrichment in intraepithelial lymphocyte (IEL) precursors that no longer migrate to the gut but instead preferentially accumulate within the mammary gland. IEL precursors differentiate into T-bet-expressing unconventional CD8αα lymphocytes in an IL-15-dependent manner. Mammary IELs control milk production by favoring the differentiation and maturation of contractile and milk-secreting cells, thereby promoting offspring fitness. Altogether, this work uncovers a contribution of the maternal adaptive immune system in organismal remodeling during pregnancy that is associated with mammary gland development and function.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39954680/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39954680</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.028>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.028</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39954680</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dan Corral</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eduard Ansaldo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jérémie Delaleu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrea C Pichler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Juraj Kabat</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cihan Oguz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ana Teijeiro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel Yong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mahnoor Abid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Claudia A Rivera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Verena M Link</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katharine Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liang Chi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jia Nie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olena Kamenyeva</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yiping Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jerry Kok Yen Chan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Florent Ginhoux</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rémy Bosselut</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yasmine Belkaid</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Mammary intraepithelial lymphocytes promote lactogenesis and offspring fitness</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39954680</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.028</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Male-male interactions shape mate selection in Drosophila</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952248/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Males of many species have evolved behavioral traits to both attract females and repel rivals. Here, we explore mate selection in Drosophila from both the male and female perspective to shed light on how these key components of sexual selection-female choice and male-male competition-work in concert to guide reproductive strategies. We find that male flies fend off competing suitors by interleaving their courtship of a female with aggressive wing flicks, which both repel competitors and generate...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 11:S0092-8674(25)00037-6. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.008. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Males of many species have evolved behavioral traits to both attract females and repel rivals. Here, we explore mate selection in Drosophila from both the male and female perspective to shed light on how these key components of sexual selection-female choice and male-male competition-work in concert to guide reproductive strategies. We find that male flies fend off competing suitors by interleaving their courtship of a female with aggressive wing flicks, which both repel competitors and generate a "song" that obscures the female's auditory perception of other potential mates. Two higher-order circuit nodes-P1a and pC1x neurons-are coordinately recruited to allow males to flexibly interleave these agonistic actions with courtship displays, assuring they persistently pursue females until their rival falters. Together, our results suggest that female mating decisions are shaped by male-male interactions, underscoring how a male's ability to subvert his rivals is central to his reproductive success.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952248/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39952248</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.008>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.008</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39952248</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tom Hindmarsh Sten</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rufei Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Florian Hollunder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shade Eleazer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vanessa Ruta</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Male-male interactions shape mate selection in Drosophila</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39952248</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.008</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Synonymous mutations promote tumorigenesis by disrupting m&lt;sup>;6&lt;/sup>;A-dependent mRNA metabolism</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952247/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cancer cells acquire numerous mutations during tumorigenesis, including synonymous mutations that do not change the amino acid sequence of a protein. RNA N6-methyladenosine (m⁶A) is a post-transcriptional modification that plays critical roles in oncogenesis. Herein, we identified 12,849 mutations in the cancer genome with the potential to perturb m⁶A modification patterns, which we refer to as "m⁶A disruption mutations (m⁶A-DMs)." These are either synonymous m⁶A-DMs (sm⁶A-DMs) or missense...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 11:S0092-8674(25)00095-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.026. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cancer cells acquire numerous mutations during tumorigenesis, including synonymous mutations that do not change the amino acid sequence of a protein. RNA N6-methyladenosine (m<sup>6</sup>A) is a post-transcriptional modification that plays critical roles in oncogenesis. Herein, we identified 12,849 mutations in the cancer genome with the potential to perturb m<sup>6</sup>A modification patterns, which we refer to as "m<sup>6</sup>A disruption mutations (m<sup>6</sup>A-DMs)." These are either synonymous m<sup>6</sup>A-DMs (sm<sup>6</sup>A-DMs) or missense m<sup>6</sup>A-DMs (mm<sup>6</sup>A-DMs) mutations, and the former is enriched within tumor suppressor genes, such as CDKN2A and BRCA2. Using epitranscriptomic editing, we demonstrate that manipulating m<sup>6</sup>A levels at specific sm<sup>6</sup>A-DM sites influences mRNA stability. Furthermore, introducing CDKN2A sm<sup>6</sup>A-DMs into cancer cells promotes tumor growth while BRCA2 sm<sup>6</sup>A-DMs sensitize tumors to the poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitor (PARPi) treatment. Our findings demonstrate sm<sup>6</sup>A-DMs as potential oncogenic drivers, unveiling implications for synonymous mutations in tumorigenesis and beyond.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952247/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39952247</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.026>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.026</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39952247</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yiheng Lan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhen Xia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qizhe Shao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peng Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinhong Lu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoying Xiao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mengyue Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Di Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanmei Dou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qi Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Synonymous mutations promote tumorigenesis by disrupting m&lt;sup>;6&lt;/sup>;A-dependent mRNA metabolism</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39952247</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.026</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Design of CoQ&lt;sub>;10&lt;/sub>; crops based on evolutionary history</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952246/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Coenzyme Q (CoQ) is essential for energy production by mitochondrial respiration, and it is a supplement most often used to promote cardiovascular health. Humans make CoQ(10), but cereals and some vegetable/fruit crops synthesize CoQ(9) with a side chain of nine isoprene units. Engineering CoQ(10) production in crops would benefit human health, but this is hindered by the fact that the specific residues of the enzyme Coq1 that control chain length are unknown. Based on an extensive investigation...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 11:S0092-8674(25)00087-X. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.023. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Coenzyme Q (CoQ) is essential for energy production by mitochondrial respiration, and it is a supplement most often used to promote cardiovascular health. Humans make CoQ<sub>10</sub>, but cereals and some vegetable/fruit crops synthesize CoQ<sub>9</sub> with a side chain of nine isoprene units. Engineering CoQ<sub>10</sub> production in crops would benefit human health, but this is hindered by the fact that the specific residues of the enzyme Coq1 that control chain length are unknown. Based on an extensive investigation of the distribution of CoQ<sub>9</sub> and CoQ<sub>10</sub> in land plants and the associated Coq1 sequence variation, we identified key amino acid changes at the base of the Coq1 catalytic pocket that occurred independently in multiple angiosperm lineages and repeatedly drove CoQ<sub>9</sub> formation. Guided by this knowledge, we used gene editing to modify the native Coq1 genes of rice and wheat to produce CoQ<sub>10</sub>, paving the way for developing additional dietary sources of CoQ<sub>10</sub>.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952246/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39952246</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.023>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.023</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39952246</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jing-Jing Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuan Lei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiao-Fan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jian-Xu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qiupeng Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiang-Dong Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yu-Guo Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenyi Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Runtong Qian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shu-Yi Xiong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kuo Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yu Jia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qiang Zhou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hang Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan-Bo Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ling-Jian Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ji-Yun Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yu Kong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qing Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinxing Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yong-Hong Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuai Zhan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Caixia Gao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiao-Ya Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Design of CoQ&lt;sub>;10&lt;/sub>; crops based on evolutionary history</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39952246</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.023</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Current status of aortic valve repair surgery</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950993/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Severe aortic valve regurgitation, if not timely treated, can significantly impact patients' survival both for tricuspid aortic valve and bicuspid aortic valve patients, with the latter being significantly younger. Increased understanding of the root anatomy and its physiology has opened the way to techniques of aortic valve repair surgery. The techniques mainly relate to re-establishing a correct root and annular geometry and eliminating leaflet prolapse. These techniques are applied both in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14:ehaf038. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf038. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Severe aortic valve regurgitation, if not timely treated, can significantly impact patients' survival both for tricuspid aortic valve and bicuspid aortic valve patients, with the latter being significantly younger. Increased understanding of the root anatomy and its physiology has opened the way to techniques of aortic valve repair surgery. The techniques mainly relate to re-establishing a correct root and annular geometry and eliminating leaflet prolapse. These techniques are applied both in the presence of a dilated and normal root and are equally valid for tricuspid or bicuspid valve. Techniques for repairing a bicuspid valve might vary depending on the different valve phenotypes. Medium and long-term results appear favourable and potentially superior to those of prosthetic replacement in terms of valve-related complications and quality of life. Optimal surgical treatment, especially in younger and selected patients, should aim to avoid aortic valve replacement and its related complications.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950993/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950993</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf038>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf038</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950993</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ruggero De Paulis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ilaria Chirichilli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laurent de Kerchove</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alessandro Della Corte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gebrine El Khoury</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hector I Michelena</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrea Salica</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hans-Joachim Schäfers</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Current status of aortic valve repair surgery</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950993</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf038</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Expanding the triglyceride range in clinical trials: therapeutic opportunities</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950981/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Individuals with mild-to-moderate hypertriglyceridaemia may not express the same magnitude of cardiovascular risk as that observed across the full range of plasma triglycerides. Future triglyceride-lowering therapy trials may want to consider enrolment across a wider range of triglyceride levels if there is no prior history of pancreatitis nor excessive alcohol intake.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14:ehaf074. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf074. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Guidelines focus on individuals with triglycerides between 2.3 and 5.6 mmol/L (200 and 499 mg/dL). The hypotheses that triglycerides across the full biological range and within this constrained range associated with cardiovascular risk were re-assessed.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Multivariable-adjusted hazard ratios for major cardiovascular events and death according to baseline triglycerides among 119 573 individuals with triglycerides across the full biological range from the Copenhagen General Population Study, among 27 757 individuals with baseline triglycerides between 2.3 and 5.6 mmol/L from the Copenhagen General Population Study and the Women's Health Study cohorts, and among 31 272 individuals with mild-to-moderate hypertriglyceridaemia from the PROMINENT, REDUCE-IT, and STRENGTH trials were calculated.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Increasing triglycerides across the full range (0.3 to 11.2 mmol/L) were associated with an increasing risk of major cardiovascular events (N = 12 241). In the cohorts, combined hazard ratios [95% confidence interval (triglyceride range in mmol/L)] for major cardiovascular events (N = 3928) from lowest to highest triglyceride quartile were 1.0 [referent (range: &lt; 2.5)], 0.95 [0.87-1.04 (range: 2.5 to &lt;3.0)], 1.04 [0.95-1.13 (range: 3.0 to &lt;3.6)], and 1.13 [1.04-1.23 (range: ≥ 3.6)]. In the three contemporary trials, the corresponding hazard ratios (N = 4265 cardiovascular events) from lowest to highest quartile were 1.0 [referent (ranges for PROMINENT/REDUCE-IT/STRENGTH: &lt; 2.6/2.0/2.2)], 1.01 [0.93-1.10 (ranges: 2.6 to &lt;3.1/2.0 to &lt;2.5/2.2 to &lt;2.7)], 1.05 [0.96-1.14 (ranges: 3.1 to &lt;3.9/2.5 to &lt;3.1/2.7 to &lt; 3.5)] and 1.09 [1.00-1.19 (ranges: ≥ 3.9/3.1/3.5)]. In neither cohorts nor trials were triglycerides across this range strongly associated with risk of cardiovascular or all-cause death.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Individuals with mild-to-moderate hypertriglyceridaemia may not express the same magnitude of cardiovascular risk as that observed across the full range of plasma triglycerides. Future triglyceride-lowering therapy trials may want to consider enrolment across a wider range of triglyceride levels if there is no prior history of pancreatitis nor excessive alcohol intake.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950981/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950981</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf074>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf074</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950981</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ask T Nordestgaard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aruna D Pradhan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brendan M Everett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jean G MacFadyen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Deepak L Bhatt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frank L J Visseren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter Libby</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Raul D Santos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Steven E Nissen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Børge G Nordestgaard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul M Ridker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Expanding the triglyceride range in clinical trials: therapeutic opportunities</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950981</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf074</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Weekly Journal Scan: transcatheter vs. surgical treatment of combined severe aortic valve stenosis and obstructive coronary artery disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950980/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14:ehaf023. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf023. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950980/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950980</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf023>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf023</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950980</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rocco Vergallo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniela Pedicino</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Weekly Journal Scan: transcatheter vs. surgical treatment of combined severe aortic valve stenosis and obstructive coronary artery disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950980</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf023</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The potential role of apolipoprotein A-1 amyloid in aortic dissection</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950978/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14:ehaf096. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf096. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950978/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950978</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf096>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf096</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950978</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hiroyuki Otsuka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nobuhiro Tahara</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eiki Tayama</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>The potential role of apolipoprotein A-1 amyloid in aortic dissection</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950978</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf096</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>How can we counsel patients desiring subsequent pregnancy after peripartum cardiomyopathy?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950969/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14:ehae888. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae888. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950969/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950969</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae888>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae888</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950969</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Olayinka Agboola</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Garima Sharma</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>How can we counsel patients desiring subsequent pregnancy after peripartum cardiomyopathy?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950969</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae888</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cardiomyocyte PRL2 Promotes Cardiac Hypertrophy via Directly Dephosphorylating AMPKα2</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950300/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: This study reveals that PRL2, as a novel AMPK-regulating phosphatase, promotes mitochondrial instability and hypertrophic injury in cardiomyocytes and provides PLR2 as a potential target for future drug development treating heart failure.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Feb 14. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325262. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Pathological cardiac hypertrophy can result in heart failure. Protein dephosphorylation plays a primary role in the mediation of various cellular processes in cardiomyocytes. Here, we investigated the effects of a protein tyrosine phosphatase, PRL2 (phosphatase of regenerative liver 2), on pathological cardiac hypertrophy.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: The PRL2 knockout mice were subjected to angiotensin II infusion or transverse aortic constriction to induce myocardial hypertrophy and cardiac dysfunction. RNA-sequencing analysis was performed to explore the underlying mechanisms. Mass spectrometry and bio-layer interferometry assays were used to identify AMPKα2 (AMP-activated protein kinase α2) as an interacting protein of PRL2. Mutant plasmids of AMPKα2 were used to clarify how PRL2 interacts and dephosphorylates AMPKα2.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A significant upregulation of PRL2 was observed in hypertrophic myocardium tissues in mice and patients with heart failure. PRL2 deficiency alleviated cardiac hypertrophy, fibrosis, and dysfunction in mice challenged with angiotensin II infusion or transverse aortic constriction. Transcriptomic and biochemical analyses showed that PRL2 knockout or silence maintained AMPK<sup>T172</sup> phosphorylation and subsequent mitochondrial integrity in angiotensin II-challenged heart tissues or cardiomyocytes. Mass spectrometry-based interactome assay indicated AMPKα2 subunit as the substrate of PRL2. Mechanistically, PRL2 binds to the C-terminal domain of AMPKα2 and then dephosphorylates AMPKα2<sup>T172</sup> via its active site C46. Adeno-associated virus 9-mediated deficiency of cardiomyocyte PRL2 also protected cardiac mitochondrial function and showed cardioprotective effects in angiotensin II-challenged mice, but these benefits were not observed in AMPKα2<sup>-/-</sup> mice.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: This study reveals that PRL2, as a novel AMPK-regulating phosphatase, promotes mitochondrial instability and hypertrophic injury in cardiomyocytes and provides PLR2 as a potential target for future drug development treating heart failure.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39950300/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39950300</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325262>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325262</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39950300</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xue Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qiaojuan Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yu Tu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiajia Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mengyang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weiqi Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruyi Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiajia Wei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shiju Ye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanmei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bozhi Ye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huazhong Ying</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guang Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cardiomyocyte PRL2 Promotes Cardiac Hypertrophy via Directly Dephosphorylating AMPKα2</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39950300</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325262</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Focus on aortic stenosis prevention and mitral regurgitation diagnosis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947236/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 14;46(7):595-597. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf015.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947236/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39947236</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf015>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39947236</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Focus on aortic stenosis prevention and mitral regurgitation diagnosis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39947236</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf015</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Resistance to Striga parasitism through reduction of strigolactone exudation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947180/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Parasitism with Striga poses a major threat to global food production. Striga germination and growth rely on strigolactones (SLs) exuded by crop roots under phosphate (Pi)-deficient conditions, although the mechanism of this host-parasite interaction remains elusive. In this study, transcriptomic and functional analyses of sorghum treated with Pi deficiency or the SL GR24^(5DS) identify two ABC transporter G (ABCG) transporters of SL, Sorghum biocolor strigolactones transporter 1 (SbSLT1) and...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 4:S0092-8674(25)00086-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.022. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Parasitism with Striga poses a major threat to global food production. Striga germination and growth rely on strigolactones (SLs) exuded by crop roots under phosphate (Pi)-deficient conditions, although the mechanism of this host-parasite interaction remains elusive. In this study, transcriptomic and functional analyses of sorghum treated with Pi deficiency or the SL GR24<sup>5DS</sup> identify two ABC transporter G (ABCG) transporters of SL, Sorghum biocolor strigolactones transporter 1 (SbSLT1) and SbSLT2. Using AlphaFold2 and amino acid conversion mutants, we identify highly conserved amino acids in SL transport channels essential for transport function. Sorghum lines with single or double knockouts of these transporters exhibit significantly reduced SL secretion from roots, leading to decreased Striga germination and parasitism in field experiments and consequently reducing the grain loss under Striga infestation. This study thus describes the mechanism of SL exudation in monocots and defines conserved residues essential for SL transporter function, offering a potential strategy for enhancing crop resistance to Striga parasitism.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947180/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39947180</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.022>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.022</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39947180</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jiayang Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cuo Mei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fengyong Ge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qingliang Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinwei Ban</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ran Xia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peiyong Xin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shujing Cheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gaohua Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiawei Nie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shiqi Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaowei Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinfang Chu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuhang Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bing Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weihua Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiayang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qi Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Feifei Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Resistance to Striga parasitism through reduction of strigolactone exudation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39947180</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.022</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ArfGAP2 promotes STING proton channel activity, cytokine transit, and autoinflammation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947179/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) transmits signals downstream of the cytosolic DNA sensor cyclic guanosine monophosphate-AMP synthase (cGAS), leading to transcriptional upregulation of cytokines. However, components of the STING signaling pathway, such as IRF3 and IFNAR1, are not essential for autoinflammatory disease in STING gain-of-function (STING-associated vasculopathy with onset in infancy [SAVI]) mice. Recent discoveries revealed that STING also functions as a proton channel that...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 5:S0092-8674(25)00096-0. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.027. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Stimulator of interferon genes (STING) transmits signals downstream of the cytosolic DNA sensor cyclic guanosine monophosphate-AMP synthase (cGAS), leading to transcriptional upregulation of cytokines. However, components of the STING signaling pathway, such as IRF3 and IFNAR1, are not essential for autoinflammatory disease in STING gain-of-function (STING-associated vasculopathy with onset in infancy [SAVI]) mice. Recent discoveries revealed that STING also functions as a proton channel that deacidifies the Golgi apparatus. Because pH impacts Golgi enzyme activity, protein maturation, and trafficking, we hypothesized that STING proton channel activity influences multiple Golgi functions. Here, we show that STING-mediated proton efflux non-transcriptionally regulates Golgi trafficking of protein cargos. This process requires the Golgi-associated protein ArfGAP2, a cell-type-specific dual regulator of STING-mediated proton efflux and signaling. Deletion of ArfGAP2 in hematopoietic and endothelial cells markedly reduces STING-mediated cytokine and chemokine secretion, immune cell activation, and autoinflammatory pathology in SAVI mice. Thus, ArfGAP2 facilitates STING-mediated signaling and cytokine release in hematopoietic cells, significantly contributing to autoinflammatory disease pathogenesis.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39947179/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39947179</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.027>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.027</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39947179</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Subhajit Poddar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel D Chauvin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher H Archer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Qian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jean A Castillo-Badillo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xin Yin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>W Miguel Disbennett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cathrine A Miner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joe A Holley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Teresa V Naismith</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>W Alexander Stinson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaochao Wei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yue Ning</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiayuan Fu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Trini A Ochoa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nehalee Surve</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shivam A Zaver</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kimberly A Wodzanowski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katherine R Balka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rajan Venkatraman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Canyu Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kelly Rome</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Will Bailis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yoko Shiba</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sara Cherry</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sunny Shin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clay F Semenkovich</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dominic De Nardo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sunnie Yoh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elisha D O Roberson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sumit K Chanda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David J Kast</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jonathan J Miner</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>ArfGAP2 promotes STING proton channel activity, cytokine transit, and autoinflammation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39947179</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.027</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fiber, Fatty Acids, and Blood Pressure: A Gut-Level Solution</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946444/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Feb 14;136(4):358-360. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326065. Epub 2025 Feb 13.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946444/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39946444</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326065>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326065</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39946444</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mohd Mabood Khan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Annet Kirabo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Fiber, Fatty Acids, and Blood Pressure: A Gut-Level Solution</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39946444</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326065</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mineral Stress and Vascular Aging: Decoding the Epigenetic Connection to Slow the Clock</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946443/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Feb 14;136(4):400-402. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326064. Epub 2025 Feb 13.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946443/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39946443</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326064>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326064</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39946443</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Qian Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lifang Ye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey J Hsu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Mineral Stress and Vascular Aging: Decoding the Epigenetic Connection to Slow the Clock</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39946443</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326064</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Meet the First Authors</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946442/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Feb 14;136(4):355-357. doi: 10.1161/RES.0000000000000709. Epub 2025 Feb 13.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946442/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39946442</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/RES.0000000000000709>10.1161/RES.0000000000000709</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39946442</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Meet the First Authors</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39946442</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/RES.0000000000000709</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Deciphering Platelets: Are They Cells or an Evolved Form of Extracellular Vesicles?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946441/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Platelets are abundant in blood, where they maintain the integrity of the vasculature. Megakaryocytes, the cells responsible for platelet genesis, produce membrane protrusions from which as many as 5000 anucleate platelets can be released into the bloodstream. Platelets lack genomic DNA but contain different molecules, such as RNA, as well as organelles transmitted from the parent megakaryocyte. There is no consensus in the scientific community on whether platelets are cells or not: for example,...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Feb 14;136(4):442-452. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324721. Epub 2025 Feb 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Platelets are abundant in blood, where they maintain the integrity of the vasculature. Megakaryocytes, the cells responsible for platelet genesis, produce membrane protrusions from which as many as 5000 anucleate platelets can be released into the bloodstream. Platelets lack genomic DNA but contain different molecules, such as RNA, as well as organelles transmitted from the parent megakaryocyte. There is no consensus in the scientific community on whether platelets are cells or not: for example, they are sometimes called cells, small cells, anucleated cells, cell fragments, or megakaryocyte fragments. Extracellular vesicles are particles delimited by a lipid bilayer that are released from cells but cannot replicate on their own. Like platelets, extracellular vesicles lack a nucleus and carry components from their donor cell. Herein, we will explore various viewpoints suggesting that platelets may be cells, albeit not conventional cells, or may be a previously unrecognized type of extracellular vesicle. Beyond a mere debate over terminology, this perspective seeks to help properly define and classify platelets, aiming for better integration into the concept of either cells or extracellular vesicles. This will foster a clearer understanding and drive advances in platelet research.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39946441/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39946441</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324721>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324721</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39946441</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Eric Boilard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dylan Burger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Edit Buzas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paolo Gresele</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kellie R Machlus</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nigel Mackman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pia Siljander</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rienk Nieuwland</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Deciphering Platelets: Are They Cells or an Evolved Form of Extracellular Vesicles?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39946441</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324721</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cardiovascular Disease in Anabolic Androgenic Steroid Users</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945117/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: AAS use is associated with a substantially increased risk of cardiovascular disease in a large cohort with a long follow-up period.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 13. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071117. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Use of anabolic androgenic steroids (AASs) is associated with increased mortality, and case reports have suggested that some of these deaths are due to cardiovascular disease. However, the epidemiology of cardiovascular disease in AAS users is still relatively unexplored. This study aimed to measure the incidence of cardiovascular disease in male AAS users and to compare these rates with those of a cohort from the general population matched by age and sex.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Men sanctioned in an antidoping program for AAS use in Danish fitness centers between 2006 and 2018 were included and matched for age and sex with 50 times as many controls from the general Danish population. The cohort was followed until June 30, 2023. Using the nationwide registries, we obtained information on admissions, prescriptions, educational length, and occupational status for both the AAS users and controls. This study investigated the incidence of acute myocardial infarction, percutaneous coronary intervention, or coronary artery bypass graft, venous thromboembolism, ischemic stroke, arrhythmia, cardiomyopathy, heart failure, and cardiac arrest during the follow-up period.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: During an average of 11 years of follow-up, AAS users (n=1189) demonstrated a significantly higher incidence of several cardiovascular events compared with controls (n=59 450). Correspondingly, AASs were associated with an increased risk of acute myocardial infarction (adjusted hazard ratio [aHR] 3.00 [95% CI, 1.67-5.39]), percutaneous coronary intervention or coronary artery bypass graft (aHR 2.95 [95% CI, 1.68-5.18]), venous thromboembolism (aHR 2.42 [95% CI, 1.54-3.80]), arrhythmias (aHR 2.26 [95% CI, 1.53-3.32]), cardiomyopathy (aHR 8.90 [95% CI, 4.99-15.88]), and heart failure (aHR 3.63 [95% CI, 2.01-6.55]). Due to the limited number of ischemic stroke and cardiac arrest cases among AAS users, these outcomes were not reportable.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: AAS use is associated with a substantially increased risk of cardiovascular disease in a large cohort with a long follow-up period.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945117/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39945117</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071117>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071117</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39945117</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Josefine Windfeld-Mathiasen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ida M Heerfordt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kim Peder Dalhoff</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jon Trærup Andersen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Asger Andersen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karl Sebastian Johansson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tor Biering-Sørensen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Flemming Javier Olsen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Henrik Horwitz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cardiovascular Disease in Anabolic Androgenic Steroid Users</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39945117</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.071117</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Evolution of Critical Care Cardiology: An Update on Structure, Care Delivery, Training, and Research Paradigms: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945062/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Critical care cardiology refers to the practice focus of and subspecialty training for the comprehensive management of life-threatening cardiovascular diseases and comorbid conditions that require advanced critical care in an intensive care unit. The development of coronary care units is often credited for a dramatic decline in mortality rates after acute myocardial infarction throughout the 1960s. As the underlying patient population became progressively sicker, changes in organizational...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 13. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001300. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Critical care cardiology refers to the practice focus of and subspecialty training for the comprehensive management of life-threatening cardiovascular diseases and comorbid conditions that require advanced critical care in an intensive care unit. The development of coronary care units is often credited for a dramatic decline in mortality rates after acute myocardial infarction throughout the 1960s. As the underlying patient population became progressively sicker, changes in organizational structure, staffing, care delivery, and training paradigms lagged. The coronary care unit gradually evolved from a focus on rapid resuscitation from ventricular arrhythmias in acute myocardial infarction into a comprehensive cardiac intensive care unit designed to care for the sickest patients with cardiovascular disease. Over the past decade, the cardiac intensive care unit has continued to transform with an aging population, increased clinical acuity, burgeoning cardiac and noncardiac comorbidities, technologic advances in cardiovascular interventions, and increased use of temporary mechanical circulatory support devices. Herein, we provide an update and contemporary expert perspective on the organizational structure, staffing, and care delivery in the cardiac intensive care unit; examine the challenges and opportunities present in the education and training of the next generation of physicians for critical care cardiology; and explore quality improvement initiatives and scientific investigation, including multicenter registry initiatives and randomized clinical trials, that may change clinical practice, care delivery, and the research landscape in this rapidly evolving discipline.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945062/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39945062</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001300>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001300</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39945062</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shashank S Sinha</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bram J Geller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jason N Katz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cynthia Arslanian-Engoren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher F Barnett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erin A Bohula</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Abdulla A Damluji</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Venu Menon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert O Roswell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saraschandra Vallabhajosyula</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amanda R Vest</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sean van Diepen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David A Morrow</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Acute Cardiac Care and General Cardiology Committee of the Council on Clinical Cardiology; Council on Cardiopulmonary, Critical Care, Perioperative and Resuscitation; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; and Council on Kidney in Cardiovascular Disease</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Evolution of Critical Care Cardiology: An Update on Structure, Care Delivery, Training, and Research Paradigms: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39945062</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001300</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Novel Directly Reprogrammed Smooth Muscle Cells Promote Vascular Regeneration as Microvascular Mural Cells</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945059/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: A combination of myocardin and all-trans retinoic acid in defined culture conditions efficiently reprogrammed human fibroblasts into contractile and functional SMCs. The rSMCs were shown to be effective for vascular repair and contributed to neovascularization through mural cells and various paracrine effects. These human rSMCs could represent a novel source for cell-based therapy and research.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 13. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070217. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Although cell therapy has emerged as a promising approach to promote neovascularization, its effects are mostly limited to capillaries. To generate larger or stable vessels, layering of mural cells such as smooth muscle cells (SMCs) or pericytes is required. Recently, direct reprogramming approaches have been developed for generating SMCs. However, such reprogrammed SMCs lack genuine features of contractile SMCs, a native SMC phenotype; thus, their therapeutic and vessel-forming potential in vivo was not explored. Therefore, we aimed to directly reprogram human dermal fibroblasts toward contractile SMCs (rSMCs) and investigated their role for generating vascular mural cells in vivo and their therapeutic effects on ischemic disease.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We applied myocardin and all-<i>trans</i> retinoic acid with specific culture conditions to directly reprogram human dermal fibroblasts into rSMCs. We characterized their phenotype as contractile SMCs through quantitative reverse-transcriptase polymerase chain reaction, flow cytometry, and immunostaining. We then explored their contractility using a vasoconstrictor, carbachol, and through transmission electron microscope and bulk RNA sequencing. Next, we evaluated whether transplantation of rSMCs improves blood flow and induces vessel formation as mural cells in a mouse model of hind-limb ischemia with laser Doppler perfusion imaging and histological analysis. We also determined their paracrine effects.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Our novel culture conditions using myocardin and all-<i>trans</i> retinoic acid efficiently reprogrammed human dermal fibroblasts into SMCs. These rSMCs displayed characteristics of contractile SMCs at the mRNA, protein, and cellular levels. Transplantation of rSMCs into ischemic mouse hind limbs enhanced blood flow recovery and vascular repair and improved limb salvage. Histological examination showed that vascular density was increased and the engrafted rSMCs were incorporated into the vascular wall as pericytes and vascular SMCs, thereby contributing to formation of stabler and larger microvessels. Quantitative reverse-transcriptase polymerase chain reaction analysis revealed that these transplanted rSMCs exerted pleiotropic effects, including angiogenic, arteriogenic, vessel-stabilizing, and tissue regenerative effects, on ischemic limbs.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: A combination of myocardin and all-<i>trans</i> retinoic acid in defined culture conditions efficiently reprogrammed human fibroblasts into contractile and functional SMCs. The rSMCs were shown to be effective for vascular repair and contributed to neovascularization through mural cells and various paracrine effects. These human rSMCs could represent a novel source for cell-based therapy and research.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39945059/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39945059</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070217>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070217</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39945059</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cholomi Jung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ji Woong Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shin-Jeong Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kyung Hee Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jee Eun Oh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seongho Bae</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sangho Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Young-Jae Nam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sangsung Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chaewon Dang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jaehyun Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nakhyung Chu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eun Jig Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Young-Sup Yoon</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Novel Directly Reprogrammed Smooth Muscle Cells Promote Vascular Regeneration as Microvascular Mural Cells</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39945059</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070217</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Therapeutic left-to-right shunting in heart failure</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39943738/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250216214512&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Heart failure with reduced or preserved ejection fraction are both associated with elevated left atrial pressure at rest due to fluid overload or during exercise, leading to pulmonary venous congestion. Even with available treatments, heart failure hospitalizations remain high, and improvements in quality-of-life scores and functional capacity are modest. Thus, there is growing interest in non-pharmacological methods to decompress the left atrium and improve heart failure symptoms and outcomes....</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 13:ehaf120. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf120. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Heart failure with reduced or preserved ejection fraction are both associated with elevated left atrial pressure at rest due to fluid overload or during exercise, leading to pulmonary venous congestion. Even with available treatments, heart failure hospitalizations remain high, and improvements in quality-of-life scores and functional capacity are modest. Thus, there is growing interest in non-pharmacological methods to decompress the left atrium and improve heart failure symptoms and outcomes. Left-to-right shunts have emerged as a potential therapeutic option to reduce left atrial hypertension, improve quality of life, and impact long-term outcomes. This nascent field carries both potential therapeutic promise as well as many unanswered questions. Recent data have questioned whether the effects of this therapy vary based on the left ventricular ejection fraction, pulmonary vascular resistance, and/or right ventricular structure and function. This review discusses the basis for left-to-right shunt therapies, synthesizes past and ongoing clinical trials, and offers future directions.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39943738/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250216214512&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39943738</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf120>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf120</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39943738</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Francesco Fioretti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ajith P Nair</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stefan D Anker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Barry A Borlaug</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dean J Kereiakes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>JoAnn Lindenfeld</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregg W Stone</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Javed Butler</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Therapeutic left-to-right shunting in heart failure</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39943738</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf120</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>