<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;ff=20250407082320
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;ff=20250407082320" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 12:23:23 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Racial Disparities in Long-Term Outcomes After Endovascular Aortic Aneurysm Repair in Black and White Medicare Beneficiaries</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190277/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Black patients demonstrated increased risk of late aortic-related events after endovascular aortic aneurysm repair after accounting for the competing risk of death and controlling for baseline covariates. Further investigation into preoperative medical management and barriers to postoperative health care access is necessary to further elucidate underlying mechanisms for the observed disparities.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Apr 7. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072018. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Despite reported racial disparities between Black and White adults in short-term outcomes after abdominal aortic aneurysmal intervention, there is a paucity of literature aimed at understanding long-term disparities. The present study aims to characterize racial disparities in long-term outcomes, perioperative outcomes, and health care use after endovascular aortic aneurysm repair.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We conducted a retrospective cohort study from 2011 to 2019 with outcome assessment through 2020. Using a 100% sample of national Medicare data, we identified beneficiaries ≥66 years of age who underwent intact infrarenal endovascular aortic aneurysm repair. The primary outcome was a composite of endovascular or open aortic reintervention, late aneurysm rupture, and all-cause mortality. Secondary outcomes included other reinterventions, perioperative outcomes, and annual rates of health care use.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A cohort of 107 636 Black (3.9%) and White (96.1%) beneficiaries was identified. The cumulative incidence of the primary outcome was 72.9% (95% CI, 71.8%-73.9%) in White patients versus 80.0% (95% CI, 76.4-83.0) in Black patients (<i>P</i>&lt;0.0001). The adjusted hazard of the primary outcome was not significantly different between Black and White adults (adjusted hazard ratio [HR] 1.04 [95% CI, 0.99-1.09]); however, when death was treated as a competing risk, a significantly higher hazard for the composite outcome was observed for Black patients (subdistribution HR, 1.56 [95% CI, 1.39-1.76]). Components of the primary outcome were also greater among Black compared with White patients. Black patients had higher rates of medical complications in the perioperative period, including acute renal failure (subdistribution HR, 1.18 [95% CI, 1.01-1.38]), dialysis initiation (subdistribution HR, 2.75 [95% CI, 2.03-3.7]), and deep vein thrombosis (subdistribution HR, 1.54 [95% CI, 1.05-2.26]). Black patients had lower rates of vascular office visits after intervention (adjusted rate ratio, 0.96 [95% CI, 0.93-0.99]) but higher rates of emergency department visits (adjusted rate ratio, 1.05 [95% CI, 1.02-1.09]) and hospital readmissions (adjusted rate ratio, 1.13 [95% CI, 1.08-1.18]).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Black patients demonstrated increased risk of late aortic-related events after endovascular aortic aneurysm repair after accounting for the competing risk of death and controlling for baseline covariates. Further investigation into preoperative medical management and barriers to postoperative health care access is necessary to further elucidate underlying mechanisms for the observed disparities.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190277/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40190277</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072018>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072018</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40190277</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Abena Appah-Sampong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christina Marcaccio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Siling Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mohamad A Hussain</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert Yeh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marc L Schermerhorn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eric A Secemsky</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Racial Disparities in Long-Term Outcomes After Endovascular Aortic Aneurysm Repair in Black and White Medicare Beneficiaries</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40190277</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072018</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Metabolic Coordination Structures Contribute to Diabetic Myocardial Dysfunction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190276/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Our findings demonstrated that ACBP mediates the bidirectional regulation of cardiomyocyte metabolic and structural associations and identified a promising therapeutic target for ameliorating cardiac dysfunction in patients with T2DM.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Apr 7. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.326044. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Individuals with diabetes are susceptible to cardiac dysfunction and heart failure, potentially resulting in mortality. Metabolic disorders frequently occur in patients with diabetes, and diabetes usually leads to remodeling of heart structure and cardiac dysfunction. However, the contribution and underlying mechanisms of metabolic and structural coupling in diabetic cardiac dysfunction remain elusive.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Two mouse models of type 2 diabetes (T2DM) were used to assess alterations in glucose/lipid metabolism and cardiac structure. The potential metabolic-structural coupling molecule ACBP (acyl-coenzyme A-binding protein) was screened from 4 published datasets of T2DM-associated heart disease. In vivo loss-of-function and gain-of-function approaches were used to investigate the role of ACBP in diabetic cardiac dysfunction. The underlying mechanisms of metabolic and structural coupling were investigated by stable-isotope tracing metabolomics, coimmunoprecipitation coupled with mass spectrometry, and chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Diabetic mouse hearts exhibit enhanced lipid metabolism and impaired ultrastructure with marked cardiac systolic and diastolic dysfunction. Analysis of 4 T2DM public datasets revealed that <i>Acbp</i> was a significant lipid metabolism gene whose expression was upregulated. Consistently, ACBP expression levels were markedly elevated in the hearts of patients with diabetes and diabetic mice. Moreover, we constructed cardiomyocyte-specific <i>Acbp</i> knockout mice that exhibited attenuation of T2DM-induced cardiac remodeling and cardiac dysfunction, including attenuation of cardiac hypertrophy, fibrosis, ultrastructural damage, and enhanced cardiomyocyte contractility and cardiac function. Conversely, cardiac-specific <i>Acbp</i> overexpression via adeno-associated virus type 9, which encodes <i>Acbp</i> under the cTnT (cardiac troponin T) promoter, recapitulated cardiac dysfunction. Mechanistically, cardiac-specific <i>Acbp</i> knockout enhances glucose utilization in diabetic cardiomyocytes, suggesting a potential compensatory mechanism for insufficient ATP levels, highlighting its metabolic role. In addition, combined with mass spectrometry analysis revealed that ACBP binds MyBPC3 (myosin-binding protein C3) in T2DM individuals, which potentially prevents MyBPC3 from assisting the formation of cross-bridge structures between myosin and actin, thereby impairing myocardial contraction. Importantly, chromatin immunoprecipitation sequencing revealed that peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor γ regulates the transcriptional activity of <i>Acbp</i>.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Our findings demonstrated that ACBP mediates the bidirectional regulation of cardiomyocyte metabolic and structural associations and identified a promising therapeutic target for ameliorating cardiac dysfunction in patients with T2DM.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190276/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40190276</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.326044>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.326044</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40190276</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Teng Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tongsheng Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Honglin Ren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Conghui Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiang Qian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinlu Fu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shangyuan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chengshu Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xi Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junhong Wan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shijie Xiong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuanjun Ji</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mengying Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huiting Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ting Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenyi Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Zou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jingwei Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maoquan Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zeyi Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peixuan Lan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinghui Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yandi Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ming Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuezhe Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jing Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weibin Cai</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Metabolic Coordination Structures Contribute to Diabetic Myocardial Dysfunction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40190276</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.326044</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Role of Technology in Promoting Heart Healthy Behavior Change to Increase Equity in Optimal Cardiovascular Health: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190270/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Populations most affected by cardiovascular health disparities, including underrepresented populations with lower socioeconomic status, people with disabilities, and those living in underserved rural communities, are disproportionately exposed to adverse social determinants of health. Specifically, economic instability and suboptimal living conditions within the neighborhood and built environment directly determine access to resources and opportunities for healthful behaviors. In this scientific...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Apr 7. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001314. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Populations most affected by cardiovascular health disparities, including underrepresented populations with lower socioeconomic status, people with disabilities, and those living in underserved rural communities, are disproportionately exposed to adverse social determinants of health. Specifically, economic instability and suboptimal living conditions within the neighborhood and built environment directly determine access to resources and opportunities for healthful behaviors. In this scientific statement, we examined the technology-enabled interventions that address cardiovascular health behaviors from adolescence to adulthood in populations most affected by health disparities. We used a broad definition of technology, including wearables, applications, and telehealth, for behavior tracking. Aligning with Life's Essential 8, we focused on interventions targeting behavior change related to physical activity, sedentary time, dietary intake, tobacco cessation, and sleep health to improve cardiovascular health. The digital determinants of health are important adjuncts to the social determinants and operate at the individual, interpersonal, community, and societal levels. The digital determinants of health include the impact of digital technologies (eg, wearables, telemedicine) across health outcomes. Evidence of effective interventions using technology to improve cardiovascular health through positive behavior change is critical for preventing cardiovascular disease events. Stronger evidence is needed to inform and implement effective approaches that are scalable and cost-effective across communities and health care institutions to advance digital equity in cardiovascular health. Dissemination of digital solutions to improve cardiovascular health in communities or across health care systems must ensure effective, feasible, available, and affordable solutions for populations most in need.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40190270/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40190270</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001314>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001314</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40190270</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tiffany M Powell-Wiley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>LaPrincess C Brewer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lora E Burke</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rosalba Hernandez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jill Landsbaugh Kaar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maura Kepper</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher E Kline</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keila N Lopez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shamarial Roberson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Colleen K Spees</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gerald J Jerome</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Council on Lifestyle and Cardiometabolic Health; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease; and Council on Quality of Care and Outcomes Research</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Role of Technology in Promoting Heart Healthy Behavior Change to Increase Equity in Optimal Cardiovascular Health: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40190270</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001314</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Channel synapse mediates neurotransmission of airway protective chemoreflexes</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187347/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Neural reflexes to chemicals in the throat protect the airway from aspiration and infection. Mechanistic understanding of these reflexes remains premature, exemplified by chronic cough-a sensitized cough reflex-being a prevalent unmet clinical need. Here, in mice, a whole-body search for channel synapses-featuring CALHM1/3 channel-mediated neurotransmitter release-and single-cell transcriptomics uncovered subclasses of the Pou2f3^(+) chemosensory cell family in the throat communicating with...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 2:S0092-8674(25)00280-6. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.007. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Neural reflexes to chemicals in the throat protect the airway from aspiration and infection. Mechanistic understanding of these reflexes remains premature, exemplified by chronic cough-a sensitized cough reflex-being a prevalent unmet clinical need. Here, in mice, a whole-body search for channel synapses-featuring CALHM1/3 channel-mediated neurotransmitter release-and single-cell transcriptomics uncovered subclasses of the Pou2f3<sup>+</sup> chemosensory cell family in the throat communicating with vagal neurons via this synapse. They express G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) for noxious chemicals, T2Rs, which upon stimulation trigger swallow and cough-like expulsive reflexes in the hypopharynx and larynx, respectively. These reflexes were abolished by Calhm3 and Pou2f3 knockout and could be triggered by targeted optogenetic stimulation. Furthermore, aeroallergen exposure augmented CALHM3-dependent expulsive reflex. This study identifies Pou2f3<sup>+</sup> epithelial cells with channel synapses as chemosensory end organs of airway protective reflexes and sites of their hyperresponsiveness, advancing mechanistic understanding of airway defense programs with distinct therapeutic potential.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187347/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40187347</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.007>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.007</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40187347</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shogo Soma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Norihito Hayatsu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kengo Nomura</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark W Sherwood</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tatsuro Murakami</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yoichiro Sugiyama</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Naofumi Suematsu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Takanori Aoki</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yu Yamada</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Moe Asayama</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mami Kaneko</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kento Ohbayashi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Misa Arizono</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Masato Ohtsuka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shun Hamada</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ichiro Matsumoto</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yusaku Iwasaki</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nobuhiko Ohno</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yasushi Okazaki</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Akiyuki Taruno</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Channel synapse mediates neurotransmission of airway protective chemoreflexes</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40187347</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.007</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Conserved genetic basis for microbial colonization of the gut</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187346/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Despite the fundamental importance of gut microbes, the genetic basis of their colonization remains largely unexplored. Here, by applying cross-species genotype-habitat association at the tree-of-life scale, we identify conserved microbial gene modules associated with gut colonization. Across thousands of species, we discovered 79 taxonomically diverse putative colonization factors organized into operonic and non-operonic modules. They include previously characterized colonization pathways such...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 2:S0092-8674(25)00283-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.010. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite the fundamental importance of gut microbes, the genetic basis of their colonization remains largely unexplored. Here, by applying cross-species genotype-habitat association at the tree-of-life scale, we identify conserved microbial gene modules associated with gut colonization. Across thousands of species, we discovered 79 taxonomically diverse putative colonization factors organized into operonic and non-operonic modules. They include previously characterized colonization pathways such as autoinducer-2 biosynthesis and novel processes including tRNA modification and translation. In vivo functional validation revealed YigZ (IMPACT family) and tRNA hydroxylation protein-P (TrhP) are required for E. coli intestinal colonization. Overexpressing YigZ alone is sufficient to enhance colonization of the poorly colonizing MG1655 E. coli by >;100-fold. Moreover, natural allelic variations in YigZ impact inter-strain colonization efficiency. Our findings highlight the power of large-scale comparative genomics in revealing the genetic basis of microbial adaptations. These broadly conserved colonization factors may prove critical for understanding gastrointestinal (GI) dysbiosis and developing therapeutics.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187346/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40187346</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.010>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40187346</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Menghan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sydney B Blattman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mai Takahashi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nandan Mandayam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenyan Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Panos Oikonomou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sohail F Tavazoie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saeed Tavazoie</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Conserved genetic basis for microbial colonization of the gut</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40187346</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Molecular basis for shifted receptor recognition by an encephalitic arbovirus</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187345/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Western equine encephalitis virus (WEEV) is an arbovirus that historically caused large outbreaks of encephalitis throughout the Americas. WEEV binds protocadherin 10 (PCDH10) as a receptor, and highly virulent ancestral WEEV strains also bind low-density lipoprotein receptor (LDLR)-related proteins. As WEEV declined as a human pathogen in North America over the past century, isolates have lost the ability to bind mammalian receptors while still recognizing avian receptors. To explain shifts in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 2:S0092-8674(25)00347-2. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.029. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Western equine encephalitis virus (WEEV) is an arbovirus that historically caused large outbreaks of encephalitis throughout the Americas. WEEV binds protocadherin 10 (PCDH10) as a receptor, and highly virulent ancestral WEEV strains also bind low-density lipoprotein receptor (LDLR)-related proteins. As WEEV declined as a human pathogen in North America over the past century, isolates have lost the ability to bind mammalian receptors while still recognizing avian receptors. To explain shifts in receptor dependencies and assess the risk of WEEV re-emergence, we determined cryoelectron microscopy structures of WEEV bound to human PCDH10, avian PCDH10, and human very-low-density lipoprotein receptor (VLDLR). We show that one to three E2 glycoprotein substitutions are sufficient for a nonpathogenic strain to regain the ability to bind mammalian receptors. A soluble VLDLR fragment protects mice from lethal challenge by a virulent ancestral WEEV strain. Because WEEV recently re-emerged in South America after decades of inactivity, our findings have important implications for outbreak preparedness.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187345/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40187345</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.029>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.029</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40187345</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xiaoyi Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wanyu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica Oros</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica A Plante</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brooke M Mitchell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jesse S Plung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Himanish Basu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sivapratha Nagappan-Chettiar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joshua M Boeckers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laurentia V Tjang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Colin J Mann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vesna Brusic</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tierra K Buck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haley Varnum</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pan Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Linzy M Malcolm</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>So Yoen Choi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William M de Souza</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isaac M Chiu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hisashi Umemori</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott C Weaver</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kenneth S Plante</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jonathan Abraham</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Molecular basis for shifted receptor recognition by an encephalitic arbovirus</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40187345</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.029</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Structural basis for plasticity in receptor engagement by an encephalitic alphavirus</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187344/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The structural basis for shifts in receptor usage remains poorly understood despite the implications for virus adaptation and emergence. Western equine encephalitis virus (WEEV) strains exhibit different patterns of engagement for two of their entry receptors: very-low-density lipoprotein receptor (VLDLR) and protocadherin 10 (PCDH10). Using structural and functional studies, we show that while all WEEV strains have a lipoprotein class A (LA) domain binding site near the E1 fusion loop, VLDLR...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 2:S0092-8674(25)00272-7. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.036. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The structural basis for shifts in receptor usage remains poorly understood despite the implications for virus adaptation and emergence. Western equine encephalitis virus (WEEV) strains exhibit different patterns of engagement for two of their entry receptors: very-low-density lipoprotein receptor (VLDLR) and protocadherin 10 (PCDH10). Using structural and functional studies, we show that while all WEEV strains have a lipoprotein class A (LA) domain binding site near the E1 fusion loop, VLDLR engagement requires a second binding site in E2 that can vary with single nucleotide substitutions. We also resolve a structure of PCDH10 bound to WEEV, which reveals interactions near the E1 fusion loop with residues that also mediate LA domain binding. Evolutionary analysis enabled the generation of a PCDH10 decoy that protects in vivo against all WEEV strains tested. Our experiments demonstrate how viruses can engage multiple receptors using shared determinants, which likely impacts cellular tropism and virulence.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40187344/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40187344</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.036>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.036</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40187344</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Saravanan Raju</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sathvik Palakurty</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alan Sariol</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ngan Wagoner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lucas J Adams</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sean Hui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William B Klimstra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daved H Fremont</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael S Diamond</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Structural basis for plasticity in receptor engagement by an encephalitic alphavirus</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40187344</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.036</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Preserving the future of heart transplantation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185874/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2025 Apr 4. doi: 10.1038/s41569-025-01146-x. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185874/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40185874</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-025-01146-x>10.1038/s41569-025-01146-x</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40185874</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>David M Kaye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David C McGiffin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Preserving the future of heart transplantation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40185874</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-025-01146-x</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Single-cell spatial transcriptome atlas and whole-brain connectivity of the macaque claustrum</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185102/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Claustrum orchestrates brain functions via its connections with numerous brain regions, but its molecular and cellular organization remains unresolved. Single-nucleus RNA sequencing of 227,750 macaque claustral cells identified 48 transcriptome-defined cell types, with most glutamatergic neurons similar to deep-layer insular neurons. Comparison of macaque, marmoset, and mouse transcriptomes revealed macaque-specific cell types. Retrograde tracer injections at 67 cortical and 7 subcortical...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Mar 30:S0092-8674(25)00273-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.037. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Claustrum orchestrates brain functions via its connections with numerous brain regions, but its molecular and cellular organization remains unresolved. Single-nucleus RNA sequencing of 227,750 macaque claustral cells identified 48 transcriptome-defined cell types, with most glutamatergic neurons similar to deep-layer insular neurons. Comparison of macaque, marmoset, and mouse transcriptomes revealed macaque-specific cell types. Retrograde tracer injections at 67 cortical and 7 subcortical regions defined four distinct distribution zones of retrogradely labeled claustral neurons. Joint analysis of whole-brain connectivity and single-cell spatial transcriptome showed that these four zones containing distinct compositions of glutamatergic (but not GABAergic) cell types preferentially connected to specific brain regions with a strong ipsilateral bias. Several macaque-specific glutamatergic cell types in ventral vs. dorsal claustral zones selectively co-projected to two functionally related areas-entorhinal cortex and hippocampus vs. motor cortex and putamen, respectively. These data provide the basis for elucidating the neuronal organization underlying diverse claustral functions.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185102/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40185102</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.037>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.037</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40185102</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ying Lei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuxuan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mingli Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nini Yuan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yujie Hou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lingjun Ding</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhiyong Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zihan Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chao Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mingyuan Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruiyi Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ana Rita Ribeiro Gomes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuanfang Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhaoke Luo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhen Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qinwen Chai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pierre Misery</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanqing Zhong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinxiang Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Camille Lamy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Cui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qian Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiao Fang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingjie An</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ye Tian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yiwen Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xing Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruiqi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huanhuan Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jingjing Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xing Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>He Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shiwen Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ling Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yong Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shenyu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kexin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guangling Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wanqiu Zhou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianfeng Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cong Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuzhen Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liangtang Chang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dafina Toplanaj</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mengni Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiabing Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yun Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Biyu Ren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hanyu Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haotian Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianyun Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lina Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yichen Zuo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Linjie Lu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liqin Gu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuting Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yaqian Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yinying He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shengkang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qi Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanbing Lu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yannong Dou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anqi Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Minyuan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinyan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying Xia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huateng Cao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhiyue Lu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zixian Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xin Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaofei Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhifeng Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shengjin Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cirong Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Changhong Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chun Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhiyong Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chengyu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan-Gang Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xun Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Colette Dehay</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Julien Vezoli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mu-Ming Poo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianhua Yao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Longqi Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wu Wei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Henry Kennedy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhiming Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Single-cell spatial transcriptome atlas and whole-brain connectivity of the macaque claustrum</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40185102</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.037</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rorγt-positive dendritic cells are required for the induction of peripheral regulatory T cells in response to oral antigens</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185101/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The intestinal immune system maintains tolerance to harmless food proteins and gut microbiota through peripherally derived RORγt^(+) Tregs (pTregs), which prevent food intolerance and inflammatory bowel disease. Recent studies suggested that RORγt^(+) antigen-presenting cells (APCs), which encompass rare dendritic cell (DC) subsets and type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s), are key to pTreg induction. Here, we developed a mouse with reduced RORγt^(+) APCs by deleting a specific cis-regulatory...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 1:S0092-8674(25)00293-4. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.020. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The intestinal immune system maintains tolerance to harmless food proteins and gut microbiota through peripherally derived RORγt<sup>+</sup> Tregs (pTregs), which prevent food intolerance and inflammatory bowel disease. Recent studies suggested that RORγt<sup>+</sup> antigen-presenting cells (APCs), which encompass rare dendritic cell (DC) subsets and type 3 innate lymphoid cells (ILC3s), are key to pTreg induction. Here, we developed a mouse with reduced RORγt<sup>+</sup> APCs by deleting a specific cis-regulatory element of Rorc encoding RORγt. Single-cell RNA sequencing and flow cytometry analyses confirmed the depletion of a RORγt<sup>+</sup> DC subset and ILC3s. These mice showed a secondary reduction in pTregs, impaired tolerance to oral antigens, and an increase in T helper (Th)2 cells. Conversely, ILC3-deficient mice showed no pTregs or Th2 cell abnormalities. Lineage tracing revealed that RORγt<sup>+</sup> DCs share a lymphoid origin with ILC3s, consistent with their similar phenotypic traits. These findings highlight the role of lymphoid RORγt<sup>+</sup> DCs in maintaining intestinal immune balance and preventing conditions like food allergies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185101/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40185101</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.020>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.020</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40185101</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Patrick Fernandes Rodrigues</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shitong Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tihana Trsan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Santosh K Panda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>José Luís Fachi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yizhou Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Siling Du</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah de Oliveira</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alina Ulezko Antonova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Darya Khantakova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Raki Sudan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pritesh Desai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael S Diamond</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Susan Gilfillan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephen K Anderson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marina Cella</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marco Colonna</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Rorγt-positive dendritic cells are required for the induction of peripheral regulatory T cells in response to oral antigens</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40185101</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.020</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PAX translocations remodel mitochondrial metabolism through altered leucine usage in rhabdomyosarcoma</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185100/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) patients harboring paired-box fusion proteins (PAX3/7-FOXO1) exhibit a greater incidence of tumor relapse, metastasis, and poor survival outcome, thereby underscoring the urgent need to develop effective therapies to treat this subtype of childhood cancer. To uncover mechanisms that contribute to tumor initiation, we develop a muscle progenitor model and use epigenomic approaches to unravel genome rewiring events mediated by PAX3/7 fusion proteins. Among the key...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 1:S0092-8674(25)00281-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.008. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma (ARMS) patients harboring paired-box fusion proteins (PAX3/7-FOXO1) exhibit a greater incidence of tumor relapse, metastasis, and poor survival outcome, thereby underscoring the urgent need to develop effective therapies to treat this subtype of childhood cancer. To uncover mechanisms that contribute to tumor initiation, we develop a muscle progenitor model and use epigenomic approaches to unravel genome rewiring events mediated by PAX3/7 fusion proteins. Among the key targets of PAX3/7 fusion proteins, we identify a cohort of oncogenes, fibroblast growth factor (FGF) receptors, tRNA-modifying enzymes, and genes essential for mitochondrial metabolism and protein translation, which we successfully targeted in preclinical trials. We identify leucine usage as a key factor driving the growth of aggressive PAX-fusion tumors, as limiting its bioavailability impaired oxidative phosphorylation and mitochondrial metabolism, delaying tumor progression and improving survival in vivo. Our data provide a compelling list of actionable targets and suggest promising new strategies to treat this tumor.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185100/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40185100</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.008>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.008</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40185100</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bhargab Kalita</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gerard Martinez-Cebrian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Justina McEvoy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Melody Allensworth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michelle Knight</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alessandro Magli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rita C R Perlingeiro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael A Dyer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Stewart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brian David Dynlacht</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>PAX translocations remodel mitochondrial metabolism through altered leucine usage in rhabdomyosarcoma</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40185100</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.008</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>20 years of histone lysine demethylases: From discovery to the clinic and beyond</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185081/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Twenty years ago, histone lysine demethylases (KDMs) were discovered. Since their discovery, they have been increasingly studied and shown to be important across species, development, and diseases. Considerable advances have been made toward understanding their (1) enzymology, (2) role as critical components of biological complexes, (3) role in normal cellular processes and functions, (4) implications in pathological conditions, and (5) therapeutic potential. This Review covers these key...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 3;188(7):1747-1783. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.023.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Twenty years ago, histone lysine demethylases (KDMs) were discovered. Since their discovery, they have been increasingly studied and shown to be important across species, development, and diseases. Considerable advances have been made toward understanding their (1) enzymology, (2) role as critical components of biological complexes, (3) role in normal cellular processes and functions, (4) implications in pathological conditions, and (5) therapeutic potential. This Review covers these key relationships related to the KDM field with the awareness that numerous laboratories have contributed to this field. The current knowledge coupled with future insights will shape our understanding about cell function, development, and disease onset and progression, which will allow for novel biomarkers to be identified and for optimal therapeutic options to be developed for KDM-related diseases in the years ahead.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40185081/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40185081</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.023>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.023</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40185081</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Zach H Gray</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Madison A Honer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pooja Ghatalia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Johnathan R Whetstine</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>20 years of histone lysine demethylases: From discovery to the clinic and beyond</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40185081</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.023</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tirzepatide, HFpEF, and the Kidney: A Triangular Relationship Requiring Measurement of GFR, Not Guesses</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40183720/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Mar 31:S0735-1097(25)05983-2. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.508. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40183720/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40183720</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.508>10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.508</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40183720</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jozine M Ter Maaten</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Javed Butler</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Tirzepatide, HFpEF, and the Kidney: A Triangular Relationship Requiring Measurement of GFR, Not Guesses</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40183720</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2025.03.508</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genetic and Lifestyle Risks for Coronary Artery Disease and Long-Term Risk of Incident Dementia Subtypes</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181791/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Individuals who are genetically predisposed to developing CAD also face an increased risk of developing dementia in old age. This risk is reduced in those demonstrating healthy lifestyle profiles earlier in the lifespan, particularly in those who may be at an increased risk of developing dementia caused by an underlying vascular pathology.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Apr 4. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070632. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Shared genetic and lifestyle risk factors may underlie the development of both coronary artery disease (CAD) and dementia. We examined whether an increased genetic risk for CAD is associated with long-term risk of developing all-cause, Alzheimer's, or vascular dementia, and investigated whether differences in potentially modifiable lifestyle factors in the mid- to late-life period may attenuate this risk.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: A prospective cohort study of 365 782 participants free from dementia for at least 5 years after baseline assessment was conducted within the UK Biobank cohort. Genetic risk was assessed using a genomewide polygenic risk score (PRS) for CAD and lifestyle risk using a modified version of the American Heart Association's Life's Essential 8 Lifestyle Risk Score (LRS). Higher values for both scores were deemed to represent increased risk. Primary outcomes were incident all-cause, Alzheimer's, and vascular dementia diagnoses obtained from electronic health records. Secondary outcomes were neuroimaging phenotypes measured in 32 028 participants recalled for magnetic resonance imaging. Sensitivity analyses were conducted to test the extent by which biological and behavioral risk factors contributed to observed associations.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A total of 8870 cases of all-cause dementia were observed over a median 13.9-year follow-up. Both genetic (PRS) and lifestyle (LRS) risk scores for CAD were associated with a modestly elevated risk of all-cause dementia (subhazard ratio per SD increase, 1.10 [1.08, 1.12], <i>P</i>&lt;0.001, for PRS and 1.04 [1.02, 1.06], <i>P</i>=0.006, for LRS). This risk appeared largely attributable to underlying vascular dementia diagnoses (subhazard ratio, 1.16 [1.11, 1.21], <i>P</i>&lt;0.001 for PRS and 1.15 [1.09, 1.22], <i>P</i>&lt;0.001, for LRS), because Alzheimer's disease was found to demonstrate moderate associations with PRS alone (subhazard ratio, 1.09 [1.06, 1.13]; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). LRS was found to have an additive rather than interactive effect with PRS, with individuals in the highest tertiles for both genetic and lifestyle risk for CAD ≈70% more likely to develop vascular dementia during follow-up compared with those in the lowest tertiles for both (subhazard ratio, 1.71 [1.39, 2.11]; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). This was substantially attenuated in those with a low LRS at baseline, however, regardless of underlying genetic risk (40% to 50% reduction for low versus high LRS tertile regardless of PRS tertile; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001 for all). In a subset of individuals recalled for neuroimaging assessments, those in the highest tertiles for genetic and lifestyle risk for CAD demonstrated a ≈25% greater volume of white matter hyperintensities than those in the lowest risk tertiles, but showed little difference in gray matter or hippocampal volumes. Sensitivity analyses identified associations between both biological and behavioral risk scores with white matter hyperintensity burden and vascular dementia, whereas some Alzheimer's dementia associations showed seemingly paradoxical relationships.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Individuals who are genetically predisposed to developing CAD also face an increased risk of developing dementia in old age. This risk is reduced in those demonstrating healthy lifestyle profiles earlier in the lifespan, particularly in those who may be at an increased risk of developing dementia caused by an underlying vascular pathology.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181791/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40181791</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070632>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070632</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40181791</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Arisa Sittichokkananon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Victoria Garfield</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott T Chiesa</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Genetic and Lifestyle Risks for Coronary Artery Disease and Long-Term Risk of Incident Dementia Subtypes</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40181791</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070632</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Piezo1 in PASMCs: Critical for Hypoxia-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension Development</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181773/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: This study provides evidence that Piezo1 expressed in PASMCs is critically involved in the pathogenesis of PH by controlling pulmonary vascular tone, arterial remodeling, and associated lung capillary rarefaction due to endothelial cell senescence.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Apr 4. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325475. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Pulmonary hypertension (PH) is a life-threatening and progressive yet incurable disease. The hallmarks of PH comprise (1) sustained contraction and (2) excessive proliferation of pulmonary arterial smooth muscle cells (PASMCs). A major stimulus to which PASMCs are exposed during PH development is altered mechanical stress, originating from increased blood pressure, changes in blood flow velocity, and a progressive stiffening of pulmonary arteries. Mechanosensitive ion channels, including Piezo1, perceive such mechanical stimuli and translate them into a variety of cellular responses, including contractility or proliferation. Thus, the objective of the present study was to elucidate the specific role of Piezo1 in PASMCs for PH development and progression.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: The cell-type specific function of Piezo1 in PH was assessed in (1) PASMCs and lung tissues from patients with PH and (2) 2 mouse strains characterized by smooth muscle cell-specific, conditional Piezo1 knockout. Taking advantage of these strains, the smooth muscle cell-specific role of Piezo1 in PH development and progression was assessed in isolated, perfused, and ventilated mouse lungs, wire myography, and proliferation assays. Finally, in vivo function of smooth muscle cell-specific Piezo1 knockout was evaluated upon induction of chronic hypoxia-induced PH in these mice with insights into pulmonary vascular cell senescence.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Compared with healthy controls, PASMCs from patients with PH featured an elevated Piezo1 expression and increased proliferative phenotype. Smooth muscle cell-specific Piezo1 deletion, as confirmed via quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction and patch clamp recordings, prevented the hypoxia-induced increase in PASMC proliferation in mice. Moreover, Piezo1 knockout reduced hypoxic pulmonary vasoconstriction in isolated, perfused, and ventilated mouse lungs, endothelial-denuded pulmonary arteries, and hemodynamic measurements in vivo. Consequently, Piezo1-deficient mice were considerably protected against chronic hypoxia-induced PH development with ameliorated right heart hypertrophy and improved hemodynamic function. In addition, distal pulmonary capillaries were preserved in the Piezo1-knockout mice, associated with a lower number of senescent endothelial cells.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: This study provides evidence that Piezo1 expressed in PASMCs is critically involved in the pathogenesis of PH by controlling pulmonary vascular tone, arterial remodeling, and associated lung capillary rarefaction due to endothelial cell senescence.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181773/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40181773</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325475>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325475</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40181773</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Fenja Knoepp</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shariq Abid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amal Houssaini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Larissa Lipskaia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mira Yasemin Gökyildirim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emmanuelle Born</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elisabeth Marcos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Malika Arhatte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Edyta Glogowska</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nora Vienney</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andreas Günther</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Simone Kraut</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ingrid Breitenborn-Mueller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karin Quanz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dagmar Fenner-Nau</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Geneviève Derumeaux</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Norbert Weissmann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eric Honoré</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Serge Adnot</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Piezo1 in PASMCs: Critical for Hypoxia-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension Development</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40181773</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325475</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>PCR London Valves: a pioneering course at the centre of advances in the treatment of heart valve disease for over 15 years</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181574/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Apr 4:ehaf103. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf103. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40181574/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40181574</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf103>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf103</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40181574</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>PCR London Valves Course Directors and Team</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>PCR London Valves: a pioneering course at the centre of advances in the treatment of heart valve disease for over 15 years</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40181574</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf103</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Therapeutic potential of allosteric HECT E3 ligase inhibition</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179885/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Targeting ubiquitin E3 ligases is therapeutically attractive; however, the absence of an active-site pocket impedes computational approaches for identifying inhibitors. In a large, unbiased biochemical screen, we discover inhibitors that bind a cryptic cavity distant from the catalytic cysteine of the homologous to E6-associated protein C terminus domain (HECT) E3 ligase, SMAD ubiquitin regulatory factor 1 (SMURF1). Structural and biochemical analyses and engineered escape mutants revealed that...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 2:S0092-8674(25)00274-0. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.001. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Targeting ubiquitin E3 ligases is therapeutically attractive; however, the absence of an active-site pocket impedes computational approaches for identifying inhibitors. In a large, unbiased biochemical screen, we discover inhibitors that bind a cryptic cavity distant from the catalytic cysteine of the homologous to E6-associated protein C terminus domain (HECT) E3 ligase, SMAD ubiquitin regulatory factor 1 (SMURF1). Structural and biochemical analyses and engineered escape mutants revealed that these inhibitors restrict an essential catalytic motion by extending an α helix over a conserved glycine hinge. SMURF1 levels are increased in pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH), a disease caused by mutation of bone morphogenetic protein receptor-2 (BMPR2). We demonstrated that SMURF1 inhibition prevented BMPR2 ubiquitylation, normalized bone morphogenetic protein (BMP) signaling, restored pulmonary vascular cell homeostasis, and reversed pathology in established experimental PAH. Leveraging this deep mechanistic understanding, we undertook an in silico machine-learning-based screen to identify inhibitors of the prototypic HECT E6AP and confirmed glycine-hinge-dependent allosteric activity in vitro. Inhibiting HECTs and other glycine-hinge proteins opens a new druggable space.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179885/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40179885</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.001>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.001</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40179885</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Alexander M K Rothman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amir Florentin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Florence Zink</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Catherine Quigley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olivier Bonneau</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rene Hemmig</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amanda Hachey</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tomas Rejtar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maulik Thaker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rishi Jain</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shih-Min Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel Sutton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jan Roger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ji-Hu Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sven Weiler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Simona Cotesta</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Johannes Ottl</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Salil Srivastava</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alina Kordonsky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Reut Avishid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elon Yariv</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ritu Rathi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Oshrit Khvalevsky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas Troxler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah K Binmahfooz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Oded Kleifeld</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicholas W Morrell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marc Humbert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew J Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gabor Jarai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rohan E J Beckwith</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer S Cobb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nichola Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nils Ostermann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John Tallarico</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Duncan Shaw</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sabine Guth-Gundel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gali Prag</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David J Rowlands</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Therapeutic potential of allosteric HECT E3 ligase inhibition</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40179885</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.001</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genetically encoded reporters of actin filament organization in living cells and tissues</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179884/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The cytoskeletal protein actin is crucial for cell shape and integrity throughout eukaryotes. Actin filaments perform essential biological functions, including muscle contraction, cell division, and tissue morphogenesis. These diverse activities are achieved through the ability of actin filaments to be arranged into precise architectures. Much progress has been made in defining the proteome of the actin cytoskeleton, but a detailed appreciation of the dynamic organizational state of the actin...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 1:S0092-8674(25)00276-4. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.003. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The cytoskeletal protein actin is crucial for cell shape and integrity throughout eukaryotes. Actin filaments perform essential biological functions, including muscle contraction, cell division, and tissue morphogenesis. These diverse activities are achieved through the ability of actin filaments to be arranged into precise architectures. Much progress has been made in defining the proteome of the actin cytoskeleton, but a detailed appreciation of the dynamic organizational state of the actin filaments themselves has been hindered by available tools. Fluorescence polarization microscopy is uniquely placed for measuring actin filament organization by exploiting the sensitivity of polarized light excitation to the orientation of fluorophores attached to actin filaments. By engineering fusions of five widely used actin localization reporters to fluorescent proteins with constrained mobility, we have succeeded in developing genetically encoded, green- and red-fluorescent-protein-based reporters for non-invasive, quantitative measurements of actin filament organization in living cells and tissues by fluorescence polarization microscopy.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179884/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40179884</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.003>10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.003</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40179884</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Carla Silva Martins</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>François Iv</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shashi Kumar Suman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas C Panagiotou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clara Sidor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>María Ruso-López</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Camille N Plancke</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shizue Omi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rebecca Pagès</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maxime Gomes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexander Llewellyn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sourish Reddy Bandi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laurie Ramond</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Federica Arbizzani</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Caio Vaz Rimoli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frank Schnorrer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>François Robin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrew Wilde</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Loïc LeGoff</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jean-Denis Pedelacq</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Antoine Jégou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stéphanie Cabantous</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sergio A Rincon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cristel Chandre</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sophie Brasselet</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Manos Mavrakis</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Genetically encoded reporters of actin filament organization in living cells and tissues</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40179884</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.03.003</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A chemical radar allows bacteria to detect and kill predators</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179883/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Amoebal predation exerts a strong evolutionary selection pressure on bacteria, thus driving the development of effective predator-defense strategies. However, little is known about the molecular interplay between bacteria and predators, particularly how bacteria can sense and kill their microbial predators. We show how the ubiquitous bacterium Pseudomonas syringae detects and kills the social amoeba Polysphondylium pallidum. Combining comparative genomics, molecular biology, and chemical...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Apr 1:S0092-8674(25)00269-7. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.033. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Amoebal predation exerts a strong evolutionary selection pressure on bacteria, thus driving the development of effective predator-defense strategies. However, little is known about the molecular interplay between bacteria and predators, particularly how bacteria can sense and kill their microbial predators. We show how the ubiquitous bacterium Pseudomonas syringae detects and kills the social amoeba Polysphondylium pallidum. Combining comparative genomics, molecular biology, and chemical analyses, we identified a chemical radar system. The system relies on P. syringae secreting the lipopeptide syringafactin, which is deacylated by the amoeba. The resulting peptides are sensed via the bacterial sensor protein chemical radar regulator (CraR) that activates genes for converting the predator-derived signal into the amoebicide pyrofactin. This system is widespread in P. syringae and enables bacteria to infect A. thaliana in the presence of amoebae. Our study advances the understanding of microbial sensing and opens new avenues for the discovery of natural products.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179883/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40179883</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.033>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.033</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40179883</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shuaibing Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kevin Schlabach</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Victor Hugo Pérez Carrillo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anan Ibrahim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shahran Nayem</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anna Komor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruchira Mukherji</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Somak Chowdhury</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lisa Reimer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Felix Trottmann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>A Corina Vlot</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christian Hertweck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ute A Hellmich</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pierre Stallforth</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>A chemical radar allows bacteria to detect and kill predators</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40179883</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.033</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cell membranes sustain phospholipid imbalance via cholesterol asymmetry</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179882/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Membranes are molecular interfaces that compartmentalize cells to control the flow of nutrients and information. These functions are facilitated by diverse collections of lipids, nearly all of which are distributed asymmetrically between the two bilayer leaflets. Most models of biomembrane structure and function include the implicit assumption that these leaflets have similar abundances of phospholipids. Here, we show that this assumption is generally invalid and investigate the consequences of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Mar 26:S0092-8674(25)00270-3. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.034. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Membranes are molecular interfaces that compartmentalize cells to control the flow of nutrients and information. These functions are facilitated by diverse collections of lipids, nearly all of which are distributed asymmetrically between the two bilayer leaflets. Most models of biomembrane structure and function include the implicit assumption that these leaflets have similar abundances of phospholipids. Here, we show that this assumption is generally invalid and investigate the consequences of lipid abundance imbalances in mammalian plasma membranes (PMs). Using lipidomics, we report that cytoplasmic leaflets of human erythrocyte membranes have >;50% overabundance of phospholipids compared with exoplasmic leaflets. This imbalance is enabled by an asymmetric interleaflet distribution of cholesterol, which regulates cellular cholesterol homeostasis. These features produce unique functional characteristics, including low PM permeability and resting tension in the cytoplasmic leaflet that regulates protein localization.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179882/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40179882</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.034>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.034</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40179882</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Milka Doktorova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica L Symons</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoxuan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hong-Yin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jan Schlegel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph H Lorent</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frederick A Heberle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erdinc Sezgin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Edward Lyman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kandice R Levental</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ilya Levental</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cell membranes sustain phospholipid imbalance via cholesterol asymmetry</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40179882</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.034</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Engineering sonogenetic EchoBack-CAR T cells</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179881/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250407082320&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapy for solid tumors encounters challenges such as on-target off-tumor toxicity, exhaustion, and limited T cell persistence. Here, we engineer sonogenetic EchoBack-CAR T cells using an ultrasensitive heat-shock promoter screened from a library and integrated with a positive feedback loop from CAR signaling, enabling long-lasting CAR expression upon focused-ultrasound (FUS) stimulation. EchoBack-hGD2CAR T cells, targeting disialoganglioside GD2,...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Mar 23:S0092-8674(25)00271-5. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.035. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapy for solid tumors encounters challenges such as on-target off-tumor toxicity, exhaustion, and limited T cell persistence. Here, we engineer sonogenetic EchoBack-CAR T cells using an ultrasensitive heat-shock promoter screened from a library and integrated with a positive feedback loop from CAR signaling, enabling long-lasting CAR expression upon focused-ultrasound (FUS) stimulation. EchoBack-hGD2CAR T cells, targeting disialoganglioside GD2, exhibited potent cytotoxicity and persistence in 3D glioblastoma (GBM) models. In mice, EchoBack-hGD2CAR T cells suppressed GBM without off-tumor toxicity and outperformed their constitutive counterparts. Single-cell RNA sequencing revealed enhanced cytotoxicity and reduced exhaustion in EchoBack-CAR T cells compared with the standard CAR T cells. This EchoBack design was further adapted to target prostate-specific membrane antigen (EchoBack-PSMACAR) for prostate cancer treatment, demonstrating long-lasting tumor suppression with minimal off-tumor toxicity. Thus, the sonogenetic EchoBack-CAR T cells can serve as a versatile, efficient, and safe strategy for solid tumor treatment.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40179881/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250407082320&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40179881</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.035>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.035</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40179881</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Longwei Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peixiang He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuxuan Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fengyi Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dulei Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhiliang Bai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yunjia Qu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Linshan Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chi Woo Yoon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xi Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yixuan Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhengyu Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yiming Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kunshu Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianze Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yushun Zeng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qifa Zhou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>H Kay Chung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rong Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingxiao Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Engineering sonogenetic EchoBack-CAR T cells</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40179881</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.035</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>