<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 22:08:35 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>A Man in His 50s With Dyspnea and Eosinophilia</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837171/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1211. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837171/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38837171</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1211>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1211</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38837171</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kai Christian Jakobs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ursula Rauch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bettina Heidecker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>A Man in His 50s With Dyspnea and Eosinophilia</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38837171</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1211</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emergency Medical Service Agency Practices and Cardiac Arrest Survival</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837166/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In a national registry for OHCA, 7 practices associated with higher rates of favorable neurological survival were identified at EMS agencies. Given wide variability in neurological survival across EMS agencies, these findings provide initial insights into EMS practices associated with top-performing EMS agencies in OHCA survival. Future studies are needed to validate these findings and identify best practices for EMS agencies.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1189. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">IMPORTANCE: Survival for out-of-hospital cardiac arrest (OHCA) varies widely across emergency medical service (EMS) agencies in the US. However, little is known about which EMS practices are associated with higher agency-level survival.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To identify resuscitation practices associated with favorable neurological survival for OHCA at EMS agencies.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: This cohort study surveyed EMS agencies participating in the Cardiac Arrest Registry to Enhance Survival (CARES) with 10 or more OHCAs annually during January 2015 to December 2019; data analyses were performed from April to October 2023.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">EXPOSURE: Survey of resuscitation practices at EMS agencies.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: Risk-standardized rates of favorable neurological survival for OHCA at each EMS agency were estimated using hierarchical logistic regression. Multivariable linear regression then examined the association of EMS practices with rates of risk-standardized favorable neurological survival.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Of 577 eligible EMS agencies, 470 agencies (81.5%) completed the survey. The mean (SD) rate of risk-standardized favorable neurological survival was 8.1% (1.8%). A total of 7 EMS practices across 3 domains (training, cardiopulmonary resuscitation [CPR], and transport) were associated with higher rates of risk-standardized favorable neurological survival. EMS agencies with higher favorable neurological survival rates were more likely to use simulation to assess CPR competency (β = 0.54; P = .05), perform frequent reassessment (at least once every 6 months) of CPR competency in new staff (β = 0.51; P = .04), use full multiperson scenario simulation for ongoing skills training (β = 0.48; P = .01), perform simulation training at least every 6 months (β = 0.63; P &lt; .001), and conduct training in the use of mechanical CPR devices at least once annually (β = 0.43; P = .04). EMS agencies with higher risk-standardized favorable neurological survival were also more likely to use CPR feedback devices (β = 0.58; P = .007) and to transport patients to a designated cardiac arrest or ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction receiving center (β = 0.57; P = .003). Adoption of more than half (≥4) of the 7 practices was more common at EMS agencies in the highest quartile of favorable neurological survival rates (70 of 118 agencies [59.3%]) vs the lowest quartile (42 of 118 agencies [35.6%]) (P &lt; .001).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In a national registry for OHCA, 7 practices associated with higher rates of favorable neurological survival were identified at EMS agencies. Given wide variability in neurological survival across EMS agencies, these findings provide initial insights into EMS practices associated with top-performing EMS agencies in OHCA survival. Future studies are needed to validate these findings and identify best practices for EMS agencies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837166/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38837166</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1189>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1189</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38837166</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Saket Girotra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kimberly C Dukes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica Sperling</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kevin Kennedy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marina Del Rios</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Remle Crowe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ashish R Panchal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas Rea</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bryan F McNally</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul S Chan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Emergency Medical Service Agency Practices and Cardiac Arrest Survival</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38837166</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1189</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Social Vulnerability and Poor Health Outcomes: There Is No Nadir</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837142/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1298. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837142/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38837142</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1298>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1298</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38837142</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Clyde W Yancy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sadiya S Khan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Social Vulnerability and Poor Health Outcomes: There Is No Nadir</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38837142</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1298</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Neighborhood Social Vulnerability and Premature Cardiovascular Disease in Haiti</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837139/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In urban Haiti, individuals living in neighborhoods with the highest social vulnerability had greater prevalence of hypertension and HF. Understanding CVD disparities in low-income countries is essential for targeting prevention and treatment interventions toward populations at highest risk globally.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1286. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">IMPORTANCE: Higher social vulnerability is associated with premature cardiovascular disease (CVD) and mortality but is understudied in low-income countries that have both the highest magnitude of social vulnerability and a growing CVD epidemic.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the association between social vulnerability and hypertension, CVD, and CVD subtypes in Haiti as a model for similar low-income countries.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: This population-based cohort study used enrollment data from adults participating in the Haiti Cardiovascular Disease Cohort Study. Recruitment occurred via multistage random sampling throughout slum and urban neighborhoods in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, from March 2019 to August 2021. Data were analyzed from May 2022 to December 2023.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">EXPOSURES: A modified Haitian Social Vulnerability Index (SVI-H) was created following the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Social Vulnerability Index method. Twelve variables across the domains of socioeconomic status, household characteristics, and social and community context were included. The SVI-H was calculated for each study neighborhood block and then stratified into SVI-H quartiles (quartile 1 was the least vulnerable; quartile 4, the most vulnerable).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: Prevalent hypertension and total CVD, defined as heart failure (HF), stroke, transient ischemic attack (TIA), angina, or myocardial infarction (MI). Age-adjusted Poisson regression analysis yielded prevalence ratios (PRs) comparing the prevalence of hypertension, total CVD, and CVD subtypes across SVI-H quartiles.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among 2925 adults (1704 [58.3%] female; mean [SD] age, 41.9 [15.9] years), the prevalence of hypertension was 32.8% (95% CI, 31.1%-34.5%) and the prevalence of CVD was 14.7% (95% CI, 13.5%-16.0%). Hypertension prevalence ranged from 26.2% (95% CI, 23.1%-29.3%) to 38.4% (95% CI, 34.8%-42.0%) between quartiles 1 and 4, while CVD prevalence ranged from 11.1% (95% CI, 8.8%-13.3%) to 19.7% (95% CI, 16.8%-22.6%). SVI-H quartile 4 vs 1 was associated with a greater prevalence of hypertension (PR, 1.17; 95% CI, 1.02-1.34) and CVD (PR, 1.48; 95% CI, 1.16-1.89). Among CVD subtypes, SVI-H was significantly associated with HF (PR, 1.64; 95% CI, 1.23-2.18) but not with combined stroke and TIA or combined angina and MI.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In urban Haiti, individuals living in neighborhoods with the highest social vulnerability had greater prevalence of hypertension and HF. Understanding CVD disparities in low-income countries is essential for targeting prevention and treatment interventions toward populations at highest risk globally.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38837139/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38837139</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1286>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1286</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38837139</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nicholas L S Roberts</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rodney Sufra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lily D Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Reichling St Sauveur</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph Inddy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Youry Macius</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michel Théard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Myung Hee Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nour Mourra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rehana Rasul</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Denis Nash</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marie M Deschamps</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Monika M Safford</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jean W Pape</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vanessa Rouzier</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Margaret L McNairy</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Neighborhood Social Vulnerability and Premature Cardiovascular Disease in Haiti</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38837139</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.1286</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aortic Valve Stenosis Causes Accumulation of Extracellular Hemoglobin and Systemic Endothelial Dysfunction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38836358/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: AS increases postvalvular swirling blood flow in the central ascending aorta, triggering RBC fragmentation with the accumulation of hemoglobin in the plasma. This increases NO consumption in blood, thereby limiting vascular NO bioavailability. Thus, AS itself promotes systemic endothelial dysfunction independent of other established risk factors. Transcatheter aortic valve replacement is capable of limiting NO scavenging and rescuing endothelial function by realigning postvalvular...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.064747. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Whether aortic valve stenosis (AS) can adversely affect systemic endothelial function independently of standard modifiable cardiovascular risk factors is unknown.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We therefore investigated endothelial and cardiac function in an experimental model of AS mice devoid of standard modifiable cardiovascular risk factors and human cohorts with AS scheduled for transcatheter aortic valve replacement. Endothelial function was determined by flow-mediated dilation using ultrasound. Extracellular hemoglobin (eHb) concentrations and NO consumption were determined in blood plasma of mice and humans by ELISA and chemiluminescence. This was complemented by measurements of aortic blood flow using 4-dimensional flow acquisition by magnetic resonance imaging and computational fluid dynamics simulations. The effects of plasma and red blood cell (RBC) suspensions on vascular function were determined in transfer experiments in a murine vasorelaxation bioassay system.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: In mice, the induction of AS caused systemic endothelial dysfunction. In the presence of normal systolic left ventricular function and mild hypertrophy, the increase in the transvalvular gradient was associated with elevated eryptosis, increased eHb and plasma NO consumption; eHb sequestration by haptoglobin restored endothelial function. Because the aortic valve orifice area in patients with AS decreased, postvalvular mechanical stress in the central ascending aorta increased. This was associated with elevated eHb, circulating RBC-derived microvesicles, eryptotic cells, lower haptoglobin levels without clinically relevant anemia, and consecutive endothelial dysfunction. Transfer experiments demonstrated that reduction of eHb by treatment with haptoglobin or elimination of fluid dynamic stress by transcatheter aortic valve replacement restored endothelial function. In patients with AS and subclinical RBC fragmentation, the remaining circulating RBCs before and after transcatheter aortic valve replacement exhibited intact membrane function, deformability, and resistance to osmotic and hypoxic stress.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: AS increases postvalvular swirling blood flow in the central ascending aorta, triggering RBC fragmentation with the accumulation of hemoglobin in the plasma. This increases NO consumption in blood, thereby limiting vascular NO bioavailability. Thus, AS itself promotes systemic endothelial dysfunction independent of other established risk factors. Transcatheter aortic valve replacement is capable of limiting NO scavenging and rescuing endothelial function by realigning postvalvular blood flow to near physiological patterns.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">REGISTRATION: URL: https://www.clinicaltrials.gov; Unique identifier: NCT05603520. URL: https://www.clinicaltrials.gov; Unique identifier: NCT01805739.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38836358/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38836358</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.064747>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.064747</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38836358</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Christine Quast</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Florian Bönner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amin Polzin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Verena Veulemans</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ramesh Chennupati</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabella Gyamfi Poku</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Susanne Pfeiler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicolas Kramser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Magdalena Nankinova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicole Staub</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elric Zweck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Juliane Jokiel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fabian Keyser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jasmina Hoffe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sven Witkowski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katrin Becker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pia Leuders</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saif Zako</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ralf Erkens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christian Jung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ulrich Flögel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianai Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Neidlin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ulrich Steinseifer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sven Thomas Niepmann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sebastian Zimmer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Norbert Gerdes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Miriam M Cortese-Krott</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin Feelisch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tobias Zeus</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Malte Kelm</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Aortic Valve Stenosis Causes Accumulation of Extracellular Hemoglobin and Systemic Endothelial Dysfunction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38836358</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.064747</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>IRE1α Mediates the Hypertrophic Growth of Cardiomyocytes Through Facilitating the Formation of Initiation Complex to Promote the Translation of TOP-Motif Transcripts</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38836349/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: These studies suggest a noncanonical, essential role of IRE1α in orchestrating protein synthesis, which may have important implications in cardiac hypertrophy in response to pressure overload and general cell growth under other physiological and pathological conditions.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 5. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067606. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Cardiomyocyte growth is coupled with active protein synthesis, which is one of the basic biological processes in living cells. However, it is unclear whether the unfolded protein response transducers and effectors directly take part in the control of protein synthesis. The connection between critical functions of the unfolded protein response in cellular physiology and requirements of multiple processes for cell growth prompted us to investigate the role of the unfolded protein response in cell growth and underlying molecular mechanisms.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Cardiomyocyte-specific inositol-requiring enzyme 1α (IRE1α) knockout and overexpression mouse models were generated to explore its function in vivo. Neonatal rat ventricular myocytes were isolated and cultured to evaluate the role of IRE1α in cardiomyocyte growth in vitro. Mass spectrometry was conducted to identify novel interacting proteins of IRE1α. Ribosome sequencing and polysome profiling were performed to determine the molecular basis for the function of IRE1α in translational control.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: We show that IRE1α is required for cell growth in neonatal rat ventricular myocytes under prohypertrophy treatment and in HEK293 cells in response to serum stimulation. At the molecular level, IRE1α directly interacts with eIF4G and eIF3, 2 critical components of the translation initiation complex. We demonstrate that IRE1α facilitates the formation of the translation initiation complex around the endoplasmic reticulum and preferentially initiates the translation of transcripts with 5' terminal oligopyrimidine motifs. We then reveal that IRE1α plays an important role in determining the selectivity and translation of these transcripts. We next show that IRE1α stimulates the translation of epidermal growth factor receptor through an unannotated terminal oligopyrimidine motif in its 5' untranslated region. We further demonstrate a physiological role of IRE1α-governed protein translation by showing that IRE1α is essential for cardiomyocyte growth and cardiac functional maintenance under hemodynamic stress in vivo.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: These studies suggest a noncanonical, essential role of IRE1α in orchestrating protein synthesis, which may have important implications in cardiac hypertrophy in response to pressure overload and general cell growth under other physiological and pathological conditions.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38836349/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38836349</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067606>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067606</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38836349</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Chao Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shiqian Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guangyu Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qinfeng Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weidan Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoding Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jane A Cook</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Miesje van der Stoel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bradley W Wright</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Francisco Altamirano</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erica L Niewold</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jungsoo Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Garrett Kimble</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pengfei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiang Luo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hery Urra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Herman I May</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anwarul Ferdous</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xue-Nan Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingfeng Deng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elina Ikonen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Claudio Hetz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Randal J Kaufman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kezhong Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas G Gillette</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Philipp E Scherer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph A Hill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jin Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhao V Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>IRE1α Mediates the Hypertrophic Growth of Cardiomyocytes Through Facilitating the Formation of Initiation Complex to Promote the Translation of TOP-Motif Transcripts</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38836349</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067606</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Emergency department visit for atrial fibrillation: sex differences in treatment and outcomes in the Global RE-LY AF Registry</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833334/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 4:ehae319. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae319. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833334/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38833334</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae319>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae319</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38833334</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Linda S Johnson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuxuan Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Judy Luu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabelle C Van Gelder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clare Atzema</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Conen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marielle Kloosterman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Luciana Armaganijan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stuart J Connolly</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael D Ezekowitz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lars Wallentin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabelle Johansson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William F McIntyre</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jonas Oldgren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey S Healey</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Emergency department visit for atrial fibrillation: sex differences in treatment and outcomes in the Global RE-LY AF Registry</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38833334</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae319</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An explosive heart: long-term outcome of intramyocardial dissecting haematoma</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833333/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 4:ehae310. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae310. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833333/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38833333</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae310>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae310</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38833333</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Marina Leitman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shmuel Fuchs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ram Sharony</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>An explosive heart: long-term outcome of intramyocardial dissecting haematoma</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38833333</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae310</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The role of natural compensatory mechanisms in complex congenital heart disease: haemodynamic evolution and clinical outcomes in a case of Cor triatriatum sinistrum syndrome</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833332/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 4:ehae354. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae354. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833332/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38833332</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae354>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae354</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38833332</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Guoliang Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yun Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zheng Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>The role of natural compensatory mechanisms in complex congenital heart disease: haemodynamic evolution and clinical outcomes in a case of Cor triatriatum sinistrum syndrome</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38833332</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae354</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Correction to: Epidemiology of heart failure in young adults: a French nationwide cohort study</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833330/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 4:ehae187. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae187. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38833330/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38833330</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae187>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae187</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38833330</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Correction to: Epidemiology of heart failure in young adults: a French nationwide cohort study</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38833330</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae187</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Forecasting the Economic Burden of Cardiovascular Disease and Stroke in the United States Through 2050: A Presidential Advisory From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832515/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: The economic burden of cardiovascular risk factors and overt cardiovascular disease in the United States is projected to increase substantially in the coming decades. Development and deployment of cost-effective programs and policies to promote cardiovascular health are urgently needed to rein in costs and to equitably enhance population health.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001258. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Quantifying the economic burden of cardiovascular disease and stroke over the coming decades may inform policy, health system, and community-level interventions for prevention and treatment.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We used nationally representative health, economic, and demographic data to project health care costs attributable to key cardiovascular risk factors (hypertension, diabetes, hypercholesterolemia) and conditions (coronary heart disease, stroke, heart failure, atrial fibrillation) through 2050. The human capital approach was used to estimate productivity losses from morbidity and premature mortality due to cardiovascular conditions.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: One in 3 US adults received care for a cardiovascular risk factor or condition in 2020. Annual inflation-adjusted (2022 US dollars) health care costs of cardiovascular risk factors are projected to triple between 2020 and 2050, from $400 billion to $1344 billion. For cardiovascular conditions, annual health care costs are projected to almost quadruple, from $393 billion to $1490 billion, and productivity losses are projected to increase by 54%, from $234 billion to $361 billion. Stroke is projected to account for the largest absolute increase in costs. Large relative increases among the Asian American population (497%) and Hispanic American population (489%) reflect the projected increases in the size of these populations.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: The economic burden of cardiovascular risk factors and overt cardiovascular disease in the United States is projected to increase substantially in the coming decades. Development and deployment of cost-effective programs and policies to promote cardiovascular health are urgently needed to rein in costs and to equitably enhance population health.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832515/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38832515</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001258>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001258</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38832515</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Dhruv S Kazi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mitchell S V Elkind</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anne Deutsch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William N Dowd</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul Heidenreich</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olga Khavjou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel Mark</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael E Mussolino</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bruce Ovbiagele</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sonali S Patel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Remy Poudel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ben Weittenhiller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tiffany M Powell-Wiley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karen E Joynt Maddox</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Forecasting the Economic Burden of Cardiovascular Disease and Stroke in the United States Through 2050: A Presidential Advisory From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38832515</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001258</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicting the Future Prevalence of Cardiovascular Disease: The Good, the Bad, the Known, and the Unknown</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832514/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070265. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832514/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38832514</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070265>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070265</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38832514</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Andrew E Moran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee Goldman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Predicting the Future Prevalence of Cardiovascular Disease: The Good, the Bad, the Known, and the Unknown</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38832514</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070265</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Projections of Soaring Costs Are a Call to Arms</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832507/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070266. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832507/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38832507</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070266>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070266</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38832507</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth A Magnuson</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Projections of Soaring Costs Are a Call to Arms</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38832507</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070266</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Forecasting the Burden of Cardiovascular Disease and Stroke in the United States Through 2050-Prevalence of Risk Factors and Disease: A Presidential Advisory From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832505/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: The prevalence of many cardiovascular risk factors and most established diseases will increase over the next 30 years. Clinical and public health interventions are needed to effectively manage, stem, and even reverse these adverse trends.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001256. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Cardiovascular disease and stroke are common and costly, and their prevalence is rising. Forecasts on the prevalence of risk factors and clinical events are crucial.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Using the 2015 to March 2020 National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey and 2015 to 2019 Medical Expenditure Panel Survey, we estimated trends in prevalence for cardiovascular risk factors based on adverse levels of Life's Essential 8 and clinical cardiovascular disease and stroke. We projected through 2050, overall and by age and race and ethnicity, accounting for changes in disease prevalence and demographics.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: We estimate that among adults, prevalence of hypertension will increase from 51.2% in 2020 to 61.0% in 2050. Diabetes (16.3% to 26.8%) and obesity (43.1% to 60.6%) will increase, whereas hypercholesterolemia will decline (45.8% to 24.0%). The prevalences of poor diet, inadequate physical activity, and smoking are estimated to improve over time, whereas inadequate sleep will worsen. Prevalences of coronary disease (7.8% to 9.2%), heart failure (2.7% to 3.8%), stroke (3.9% to 6.4%), atrial fibrillation (1.7% to 2.4%), and total cardiovascular disease (11.3% to 15.0%) will rise. Clinical CVD will affect 45 million adults, and CVD including hypertension will affect more than 184 million adults by 2050 (>;61%). Similar trends are projected in children. Most adverse trends are projected to be worse among people identifying as American Indian/Alaska Native or multiracial, Black, or Hispanic.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: The prevalence of many cardiovascular risk factors and most established diseases will increase over the next 30 years. Clinical and public health interventions are needed to effectively manage, stem, and even reverse these adverse trends.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832505/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38832505</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001256>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001256</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38832505</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Karen E Joynt Maddox</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mitchell S V Elkind</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hugo J Aparicio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yvonne Commodore-Mensah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah D de Ferranti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William N Dowd</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Adrian F Hernandez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olga Khavjou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erin D Michos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Latha Palaniappan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joanne Penko</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Remy Poudel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Véronique L Roger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dhruv S Kazi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Forecasting the Burden of Cardiovascular Disease and Stroke in the United States Through 2050-Prevalence of Risk Factors and Disease: A Presidential Advisory From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38832505</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001256</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cerebrovascular Effects of Sildenafil in Small Vessel Disease: The OxHARP Trial</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832504/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Sildenafil did not reduce pulsatility but increased cerebrovascular reactivity and perfusion. Sildenafil merits further study to determine whether it prevents the clinical sequelae of small vessel disease.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 4. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324327. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Vascular cognitive impairment due to cerebral small vessel disease is associated with cerebral pulsatility, white matter hypoperfusion, and reduced cerebrovascular reactivity (CVR), and is potentially improved by endothelium-targeted drugs such as cilostazol. Whether sildenafil, a phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitor, improves cerebrovascular dysfunction is unknown.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: OxHARP trial (Oxford Haemodynamic Adaptation to Reduce Pulsatility) was a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, 3-way crossover trial after nonembolic cerebrovascular events with mild-moderate white matter hyperintensities (WMH), the most prevalent manifestation of cerebral small vessel disease. The primary outcome assessed the superiority of 3 weeks of sildenafil 50 mg thrice daily versus placebo (mixed-effect linear models) on middle cerebral artery pulsatility, derived from peak systolic and end-diastolic velocities (transcranial ultrasound), with noninferiority to cilostazol 100 mg twice daily. Secondary end points included the following: cerebrovascular reactivity during inhalation of air, 4% and 6% CO<sub>2</sub> on transcranial ultrasound (transcranial ultrasound-CVR); blood oxygen-level dependent-magnetic resonance imaging within WMH (CVR-WMH) and normal-appearing white matter (CVR-normal-appearing white matter); cerebral perfusion by arterial spin labeling (magnetic resonance imaging pseudocontinuous arterial spin labeling); and resistance by cerebrovascular conductance. Adverse effects were compared by Cochran Q.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: In 65/75 (87%) patients (median, 70 years;79% male) with valid primary outcome data, cerebral pulsatility was unchanged on sildenafil versus placebo (0.02, -0.01 to 0.05; <i>P</i>=0.18), or versus cilostazol (-0.01, -0.04 to 0.02; <i>P</i>=0.36), despite increased blood flow (∆ peak systolic velocity, 6.3 cm/s, 3.5-9.07; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001; ∆ end-diastolic velocity, 1.98, 0.66-3.29; <i>P</i>=0.004). Secondary outcomes improved on sildenafil versus placebo for CVR-transcranial ultrasound (0.83 cm/s per mm Hg, 0.23-1.42; <i>P</i>=0.007), CVR-WMH (0.07, 0-0.14; <i>P</i>=0.043), CVR-normal-appearing white matter (0.06, 0.00-0.12; <i>P</i>=0.048), perfusion (WMH: 1.82 mL/100 g per minutes, 0.5-3.15; <i>P</i>=0.008; and normal-appearing white matter, 2.12, 0.66-3.6; <i>P</i>=0.006) and cerebrovascular resistance (sildenafil-placebo: 0.08, 0.05-0.10; <i>P</i>=4.9×10<sup>-8</sup>; cilostazol-placebo, 0.06, 0.03-0.09; <i>P</i>=5.1×10<sup>-</sup><sup>5</sup>). Both drugs increased headaches (<i>P</i>=1.1×10<sup>-</sup><sup>4</sup>), while cilostazol increased moderate-severe diarrhea (<i>P</i>=0.013).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Sildenafil did not reduce pulsatility but increased cerebrovascular reactivity and perfusion. Sildenafil merits further study to determine whether it prevents the clinical sequelae of small vessel disease.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">REGISTRATION: URL: https://www.clinicaltrials.gov; Unique identifier: NCT03855332.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38832504/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38832504</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324327>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324327</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38832504</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Alastair J S Webb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jacqueline Birks</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karolina A Feakins</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amy Lawson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jesse Dawson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexander M K Rothman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David J Werring</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Osian Llwyd</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Catriona Stewart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cerebrovascular Effects of Sildenafil in Small Vessel Disease: The OxHARP Trial</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38832504</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324327</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Seeing is Believing: Muscleblind-like 1 Is Necessary For Mammalian Cardiomyocyte Maturation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829935/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4;149(23):1830-1832. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068657. Epub 2024 Jun 3.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829935/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38829935</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC11149904/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">PMC11149904</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068657>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068657</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38829935</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Khalid B Dar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shah R Ali</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Seeing is Believing: Muscleblind-like 1 Is Necessary For Mammalian Cardiomyocyte Maturation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38829935</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>pmc:PMC11149904</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068657</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Implanted Human Cardiac Spheroids Electrically Couple With Infarcted Swine Myocardium</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829934/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4;149(23):1855-1857. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068568. Epub 2024 Jun 3.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829934/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38829934</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC11149905/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">PMC11149905</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068568>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068568</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38829934</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bijay Guragain</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuhua Wei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hanyu Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Asher Kahn-Krell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Ye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory P Walcott</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jack M Rogers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianyi Jay Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Implanted Human Cardiac Spheroids Electrically Couple With Infarcted Swine Myocardium</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38829934</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>pmc:PMC11149905</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068568</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Future of Clinical Trials</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829933/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4;149(23):1783-1785. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066982. Epub 2024 Jun 3.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829933/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38829933</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066982>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066982</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38829933</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Faiez Zannad</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bertram Pitt</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>The Future of Clinical Trials</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38829933</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066982</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Wide Complex Tachycardia</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829932/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4;149(23):1852-1854. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069785. Epub 2024 Jun 3.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829932/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38829932</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069785>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069785</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38829932</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Chan-Hee Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emily Higgs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Melvin M Scheinman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>A Wide Complex Tachycardia</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38829932</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069785</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pharmacogenetic Influences Over Mavacamten Pharmacokinetics: Considerations for the Treatment of Individuals With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829931/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 4;149(23):1786-1788. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066916. Epub 2024 Jun 3.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38829931/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38829931</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066916>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066916</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38829931</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kathryn A McGurk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nagme Bilgehan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James S Ware</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Pharmacogenetic Influences Over Mavacamten Pharmacokinetics: Considerations for the Treatment of Individuals With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38829931</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.066916</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genetic Architecture and Clinical Outcomes of Combined Lipid Disturbances</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38828614/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240605180834&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Simultaneous assessment of multiple lipid derangements revealed nuanced differences in coronary artery disease risk and genetic architectures across dyslipoproteinemia subtypes. These findings highlight the importance of looking beyond single lipid traits to better understand combined lipid and lipoprotein phenotypes and implications for disease risk.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 3. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323973. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Dyslipoproteinemia often involves simultaneous derangements of multiple lipid traits. We aimed to evaluate the phenotypic and genetic characteristics of combined lipid disturbances in a general population-based cohort.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Among UK Biobank participants without prevalent coronary artery disease, we used blood lipid and apolipoprotein B concentrations to ascribe individuals into 1 of 6 reproducible and mutually exclusive dyslipoproteinemia subtypes. Incident coronary artery disease risk was estimated for each subtype using Cox proportional hazards models. Phenome-wide analyses and genome-wide association studies were performed for each subtype, followed by in silico causal gene prioritization and heritability analyses. Additionally, the prevalence of disruptive variants in causal genes for Mendelian lipid disorders was assessed using whole-exome sequence data.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among 450 636 UK Biobank participants: 63 (0.01%) had chylomicronemia; 40 005 (8.9%) had hypercholesterolemia; 94 785 (21.0%) had combined hyperlipidemia; 13 998 (3.1%) had remnant hypercholesterolemia; 110 389 (24.5%) had hypertriglyceridemia; and 49 (0.01%) had mixed hypertriglyceridemia and hypercholesterolemia. Over a median (interquartile range) follow-up of 11.1 (10.4-11.8) years, incident coronary artery disease risk varied across subtypes, with combined hyperlipidemia exhibiting the largest hazard (hazard ratio, 1.92 [95% CI, 1.84-2.01]; <i>P</i>=2×10<sup>-16</sup>), even when accounting for non-HDL-C (hazard ratio, 1.45 [95% CI, 1.30-1.60]; <i>P</i>=2.6×10<sup>-12</sup>). Genome-wide association studies revealed 250 loci significantly associated with dyslipoproteinemia subtypes, of which 72 (28.8%) were not detected in prior single lipid trait genome-wide association studies. Mendelian lipid variant carriers were rare (2.0%) among individuals with dyslipoproteinemia, but polygenic heritability was high, ranging from 23% for remnant hypercholesterolemia to 54% for combined hyperlipidemia.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Simultaneous assessment of multiple lipid derangements revealed nuanced differences in coronary artery disease risk and genetic architectures across dyslipoproteinemia subtypes. These findings highlight the importance of looking beyond single lipid traits to better understand combined lipid and lipoprotein phenotypes and implications for disease risk.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38828614/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240605180834&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38828614</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323973>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323973</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38828614</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Thomas Gilliland</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jacqueline S Dron</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Margaret Sunitha Selvaraj</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark Trinder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kaavya Paruchuri</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah M Urbut</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sara Haidermota</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rachel Bernardo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Md Mesbah Uddin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael C Honigberg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gina M Peloso</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pradeep Natarajan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Genetic Architecture and Clinical Outcomes of Combined Lipid Disturbances</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38828614</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323973</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>