<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;v=2.18.0&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;v=2.18.0&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 22:07:58 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Acid-sensing ion channel 1a blockade reduces myocardial injury in rodent models of myocardial infarction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095341/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 14:ehad793. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad793. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095341/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38095341</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad793>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad793</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38095341</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Meredith A Redd</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yusuke Yoshikawa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nemat Khan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maleeha Waqar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Natalie J Saez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer E Outhwaite</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jake S Russell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amy D Hanna</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Han S Chiu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sing Yan Er</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Neville J Butcher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karine Mardon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John F Fraser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark L Smythe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lachlan D Rash</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Walter G Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Glenn F King</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Melissa E Reichelt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nathan J Palpant</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Acid-sensing ion channel 1a blockade reduces myocardial injury in rodent models of myocardial infarction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38095341</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad793</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Transcatheter aortic valve replacement in patients with cardiogenic shock: safe and effective, but the most critical patients require further investigations</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095334/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 14:ehad808. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad808. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095334/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38095334</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad808>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad808</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38095334</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Pierre-Guillaume Piriou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Julien Plessis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrice Guerin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Transcatheter aortic valve replacement in patients with cardiogenic shock: safe and effective, but the most critical patients require further investigations</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38095334</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad808</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Troponin I Tyrosine Phosphorylation Beneficially Accelerates Diastolic Function</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095088/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: We have demonstrated that tyrosine kinase phosphorylation of TnI is a novel mechanism to directly and beneficially accelerate myocardial relaxation in vivo.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2023 Dec 14. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323132. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: A healthy heart is able to modify its function and increase relaxation through posttranslational modifications of myofilament proteins. While there are known examples of serine/threonine kinases directly phosphorylating myofilament proteins to modify heart function, the roles of tyrosine (Y) phosphorylation to directly modify heart function have not been demonstrated. The myofilament protein TnI (troponin I) is the inhibitory subunit of the troponin complex and is a key regulator of cardiac contraction and relaxation. We previously demonstrated that TnI-Y26 phosphorylation decreases calcium-sensitive force development and accelerates calcium dissociation, suggesting a novel role for tyrosine kinase-mediated TnI-Y26 phosphorylation to regulate cardiac relaxation. Therefore, we hypothesize that increasing TnI-Y26 phosphorylation will increase cardiac relaxation in vivo and be beneficial during pathological diastolic dysfunction.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: The signaling pathway involved in TnI-Y26 phosphorylation was predicted in silico and validated by tyrosine kinase activation and inhibition in primary adult murine cardiomyocytes. To investigate how TnI-Y26 phosphorylation affects cardiac muscle, structure, and function in vivo, we developed a novel TnI-Y26 phosphorylation-mimetic mouse that was subjected to echocardiography, pressure-volume loop hemodynamics, and myofibril mechanical studies. TnI-Y26 phosphorylation-mimetic mice were further subjected to the nephrectomy/deoxycorticosterone acetate model of diastolic dysfunction to investigate the effects of increased TnI-Y26 phosphorylation in disease.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Src tyrosine kinase is sufficient to phosphorylate TnI-Y26 in cardiomyocytes. TnI-Y26 phosphorylation accelerates in vivo relaxation without detrimental structural or systolic impairment. In a mouse model of diastolic dysfunction, TnI-Y26 phosphorylation is beneficial and protects against the development of disease.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: We have demonstrated that tyrosine kinase phosphorylation of TnI is a novel mechanism to directly and beneficially accelerate myocardial relaxation in vivo.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095088/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38095088</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323132>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323132</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38095088</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Lorien G Salyer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hussam E Salhi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth A Brundage</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vikram Shettigar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah L Sturgill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Helena Zanella</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benjamin Templeton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eaman Abay</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kathryn M Emmer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeovanna Lowe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jill A Rafael-Fortney</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Narasimham Parinandi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>D Brian Foster</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Timothy A McKinsey</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kathleen C Woulfe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark T Ziolo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brandon J Biesiadecki</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Troponin I Tyrosine Phosphorylation Beneficially Accelerates Diastolic Function</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38095088</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323132</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Role of &lt;em>;MAPRE2&lt;/em>; and Microtubules in Maintaining Normal Ventricular Conduction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095085/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Genetic ablation of mapre2 led to a decrease in voltage-gated sodium channel function, a hallmark of Brugada syndrome, associated with disruption of adherens junctions, decrease of detyrosinated tubulin as a marker of microtubule stability, and changes in microtubule dynamics. Restoration of the detyrosinated tubulin fraction with ttl knockdown led to rescue of voltage-gated sodium channel-related functional parameters in mapre2 knockout hearts. Taken together, our study implicates...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2023 Dec 14. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323231. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: The Brugada syndrome is associated with loss-of-function <i>SCN5A</i> variants, yet these account for only ≈20% of cases. A recent genome-wide association study identified a novel locus within <i>MAPRE2</i>, which encodes EB (microtubule end-binding protein) 2, implicating microtubule involvement in the Brugada syndrome.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: A <i>mapre2</i> knockout zebra fish model was generated using CRISPR/Cas9 (clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats/clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeat-associated 9) and validated by Western blot. Larval hearts at 5 days post-fertilization were isolated for voltage mapping and immunocytochemistry. Adult fish hearts were used for ECG, patch clamping, and immunocytochemistry. Morpholinos were injected into embryos at 1-cell stage for knockdown experiments. A transgenic zebra fish line with <i>cdh2</i> tandem fluorescent timer was used to study adherens junctions. Microtubule plus-end tracking and patch clamping were performed in human iPSC-derived cardiomyocytes with <i>MAPRE2</i> knockdown and knockout, respectively.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Voltage mapping of <i>mapre2</i> knockout hearts showed a decrease in ventricular maximum upstroke velocity of the action potential and conduction velocity, suggesting loss of cardiac voltage-gated sodium channel function. ECG showed QRS prolongation in adult knockout fish, and patch clamping showed decreased sodium current density in knockout ventricular myocytes and arrhythmias in knockout iPSC cardiomyocytes. Confocal imaging showed disorganized adherens junctions and mislocalization of mature Ncad (N-cadherin) with <i>mapre2</i> loss of function, associated with a decrease of detyrosinated tubulin. <i>MAPRE2</i> knockdown in iPSC cardiomyocytes led to an increase in microtubule growth velocity and distance, indicating changes in microtubule dynamics. Finally, knockdown of <i>ttl</i> encoding tubulin tyrosine ligase in <i>mapre2</i> knockout larvae rescued tubulin detyrosination and ventricular maximum upstroke velocity of the action potential.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Genetic ablation of <i>mapre2</i> led to a decrease in voltage-gated sodium channel function, a hallmark of Brugada syndrome, associated with disruption of adherens junctions, decrease of detyrosinated tubulin as a marker of microtubule stability, and changes in microtubule dynamics. Restoration of the detyrosinated tubulin fraction with <i>ttl</i> knockdown led to rescue of voltage-gated sodium channel-related functional parameters in <i>mapre2</i> knockout hearts. Taken together, our study implicates microtubule dynamics in the modulation of ventricular conduction.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095085/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38095085</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323231>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323231</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38095085</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>David Y Chiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arie O Verkerk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rachelle Victorio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Boris I Shneyer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Babet van der Vaart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mariam Jouni</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nakul Narendran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ashmita Kc</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James R Sampognaro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Franki Vetrano-Olsen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John S Oh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eva Buys</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Berend de Jonge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Disheet A Shah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tuomas Kiviniemi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul W Burridge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Connie R Bezzina</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anna Akhmanova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Calum A MacRae</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>The Role of &lt;em>;MAPRE2&lt;/em>; and Microtubules in Maintaining Normal Ventricular Conduction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38095085</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323231</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Current Status and Principles for the Treatment and Prevention of Diabetic Foot Ulcers in the Cardiovascular Patient Population: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095068/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Despite the known higher risk of cardiovascular disease in individuals with type 2 diabetes, the pathophysiology and optimal management of diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs), a leading complication associated with diabetes, is complex and continues to evolve. Complications of type 2 diabetes, such as DFUs, are a major cause of morbidity and mortality and the leading cause of major lower extremity amputation in the United States. There has recently been a strong focus on the prevention and early...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2023 Dec 14. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001192. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite the known higher risk of cardiovascular disease in individuals with type 2 diabetes, the pathophysiology and optimal management of diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs), a leading complication associated with diabetes, is complex and continues to evolve. Complications of type 2 diabetes, such as DFUs, are a major cause of morbidity and mortality and the leading cause of major lower extremity amputation in the United States. There has recently been a strong focus on the prevention and early treatment of DFUs, leading to the development of multidisciplinary diabetic wound and amputation prevention clinics across the country. Mounting evidence has shown that, despite these efforts, amputations associated with DFUs continue to increase. Furthermore, due to increasing patient complexity of management secondary to comorbid conditions, such as cardiovascular disease, the management of peripheral artery disease associated with DFUs has become increasingly difficult, and care delivery is often episodic and fragmented. Although structured, process-specific approaches exist at individual institutions for the management of DFUs in the cardiovascular patient population, there is insufficient awareness of these principles in the general medicine communities. Furthermore, there is growing interest in better understanding the mechanistic underpinnings of DFUs to better define personalized medicine to improve outcomes. The goals of this scientific statement are to provide salient background information on the complex pathogenesis and current management of DFUs in cardiovascular patients, to guide therapeutic and preventive strategies and future research directions, and to inform public policy makers on health disparities and other barriers to improving and advancing care in this expanding patient population.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38095068/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38095068</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001192>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001192</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38095068</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Katherine A Gallagher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph L Mills</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David G Armstrong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael S Conte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert S Kirsner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samantha D Minc</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jorge Plutzky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kevin W Southerland</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marjana Tomic-Canic</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Clinical Cardiology; and Council on Lifestyle and Cardiometabolic Health</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Current Status and Principles for the Treatment and Prevention of Diabetic Foot Ulcers in the Cardiovascular Patient Population: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38095068</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001192</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>New inflammatory predictors of cardiovascular events and the role of Mendelian randomizations</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38093458/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 14;44(47):4897-4901. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad804.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38093458/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38093458</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad804>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad804</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38093458</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>New inflammatory predictors of cardiovascular events and the role of Mendelian randomizations</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38093458</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad804</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Correction to: HFrEF phenotyping in real life</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092693/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad839. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad839. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092693/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38092693</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad839>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad839</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38092693</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Correction to: HFrEF phenotyping in real life</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38092693</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad839</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risks, 1990-2022</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092509/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023 Dec 19;82(25):2350-2473. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.007.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092509/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38092509</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.007>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.007</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38092509</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>George A Mensah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valentin Fuster</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher J L Murray</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory A Roth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risks Collaborators</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Global Burden of Cardiovascular Diseases and Risks, 1990-2022</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38092509</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.007</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A Heart-Healthy and Stroke-Free World: Using Data to Inform Global Action</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092508/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2023 Dec 19;82(25):2343-2349. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.003.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38092508/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38092508</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.003>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.003</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38092508</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>George A Mensah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valentin Fuster</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory A Roth</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>A Heart-Healthy and Stroke-Free World: Using Data to Inform Global Action</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38092508</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.003</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Spatiotemporal transcriptome atlas reveals the regional specification of the developing human brain</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091994/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Different functional regions of brain are fundamental for basic neurophysiological activities. However, the regional specification remains largely unexplored during human brain development. Here, by combining spatial transcriptomics (scStereo-seq) and scRNA-seq, we built a spatiotemporal developmental atlas of multiple human brain regions from 6-23 gestational weeks (GWs). We discovered that, around GW8, radial glia (RG) cells have displayed regional heterogeneity and specific spatial...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2023 Dec 2:S0092-8674(23)01233-3. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.016. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Different functional regions of brain are fundamental for basic neurophysiological activities. However, the regional specification remains largely unexplored during human brain development. Here, by combining spatial transcriptomics (scStereo-seq) and scRNA-seq, we built a spatiotemporal developmental atlas of multiple human brain regions from 6-23 gestational weeks (GWs). We discovered that, around GW8, radial glia (RG) cells have displayed regional heterogeneity and specific spatial distribution. Interestingly, we found that the regional heterogeneity of RG subtypes contributed to the subsequent neuronal specification. Specifically, two diencephalon-specific subtypes gave rise to glutamatergic and GABAergic neurons, whereas subtypes in ventral midbrain were associated with the dopaminergic neurons. Similar GABAergic neuronal subtypes were shared between neocortex and diencephalon. Additionally, we revealed that cell-cell interactions between oligodendrocyte precursor cells and GABAergic neurons influenced and promoted neuronal development coupled with regional specification. Altogether, this study provides comprehensive insights into the regional specification in the developing human brain.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091994/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38091994</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.016>10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.016</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38091994</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yanxin Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhongqiu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Changliang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Min Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ziqing He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Feiyang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuehong Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rong Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yunxia Gong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Binhong Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Baoguang Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chunyue Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hong Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peifu Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nana Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhifeng Wei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan-Ling Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Jin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peng Du</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ji Dong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianwei Jiao</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Spatiotemporal transcriptome atlas reveals the regional specification of the developing human brain</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38091994</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.016</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ineffective control of Epstein-Barr-virus-induced autoimmunity increases the risk for multiple sclerosis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091993/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a demyelinating disease of the CNS. Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) contributes to the MS pathogenesis because high levels of EBV EBNA(386-405)-specific antibodies cross react with the CNS-derived GlialCAM(370-389). However, it is unclear why only some individuals with such high autoreactive antibody titers develop MS. Here, we show that autoreactive cells are eliminated by distinct immune responses, which are determined by genetic variations of the host, as well as of the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2023 Dec 3:S0092-8674(23)01232-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.015. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a demyelinating disease of the CNS. Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) contributes to the MS pathogenesis because high levels of EBV EBNA<sub>386-405</sub>-specific antibodies cross react with the CNS-derived GlialCAM<sub>370-389</sub>. However, it is unclear why only some individuals with such high autoreactive antibody titers develop MS. Here, we show that autoreactive cells are eliminated by distinct immune responses, which are determined by genetic variations of the host, as well as of the infecting EBV and human cytomegalovirus (HCMV). We demonstrate that potent cytotoxic NKG2C<sup>+</sup> and NKG2D<sup>+</sup> natural killer (NK) cells and distinct EBV-specific T cell responses kill autoreactive GlialCAM<sub>370-389</sub>-specific cells. Furthermore, immune evasion of these autoreactive cells was induced by EBV-variant-specific upregulation of the immunomodulatory HLA-E. These defined virus and host genetic pre-dispositions are associated with an up to 260-fold increased risk of MS. Our findings thus allow the early identification of patients at risk for MS and suggest additional therapeutic options against MS.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091993/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38091993</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.015>10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38091993</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hannes Vietzen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah M Berger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura M Kühner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Philippe L Furlano</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gabriel Bsteh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas Berger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paulus Rommer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elisabeth Puchhammer-Stöckl</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Ineffective control of Epstein-Barr-virus-induced autoimmunity increases the risk for multiple sclerosis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38091993</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.11.015</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>JAMA Cardiology</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091001/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2023 Dec 1;8(12):1106. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3464.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38091001/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38091001</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3464>10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3464</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38091001</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>JAMA Cardiology</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38091001</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2022.3464</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonism by Eplerenone and Arterial Inflammation in HIV: The MIRABELLA HIV Study</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38090987/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSION AND RELEVANCE: In this small randomized clinical trial, eplerenone was associated with reduction in arterial inflammation among well-treated PWH without known CVD. In addition, reductions in arterial inflammation as measured by 18F-FDG PET/CT were related to improvements in stress myocardial perfusion. Further larger studies should explore whether eplerenone is a potential treatment strategy for inflammatory-mediated CVD in PWH.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2023 Dec 13. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2023.4578. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">IMPORTANCE: The risk for atherosclerotic disease is increased 1.5- to 2.0-fold among persons with HIV (PWH). Increased activation of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system may contribute to increased arterial inflammation in this population.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To determine the effects of eplerenone on arterial inflammation among well-treated PWH without known cardiovascular disease (CVD).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: Well-treated PWH who participated in the double-blinded, placebo-controlled, Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonism for Cardiovascular Health in HIV (MIRACLE HIV) study between February 2017 and March 2022 assessing the effects of eplerenone on myocardial perfusion were invited to participate in the Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonism By Eplerenone to Lower Arterial Inflammation in HIV (MIRABELLA) substudy if there was no current statin use. Participants were enrolled in the MIRABELLA study and underwent additional 18F-fludeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography/computed tomography (18F-FDG PET/CT) imaging of the aorta and carotid arteries to assess arterial inflammation over 12 months of treatment with eplerenone vs placebo.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">INTERVENTIONS: Eplerenone, 50 mg, twice a day vs identical placebo.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: The primary outcome was change in target to background ratio (TBR), a measure of arterial wall inflammation, in the index vessel after 12 months of treatment. The index vessel was defined as the vessel (aorta, left carotid artery, or right carotid artery) with the highest TBR at baseline in each participant.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A total of 26 participants (mean [SD] age, 54 [7] years; 18 male [69%]) were enrolled in the study. Treatment groups (eplerenone, 13 vs placebo, 13) were of similar age, sex, and body mass index. Eplerenone was associated with a reduction in TBR of the primary end point, the index vessel (eplerenone vs placebo: model treatment effect, -0.31; 95% CI, -0.50 to -0.11; P = .006; percentage change, -12.4% [IQR, -21.9% to -2.6%] vs 5.1% [IQR, -1.6% to 11.0%]; P = .003). We further observed a significant reduction of the TBR of the most diseased segment (MDS) of the index vessel (eplerenone vs placebo: -19.1% [IQR, -27.0% to -11.9%] vs 6.8% [IQR, -9.1% to 12.1%]; P = .007). A similar result was seen assessing the index vessel of the carotids (eplerenone vs placebo: -10.0% [IQR, -21.8% to 3.6%] vs 9.7% [IQR, -9.8% to 15.9%]; P = .046). Reduction in the TBR of MDS of the index vessel on 18F-FDG PET/CT correlated with improvement in the stress myocardial blood flow on cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (Spearman ρ = -0.67; P = .01).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSION AND RELEVANCE: In this small randomized clinical trial, eplerenone was associated with reduction in arterial inflammation among well-treated PWH without known CVD. In addition, reductions in arterial inflammation as measured by 18F-FDG PET/CT were related to improvements in stress myocardial perfusion. Further larger studies should explore whether eplerenone is a potential treatment strategy for inflammatory-mediated CVD in PWH.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">TRIAL REGISTRATION: ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT02740179.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38090987/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38090987</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2023.4578>10.1001/jamacardio.2023.4578</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38090987</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Suman Srinivasa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shady Abohashem</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Allie R Walpert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carolyn N Dunderdale</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sanjna Iyengar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Grace Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Jerosch-Herold</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher R deFilippi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory K Robbins</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hang Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Raymond Y Kwong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gail K Adler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ahmed Tawakol</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Steven K Grinspoon</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonism by Eplerenone and Arterial Inflammation in HIV: The MIRABELLA HIV Study</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38090987</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2023.4578</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ChatGPT hallucinating: can it get any more humanlike?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088452/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad766. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad766. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088452/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38088452</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad766>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad766</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38088452</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Konstantinos C Siontis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zachi I Attia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel J Asirvatham</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul A Friedman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>ChatGPT hallucinating: can it get any more humanlike?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38088452</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad766</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Residual leaks following percutaneous left atrial appendage occlusion and outcomes: a meta-analysis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088437/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Peri-device leak detected by TEE was associated with adverse events, primarily thromboembolism. Residual leaks detected by CT were more frequent but lacked prognostic significance.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad828. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad828. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Residual leaks are not infrequent after left atrial appendage occlusion. However, there is still uncertainty regarding their prognostic implications. The aim of this study is to evaluate the impact of residual leaks after left atrial appendage occlusion.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: A literature search was conducted until 19 February 2023. Residual leaks comprised peri-device leaks (PDLs) on transoesophageal echocardiography (TEE) or computed tomography (CT), as well as left atrial appendage patency on CT. Random-effects meta-analyses were performed to assess the clinical impact of residual leaks.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Overall 48 eligible studies (44 non-randomized/observational and 4 randomized studies) including 61 666 patients with atrial fibrillation who underwent left atrial appendage occlusion were analysed. Peri-device leak by TEE was present in 26.1% of patients. Computed tomography-based left atrial appendage patency and PDL were present in 54.9% and 57.3% of patients, respectively. Transoesophageal echocardiography-based PDL (i.e. any reported PDL regardless of its size) was significantly associated with a higher risk of thromboembolism [pooled odds ratio (pOR) 2.04, 95% confidence interval (CI): 1.52-2.74], all-cause mortality (pOR 1.16, 95% CI: 1.08-1.24), and major bleeding (pOR 1.12, 95% CI: 1.03-1.22), compared with no reported PDL. A positive graded association between PDL size and risk of thromboembolism was noted across TEE cut-offs. For any PDL of >;0, >;1, >;3, and >;5 mm, the pORs for thromboembolism were 1.82 (95% CI: 1.35-2.47), 2.13 (95% CI: 1.04-4.35), 4.14 (95% CI: 2.07-8.27), and 4.44 (95% CI: 2.09-9.43), respectively, compared with either no PDL or PDL smaller than each cut-off. Neither left atrial appendage patency, nor PDL by CT was associated with thromboembolism (pOR 1.45 and 1.04, 95% CI: 0.84-2.50 and 0.52-2.07, respectively).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Peri-device leak detected by TEE was associated with adverse events, primarily thromboembolism. Residual leaks detected by CT were more frequent but lacked prognostic significance.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088437/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38088437</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad828>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad828</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38088437</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Athanasios Samaras</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andreas S Papazoglou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Charalampos Balomenakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexandra Bekiaridou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dimitrios V Moysidis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vasiliki Patsiou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Antonios Orfanidis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>George Giannakoulas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>George Kassimis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nikolaos Fragakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jacqueline Saw</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ulf Landmesser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mohamad Adnan Alkhouli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Apostolos Tzikas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Residual leaks following percutaneous left atrial appendage occlusion and outcomes: a meta-analysis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38088437</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad828</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Visualizing the unseen: lights and shadows of imaging in the electrophysiology laboratory</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088436/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad777. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad777. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38088436/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38088436</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad777>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad777</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38088436</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Francesco De Sensi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Diego Penela</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ugo Limbruno</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Antonio Berruezo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Visualizing the unseen: lights and shadows of imaging in the electrophysiology laboratory</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38088436</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad777</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Randomized controlled trials are not always the solution</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087934/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad805. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad805. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087934/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38087934</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad805>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad805</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38087934</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sara Finocchietti</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Randomized controlled trials are not always the solution</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38087934</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad805</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intricacies of aortic risk assessment studies: not a simple matter</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087929/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad795. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad795. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087929/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38087929</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad795>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad795</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38087929</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mohammad A Zafar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinlin Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John A Elefteriades</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Intricacies of aortic risk assessment studies: not a simple matter</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38087929</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad795</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Randomized controlled trials remain underutilized</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087906/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad806. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad806. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087906/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38087906</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad806>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad806</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38087906</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>George C M Siontis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>André Frenk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephan Windecker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Randomized controlled trials remain underutilized</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38087906</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad806</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fate of the unoperated ascending thoracic aortic aneurysm-patient selection and the importance of the denominator</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087827/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad794. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad794. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087827/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38087827</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad794>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad794</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38087827</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Matthew D Solomon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David H Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>D Craig Miller</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Fate of the unoperated ascending thoracic aortic aneurysm-patient selection and the importance of the denominator</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38087827</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad794</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Alternatives to animal experimentation in cardiovascular research: human models of disease and biobanking</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087812/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20231214170758&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2023 Dec 13:ehad709. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad709. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38087812/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20231214170758&v=2.18.0">38087812</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad709>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad709</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38087812</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Inês Falcão-Pires</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2023-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Alternatives to animal experimentation in cardiovascular research: human models of disease and biobanking</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38087812</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad709</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>