<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;v=2.18.0&amp;ff=20240114212713
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;v=2.18.0&amp;ff=20240114212713" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 02:27:14 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Focus on interventional cardiology: the need for quality and transparency of evidence for implantable cardiovascular medical devices</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38218588/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jan 14;45(3):147-151. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad894.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38218588/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38218588</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad894>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad894</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38218588</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Focus on interventional cardiology: the need for quality and transparency of evidence for implantable cardiovascular medical devices</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38218588</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad894</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Inherited blood cancer predisposition through altered transcription elongation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38218188/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Despite advances in defining diverse somatic mutations that cause myeloid malignancies, a significant heritable component for these cancers remains largely unexplained. Here, we perform rare variant association studies in a large population cohort to identify inherited predisposition genes for these blood cancers. CTR9, which encodes a key component of the PAF1 transcription elongation complex, is among the significant genes identified. The risk variants found in the cases cause loss of function...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jan 4:S0092-8674(23)01348-X. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.016. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite advances in defining diverse somatic mutations that cause myeloid malignancies, a significant heritable component for these cancers remains largely unexplained. Here, we perform rare variant association studies in a large population cohort to identify inherited predisposition genes for these blood cancers. CTR9, which encodes a key component of the PAF1 transcription elongation complex, is among the significant genes identified. The risk variants found in the cases cause loss of function and result in a ∼10-fold increased odds of acquiring a myeloid malignancy. Partial CTR9 loss of function expands human hematopoietic stem cells (HSCs) by increased super elongation complex-mediated transcriptional activity, which thereby increases the expression of key regulators of HSC self-renewal. By following up on insights from a human genetic study examining inherited predisposition to the myeloid malignancies, we define a previously unknown antagonistic interaction between the PAF1 and super elongation complexes. These insights could enable targeted approaches for blood cancer prevention.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38218188/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38218188</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.016>10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.016</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38218188</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jiawei Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liam D Cato</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Uma P Arora</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erik L Bao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel C Bryant</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicholas Williams</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuemeng Jia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seth R Goldman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jyoti Nangalia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael A Erb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seychelle M Vos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott A Armstrong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vijay G Sankaran</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Inherited blood cancer predisposition through altered transcription elongation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38218188</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.016</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Specialized pro-resolving mediators in vascular inflammation and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38216693/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Timely resolution of the acute inflammatory response (or inflammation resolution) is an active, highly coordinated process that is essential to optimal health. Inflammation resolution is regulated by specific endogenous signalling molecules that function as 'stop signals' to terminate the inflammatory response when it is no longer needed; to actively promote healing, regeneration and tissue repair; and to limit pain. Specialized pro-resolving mediators are a superfamily of signalling molecules...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2024 Jan 12. doi: 10.1038/s41569-023-00984-x. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Timely resolution of the acute inflammatory response (or inflammation resolution) is an active, highly coordinated process that is essential to optimal health. Inflammation resolution is regulated by specific endogenous signalling molecules that function as 'stop signals' to terminate the inflammatory response when it is no longer needed; to actively promote healing, regeneration and tissue repair; and to limit pain. Specialized pro-resolving mediators are a superfamily of signalling molecules that initiate anti-inflammatory and pro-resolving actions. Without an effective and timely resolution response, inflammation can become chronic, a pathological state that is associated with many widely occurring human diseases, including atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Uncovering the mechanisms of inflammation resolution failure in cardiovascular diseases and identifying useful biomarkers for non-resolving inflammation are unmet needs. In this Review, we discuss the accumulating evidence that supports the role of non-resolving inflammation in atherosclerosis and the use of specialized pro-resolving mediators as therapeutic tools for the treatment of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. We highlight open questions about therapeutic strategies and mechanisms of disease to provide a framework for future studies on the prevention and treatment of atherosclerosis.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38216693/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38216693</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-023-00984-x>10.1038/s41569-023-00984-x</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38216693</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Gabrielle Fredman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Charles N Serhan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Specialized pro-resolving mediators in vascular inflammation and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38216693</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-023-00984-x</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hypoxia and intra-complex genetic suppressors rescue complex I mutants by a shared mechanism</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38215760/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>The electron transport chain (ETC) of mitochondria, bacteria, and archaea couples electron flow to proton pumping and is adapted to diverse oxygen environments. Remarkably, in mice, neurological disease due to ETC complex I dysfunction is rescued by hypoxia through unknown mechanisms. Here, we show that hypoxia rescue and hyperoxia sensitivity of complex I deficiency are evolutionarily conserved to C. elegans and are specific to mutants that compromise the electron-conducting matrix arm. We show...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jan 5:S0092-8674(23)01342-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.010. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The electron transport chain (ETC) of mitochondria, bacteria, and archaea couples electron flow to proton pumping and is adapted to diverse oxygen environments. Remarkably, in mice, neurological disease due to ETC complex I dysfunction is rescued by hypoxia through unknown mechanisms. Here, we show that hypoxia rescue and hyperoxia sensitivity of complex I deficiency are evolutionarily conserved to C. elegans and are specific to mutants that compromise the electron-conducting matrix arm. We show that hypoxia rescue does not involve the hypoxia-inducible factor pathway or attenuation of reactive oxygen species. To discover the mechanism, we use C. elegans genetic screens to identify suppressor mutations in the complex I accessory subunit NDUFA6/nuo-3 that phenocopy hypoxia rescue. We show that NDUFA6/nuo-3(G60D) or hypoxia directly restores complex I forward activity, with downstream rescue of ETC flux and, in some cases, complex I levels. Additional screens identify residues within the ubiquinone binding pocket as being required for the rescue by NDUFA6/nuo-3(G60D) or hypoxia. This reveals oxygen-sensitive coupling between an accessory subunit and the quinone binding pocket of complex I that can restore forward activity in the same manner as hypoxia.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38215760/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38215760</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.010>10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38215760</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Joshua D Meisel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maria Miranda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Owen S Skinner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Presli P Wiesenthal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sandra M Wellner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexis A Jourdain</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gary Ruvkun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vamsi K Mootha</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Hypoxia and intra-complex genetic suppressors rescue complex I mutants by a shared mechanism</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38215760</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>ErbB3 Governs Endothelial Dysfunction in Hypoxia-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38214194/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Our study reveals, for the first time, that ErbB3 serves as a novel biomarker and a promising target for the treatment of PH.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jan 12. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067005. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Pulmonary hypertension, characterized by vascular remodeling, currently lacks curative therapeutic options. The dysfunction of pulmonary artery endothelial cells plays a pivotal role in the initiation and progression of pulmonary hypertension (PH). ErbB3 (human epidermal growth factor receptor 3), also recognized as HER3, is a member of the ErbB family of receptor tyrosine kinases.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Microarray, immunofluorescence, and Western blotting analyses were conducted to investigate the pathological role of ErbB3. Blood samples were collected for biomarker examination from healthy donors or patients with hypoxic PH. The pathological functions of ErbB3 were further validated in rodents subjected to chronic hypoxia- and Sugen-induced PH, with or without adeno-associated virus-mediated ErbB3 overexpression, systemic deletion, or endothelial cell-specific ErbB3 knockdown. Primary human pulmonary artery endothelial cells and pulmonary artery smooth muscle cells were used to elucidate the underlying mechanisms.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: ErbB3 exhibited significant upregulation in the serum, lungs, distal pulmonary arteries, and pulmonary artery endothelial cells isolated from patients with PH compared with those from healthy donors. ErbB3 overexpression stimulated hypoxia-induced endothelial cell proliferation, exacerbated pulmonary artery remodeling, elevated systolic pressure in the right ventricle, and promoted right ventricular hypertrophy in murine models of PH. Conversely, systemic deletion or endothelial cell-specific knockout of ErbB3 yielded opposite effects. Coimmunoprecipitation and proteomic analysis identified YB-1 (Y-box binding protein 1) as a downstream target of ErbB3. ErbB3 induced nuclear translocation of YB-1 and subsequently promoted hypoxia-inducible factor 1/2α transcription. A positive loop involving ErbB3-periostin-hypoxia-inducible factor 1/2α was identified to mediate the progressive development of this disease. MM-121, a human anti-ErbB3 monoclonal antibody, exhibited both preventive and therapeutic effects against hypoxia-induced PH.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Our study reveals, for the first time, that ErbB3 serves as a novel biomarker and a promising target for the treatment of PH.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38214194/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38214194</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067005>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067005</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38214194</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jin-Song Bian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jingyu Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junting Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianxin Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuan Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xusheng Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yiying Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lin Deng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rongchang Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaowei Nie</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>ErbB3 Governs Endothelial Dysfunction in Hypoxia-Induced Pulmonary Hypertension</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38214194</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067005</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ptpn23 Controls Cardiac T-Tubule Patterning by Promoting the Assembly of Dystrophin-Glycoprotein Complex</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38214189/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Ptpn23 is essential for cardiac T-tubule formation and maintenance along Z-discs. During postnatal heart development, Ptpn23 interacts with sarcomeric α-actinin and coordinates the assembly of the DGC at costameres to sculpt T-tubule spatial patterning and morphology.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jan 12. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065767. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Cardiac transverse tubules (T-tubules) are anchored to sarcomeric Z-discs by costameres to establish a regular spaced pattern. One of the major components of costameres is the dystrophin-glycoprotein complex (DGC). Nevertheless, how the assembly of the DGC coordinates with the formation and maintenance of T-tubules under physiological and pathological conditions remains unclear.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Given the known role of Ptpn23 (protein tyrosine phosphatase, nonreceptor type 23) in regulating membrane deformation, its expression in patients with dilated cardiomyopathy was determined. Taking advantage of Cre/Loxp, CRISPR/Cas9, and adeno-associated virus 9 (AAV9)-mediated in vivo gene editing, we generated cardiomyocyte-specific <i>Ptpn23</i> and <i>Actn2</i> (α-actinin-2, a major component of Z-discs) knockout mice. We also perturbed the DGC by using dystrophin global knockout mice (<i>Dmd</i><sup>E4</sup><sup>*</sup>). MM 4-64 and Di-8-ANEPPS staining, Cav3 immunofluorescence, and transmission electron microscopy were performed to determine T-tubule structure in isolated cells and intact hearts. In addition, the assembly of the DGC with <i>Ptpn23</i> and dystrophin loss of function was determined by glycerol-gradient fractionation and SDS-PAGE analysis.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: The expression level of Ptpn23 was reduced in failing hearts from dilated cardiomyopathy patients and mice. Genetic deletion of <i>Ptpn23</i> resulted in disorganized T-tubules with enlarged diameters and progressive dilated cardiomyopathy without affecting sarcomere organization. AAV9-mediated mosaic somatic mutagenesis further indicated a cell-autonomous role of <i>Ptpn23</i> in regulating T-tubule formation. Genetic and biochemical analyses showed that Ptpn23 was essential for the integrity of costameres, which anchor the T-tubule membrane to Z-discs, through interactions with α-actinin and dystrophin. Deletion of α-actinin altered the subcellular localization of Ptpn23 and DGCs. In addition, genetic inactivation of dystrophin caused similar T-tubule defects to <i>Ptpn23</i> loss-of-function without affecting Ptpn23 localization at Z-discs. Last, inducible <i>Ptpn23</i> knockout at 1 month of age showed Ptpn23 is also required for the maintenance of T-tubules in adult cardiomyocytes.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Ptpn23 is essential for cardiac T-tubule formation and maintenance along Z-discs. During postnatal heart development, Ptpn23 interacts with sarcomeric α-actinin and coordinates the assembly of the DGC at costameres to sculpt T-tubule spatial patterning and morphology.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38214189/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38214189</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065767>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065767</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38214189</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Chen Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ge Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinjian Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaozhi Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiayin Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuxian Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinxi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Duane D Hall</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruoqing Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Feng He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xing Chang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fudi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenjun Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhichao Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Long-Sheng Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peidong Han</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Ptpn23 Controls Cardiac T-Tubule Patterning by Promoting the Assembly of Dystrophin-Glycoprotein Complex</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38214189</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065767</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Therapeutic application of human type 2 innate lymphoid cells via induction of granzyme B-mediated tumor cell death</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38211590/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>The therapeutic potential for human type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) has been underexplored. Although not observed in mouse ILC2s, we found that human ILC2s secrete granzyme B (GZMB) and directly lyse tumor cells by inducing pyroptosis and/or apoptosis, which is governed by a DNAM-1-CD112/CD155 interaction that inactivates the negative regulator FOXO1. Over time, the high surface density expression of CD155 in acute myeloid leukemia cells impairs the expression of DNAM-1 and GZMB, thus...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jan 5:S0092-8674(23)01347-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.015. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The therapeutic potential for human type 2 innate lymphoid cells (ILC2s) has been underexplored. Although not observed in mouse ILC2s, we found that human ILC2s secrete granzyme B (GZMB) and directly lyse tumor cells by inducing pyroptosis and/or apoptosis, which is governed by a DNAM-1-CD112/CD155 interaction that inactivates the negative regulator FOXO1. Over time, the high surface density expression of CD155 in acute myeloid leukemia cells impairs the expression of DNAM-1 and GZMB, thus allowing for immune evasion. We describe a reliable platform capable of up to 2,000-fold expansion of human ILC2s within 4 weeks, whose molecular and cellular ILC2 profiles were validated by single-cell RNA sequencing. In both leukemia and solid tumor models, exogenously administered expanded human ILC2s show significant antitumor effects in vivo. Collectively, we demonstrate previously unreported properties of human ILC2s and identify this innate immune cell subset as a member of the cytolytic immune effector cell family.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38211590/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38211590</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.015>10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38211590</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Zhenlong Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rui Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hejun Tang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiamin Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zahir Shah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianying Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ningyuan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuai Cao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guido Marcucci</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Artis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael A Caligiuri</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jianhua Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Therapeutic application of human type 2 innate lymphoid cells via induction of granzyme B-mediated tumor cell death</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38211590</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2023.12.015</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The '10 commandments' for the 2023 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38206306/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jan 11:ehad863. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad863. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38206306/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38206306</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad863>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad863</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38206306</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Robert Byrne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J J Coughlan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xavier Rossello</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Borja Ibanez</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>The '10 commandments' for the 2023 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38206306</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad863</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ten tips for promoting cardiometabolic health and slowing cardiovascular aging</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38206047/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jan 11:ehad853. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad853. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38206047/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38206047</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad853>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad853</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38206047</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Maria L Cagigas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephen M Twigg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Luigi Fontana</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Ten tips for promoting cardiometabolic health and slowing cardiovascular aging</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38206047</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad853</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cannabis for chronic pain: cardiovascular safety in a nationwide Danish study</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38200679/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: In patients with chronic pain, the use of prescribed medical cannabis was associated with an elevated risk of new-onset arrhythmia compared with no use-most pronounced in the 180 days following the initiation of treatment.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jan 11:ehad834. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad834. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND AND AIMS: A rising number of countries allow physicians to treat chronic pain with medical cannabis. However, recreational cannabis use has been linked with cardiovascular side effects, necessitating investigations concerning the safety of prescribed medical cannabis.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Using nationwide Danish registers, patients with chronic pain initiating first-time treatment with medical cannabis during 2018-21 were identified and matched 1:5 to corresponding control patients on age, sex, chronic pain diagnosis, and concomitant use of other pain medication. The absolute risks of first-time arrhythmia (atrial fibrillation/flutter, conduction disorders, paroxysmal tachycardias, and ventricular arrhythmias) and acute coronary syndrome were reported comparing medical cannabis use with no use.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among 1.88 million patients with chronic pain (46% musculoskeletal, 11% cancer, 13% neurological, and 30% unspecified pain), 5391 patients claimed a prescription of medical cannabis [63.2% women, median age: 59 (inter-quartile range 48-70) years] and were compared with 26 941 control patients of equal sex- and age composition. Arrhythmia was observed in 42 and 107 individuals, respectively, within 180 days. Medical cannabis use was associated with an elevated risk of new-onset arrhythmia {180-day absolute risk: 0.8% [95% confidence interval (CI) 0.6%-1.1%]} compared with no use [180-day absolute risk: 0.4% (95% CI 0.3%-0.5%)]: a risk ratio of 2.07 (95% CI 1.34-2.80) and a 1-year risk ratio of 1.36 (95% CI 1.00-1.73). No significant association was found for acute coronary syndrome [180-day risk ratio: 1.20 (95% CI 0.35-2.04)].</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: In patients with chronic pain, the use of prescribed medical cannabis was associated with an elevated risk of new-onset arrhythmia compared with no use-most pronounced in the 180 days following the initiation of treatment.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38200679/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38200679</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad834>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad834</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38200679</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Anders Holt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nina Nouhravesh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jarl E Strange</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sebastian Kinnberg Nielsen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anne-Marie Schjerning</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter Vibe Rasmussen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christian Torp-Pedersen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gunnar H Gislason</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Morten Schou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patricia McGettigan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Morten Lamberts</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cannabis for chronic pain: cardiovascular safety in a nationwide Danish study</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38200679</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad834</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cannabis by any name does not smell as sweet: potential cardiovascular events with medical cannabis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38200676/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jan 11:ehad848. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehad848. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38200676/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38200676</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehad848>10.1093/eurheartj/ehad848</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38200676</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Robert L Page Ii</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cannabis by any name does not smell as sweet: potential cardiovascular events with medical cannabis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38200676</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehad848</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hospitalization With Cardiovascular Conditions in the Postpartum Year Among Commercially Insured Women in the U.S</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199715/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):382-384. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.006.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199715/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199715</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.006>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.006</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199715</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nicole D Ford</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carla L DeSisto</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lindsay S Womack</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Romeo R Galang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lisa M Hollier</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laurence S Sperling</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Janet S Wright</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jean Y Ko</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Hospitalization With Cardiovascular Conditions in the Postpartum Year Among Commercially Insured Women in the U.S</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199715</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.006</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hyperuricemia and Gout Reduction by SGLT2 Inhibitors in Diabetes and Heart Failure: JACC Review Topic of the Week</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199714/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Gout is characterized by increased production of purines (through the pentose phosphate pathway), which is coupled with reduced renal or intestinal excretion of urate. Concurrent upregulation of nutrient surplus signaling (mammalian target of rapamycin and hypoxia-inducible factor-1a) and downregulation of nutrient deprivation signaling (sirtuin-1 and adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase) redirects glucose toward anabolic pathways (rather than adenosine triphosphate production), thus...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):371-381. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.030.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Gout is characterized by increased production of purines (through the pentose phosphate pathway), which is coupled with reduced renal or intestinal excretion of urate. Concurrent upregulation of nutrient surplus signaling (mammalian target of rapamycin and hypoxia-inducible factor-1a) and downregulation of nutrient deprivation signaling (sirtuin-1 and adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase) redirects glucose toward anabolic pathways (rather than adenosine triphosphate production), thus promoting heightened oxidative stress and cardiomyocyte and proximal tubular dysfunction, leading to cardiomyopathy and kidney disease. Hyperuricemia is a marker (rather than a driver) of these cellular stresses. By inducing a state of starvation mimicry in a state of nutrient surplus, sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors decrease flux through the pentose phosphate pathway (thereby attenuating purine and urate synthesis) while promoting renal urate excretion. These convergent actions exert a meaningful effect to lower serum uric acid by ≈0.6 to 1.5 mg/dL and to reduce the risk of gout by 30% to 50% in large-scale clinical trials.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199714/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199714</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.030>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.030</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199714</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Milton Packer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Hyperuricemia and Gout Reduction by SGLT2 Inhibitors in Diabetes and Heart Failure: JACC Review Topic of the Week</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199714</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.030</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sudden Cardiac Death in Young Athletes: JACC State-of-the-Art Review</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199713/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>Athletes epitomize the healthiest segment of society. Despite this premise, sudden cardiac death may occur in apparently healthy athletes, attracting significant attention not only in the medical community but also in laypersons and media. The incidence of sudden cardiac death is variably reported, and epidemiological burden differs among cohorts. Athletes appear to be at risk of developing fatal arrhythmias when harboring a quiescent cardiac disorder. Primary cardiomyopathies, ion...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):350-370. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.032.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Athletes epitomize the healthiest segment of society. Despite this premise, sudden cardiac death may occur in apparently healthy athletes, attracting significant attention not only in the medical community but also in laypersons and media. The incidence of sudden cardiac death is variably reported, and epidemiological burden differs among cohorts. Athletes appear to be at risk of developing fatal arrhythmias when harboring a quiescent cardiac disorder. Primary cardiomyopathies, ion channelopathies, and coronary artery anomalies are prevalent causes in young individuals. Cardiac assessment of athletes can be challenging because these individuals exhibit a plethora of electrical, structural, and functional physiological changes that overlap with cardiac pathology. A diagnosis of cardiac disease in a young athlete is not necessarily an indication to terminate competition and sports participation. International guidelines, traditionally focused on disqualification of individuals with cardiac disease, have recently adopted a more liberal attitude, based on a careful assessment of the risk and on a shared-decision making approach.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199713/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199713</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.032>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.032</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199713</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Gherardo Finocchiaro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph Westaby</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mary N Sheppard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Papadakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sanjay Sharma</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Sudden Cardiac Death in Young Athletes: JACC State-of-the-Art Review</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199713</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.032</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Best Oral Anticoagulant for Transcatheter Mitral Valve Replacement</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199712/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):347-349. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.005.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199712/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199712</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.005>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.005</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199712</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jurriën M Ten Berg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniël C Overduin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dirk Jan van Ginkel</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Best Oral Anticoagulant for Transcatheter Mitral Valve Replacement</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199712</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.005</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Comparison of Direct Oral Anticoagulants vs Vitamin K Antagonists After Transcatheter Mitral Valve Replacement</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199711/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: The use of DOACs after TMVR, compared with VKAs, appears to reduce the risk of bleeding complications and decrease the length of hospital stay for patients, without a significant increase in the risk of thrombotic events.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):334-346. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.031.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: There is currently no established recommendation for antithrombotic treatment following transcatheter mitral valve replacement (TMVR). However, based on the analogy with surgical mitral bioprosthesis, vitamin K antagonists (VKAs) are predominantly used.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: The purpose of this study was to compare bleeding and thrombotic events associated with direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) or VKAs in a prospective cohort of TMVR patients.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We enrolled consecutive patients who underwent transseptal TMVR using a SAPIEN family prosthesis at our center between 2011 and 2023. The primary outcome was the occurrence of bleeding. VKAs were administered to patients until October 2019, after which DOACs were prescribed. The median follow-up was 4.7 months (Q1-Q3: 2.6-6.7 months).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A total of 156 patients were included. The mean age was 65 ± 18.5 years, and 103 patients (66%) were women. The median EuroSCORE II was 7.48% (Q1-Q3: 3.80%-12.97%). Of the participants, 20.5% received DOACs and 79.5% were treated with VKAs. The primary outcome was observed in 50 (40%) patients in the VKA group and 3 (9%) patients in the DOAC group (adjusted HR: 0.21; 95% CI: 0.06-0.74; P = 0.02). Treatment with DOAC was associated with a shorter length of hospital stay. No significant differences were found in terms of thrombotic events, major vascular complications, stroke, or death.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: The use of DOACs after TMVR, compared with VKAs, appears to reduce the risk of bleeding complications and decrease the length of hospital stay for patients, without a significant increase in the risk of thrombotic events.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199711/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199711</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.031>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.031</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199711</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nathan El Bèze</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dominique Himbert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gaspard Suc</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eric Brochet</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nadine Ajzenberg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Audrey Cailliau</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John Kikoïne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clemence Delhomme</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jose Luis Carrasco</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Phalla Ou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bernard Iung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marina Urena</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Comparison of Direct Oral Anticoagulants vs Vitamin K Antagonists After Transcatheter Mitral Valve Replacement</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199711</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.031</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>What Do We Really Know About Transcatheter Mitral Valve-in-Valve Procedures?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199710/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):331-333. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.009.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199710/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199710</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.009>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.009</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199710</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Matthew W Sherwood</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amit N Vora</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>What Do We Really Know About Transcatheter Mitral Valve-in-Valve Procedures?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199710</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.009</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Timing Surgical Mitral Valve Repair for Primary Mitral Regurgitation: An Opportunity for Sex-Guided Precision Medicine</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199709/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):313-316. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.035.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199709/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199709</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.035>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.035</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199709</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Anna Sannino</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Federico Fortuni</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Timing Surgical Mitral Valve Repair for Primary Mitral Regurgitation: An Opportunity for Sex-Guided Precision Medicine</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199709</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.035</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sex-Specific Prognosis of Left Ventricular Size and Function Following Repair of Degenerative Mitral Regurgitation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199708/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: After mitral valve repair, women have a higher risk for all-cause mortality at lower LVESD and LVESDi and higher EF. These results support consideration of sex-specific thresholds for LVESDi in surgical decision making for patients with severe MR.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):303-312. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.033.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Prior studies have demonstrated worse long-term outcomes for women after surgery for severe mitral regurgitation (MR). The current Class I indications for surgery for severe degenerative MR use cutoffs of left ventricular end-systolic dimension (LVESD) and left ventricular ejection fraction (EF) that do not account for known sex-related differences.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: The primary objective of this study was to assess long-term mortality following mitral valve repair in women compared with men on the basis of preoperative left ventricular systolic dimensions and EF.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Consecutive patients who underwent isolated mitral valve repair for degenerative MR at a single institution between 1994 and 2016 were screened. Adjusted HRs for all-cause mortality were compared according to baseline LVESD, LVESD indexed to body surface area (LVESDi), and EF for men and women.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among 4,589 patients, 1,825 were women (40%), and after a median follow-up period of 7.2 years, 344 patients (7.5%) had died. The risk for mortality for women increased from the baseline hazard at an LVESD of 3.6 cm, whereas an inflection point for increased risk with LVESD was not evident in men. Regarding LVESDi, the risk for women increased at 1.8 cm/m<sup>2</sup> compared with 2.1 cm/m<sup>2</sup> in men. For EF, women and men had a similar inflection point (58%); however, mortality was higher for women as EF decreased.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: After mitral valve repair, women have a higher risk for all-cause mortality at lower LVESD and LVESDi and higher EF. These results support consideration of sex-specific thresholds for LVESDi in surgical decision making for patients with severe MR.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199708/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199708</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.033>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.033</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199708</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bryan Q Abadie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul C Cremer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sneha Vakamudi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>A Marc Gillinov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lars G Svensson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Leslie Cho</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Sex-Specific Prognosis of Left Ventricular Size and Function Following Repair of Degenerative Mitral Regurgitation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199708</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.033</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Clinical Utility of the Humble Exercise ECG Stress Test</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199707/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):300-302. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.036.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199707/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199707</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.036>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.036</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199707</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>John F Beltrame</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarena La</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica Marathe</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Clinical Utility of the Humble Exercise ECG Stress Test</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199707</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.036</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rethinking False Positive Exercise Electrocardiographic Stress Tests by Assessing Coronary Microvascular Function</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199706/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240114212713&amp;v=2.18.0
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: In patients with ANOCA, ischemia on EST was highly specific of an underlying ischemic substrate. These findings challenge the traditional belief that EST has a high false positive rate.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 16;83(2):291-299. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.034.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Exercise electrocardiographic stress testing (EST) has historically been validated against the demonstration of obstructive coronary artery disease. However, myocardial ischemia can occur because of coronary microvascular dysfunction (CMD) in the absence of obstructive coronary artery disease.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study was to assess the specificity of EST to detect an ischemic substrate against the reference standard of coronary endothelium-independent and endothelium-dependent microvascular function in patients with angina with nonobstructive coronary arteries (ANOCA).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Patients with ANOCA underwent invasive coronary physiological assessment using adenosine and acetylcholine. CMD was defined as impaired endothelium-independent and/or endothelium-dependent function. EST was performed using a standard Bruce treadmill protocol, with ischemia defined as the appearance of ≥0.1-mV ST-segment depression 80 ms from the J-point on electrocardiography. The study was powered to detect specificity of ≥91%.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: A total of 102 patients were enrolled (65% women, mean age 60 ± 8 years). Thirty-two patients developed ischemia (ischemic group) during EST, whereas 70 patients did not (nonischemic group); both groups were phenotypically similar. Ischemia during EST was 100% specific for CMD. Acetylcholine flow reserve was the strongest predictor of ischemia during exercise. Using endothelium-independent and endothelium-dependent microvascular dysfunction as the reference standard, the false positive rate of EST dropped to 0%.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: In patients with ANOCA, ischemia on EST was highly specific of an underlying ischemic substrate. These findings challenge the traditional belief that EST has a high false positive rate.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38199706/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240114212713&v=2.18.0">38199706</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.034>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.034</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38199706</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Aish Sinha</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Utkarsh Dutta</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ozan M Demir</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kalpa De Silva</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Howard Ellis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel Belford</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark Ogden</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew Li Kam Wa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Holly P Morgan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ajay M Shah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amedeo Chiribiri</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrew J Webb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Marber</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haseeb Rahman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Divaka Perera</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Rethinking False Positive Exercise Electrocardiographic Stress Tests by Assessing Coronary Microvascular Function</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38199706</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.034</dc:identifier>
</item>




























</channel>
</rss>