<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 12:20:34 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>The growing relevance of sex-specific risk factors</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39980454/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 21;46(8):673-676. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf021.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39980454/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39980454</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf021>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf021</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39980454</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>The growing relevance of sex-specific risk factors</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39980454</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf021</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SecY translocon chaperones protein folding during membrane protein insertion</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978345/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The Sec translocon is vital for guiding membrane protein insertion into lipid bilayers. The insertion and folding processes of membrane proteins are poorly understood. Here, we report cryo-electron microscopy structures of multi-spanning membrane proteins inserting through the SecY channel, the Sec translocon in prokaryotes. The high-resolution structures illustrate how bulky amino acids pass the narrow channel restriction. Comparison of different translocation states reveals that the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 12:S0092-8674(25)00106-0. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.037. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The Sec translocon is vital for guiding membrane protein insertion into lipid bilayers. The insertion and folding processes of membrane proteins are poorly understood. Here, we report cryo-electron microscopy structures of multi-spanning membrane proteins inserting through the SecY channel, the Sec translocon in prokaryotes. The high-resolution structures illustrate how bulky amino acids pass the narrow channel restriction. Comparison of different translocation states reveals that the cytoplasmic and extracellular cavities of the channel create distinct environments for promoting the unfolding and folding of transmembrane segments (TMs), respectively. Released substrate TMs are either flexible or stabilized by an unexpected hydrophilic groove between TM3 and TM4 of SecY. Disruption of the groove causes global defects in the folding of the membrane proteome. These findings demonstrate that beyond its role as a passive protein-conducting channel, the SecY translocon actively serves as a chaperone, employing multiple mechanisms to promote membrane protein insertion and folding.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978345/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39978345</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.037>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.037</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39978345</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xiaomin Ou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chengying Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dongjie Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinkun Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaofei Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dali Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Song Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ning Gao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chen Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Long Li</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>SecY translocon chaperones protein folding during membrane protein insertion</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39978345</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.037</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Motor and vestibular signals in the visual cortex permit the separation of self versus externally generated visual motion</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978344/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Knowing whether we are moving or something in the world is moving around us is possibly the most critical sensory discrimination we need to perform. How the brain and, in particular, the visual system solves this motion-source separation problem is not known. Here, we find that motor, vestibular, and visual motion signals are used by the mouse primary visual cortex (VISp) to differentially represent the same visual flow information according to whether the head is stationary or experiencing...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 14:S0092-8674(25)00101-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.032. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Knowing whether we are moving or something in the world is moving around us is possibly the most critical sensory discrimination we need to perform. How the brain and, in particular, the visual system solves this motion-source separation problem is not known. Here, we find that motor, vestibular, and visual motion signals are used by the mouse primary visual cortex (VISp) to differentially represent the same visual flow information according to whether the head is stationary or experiencing passive versus active translation. During locomotion, we find that running suppresses running-congruent translation input and that translation signals dominate VISp activity when running and translation speed become incongruent. This cross-modal interaction between the motor and vestibular systems was found throughout the cortex, indicating that running and translation signals provide a brain-wide egocentric reference frame for computing the internally generated and actual speed of self when moving through and sensing the external world.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978344/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39978344</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.032>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.032</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39978344</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mateo Vélez-Fort</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lee Cossell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura Porta</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Claudia Clopath</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Troy W Margrie</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Motor and vestibular signals in the visual cortex permit the separation of self versus externally generated visual motion</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39978344</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.032</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Contextual computation by competitive protein dimerization networks</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978343/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Many biological signaling pathways employ proteins that competitively dimerize in diverse combinations. These dimerization networks can perform biochemical computations in which the concentrations of monomer inputs determine the concentrations of dimer outputs. Despite their prevalence, little is known about the range of input-output computations that dimerization networks can perform and how it depends on network size and connectivity. Using a systematic computational approach, we demonstrate...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 11:S0092-8674(25)00105-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.036. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Many biological signaling pathways employ proteins that competitively dimerize in diverse combinations. These dimerization networks can perform biochemical computations in which the concentrations of monomer inputs determine the concentrations of dimer outputs. Despite their prevalence, little is known about the range of input-output computations that dimerization networks can perform and how it depends on network size and connectivity. Using a systematic computational approach, we demonstrate that even small dimerization networks of 3-6 monomers are expressive, performing diverse multi-input computations. Further, dimerization networks are versatile, performing different computations when their protein components are expressed at different levels, such as in different cell types. Remarkably, individual networks with random interaction affinities, when large enough, can perform nearly all potential one-input network computations merely by tuning their monomer expression levels. Thus, even the simple process of competitive dimerization provides a powerful architecture for multi-input, cell-type-specific signal processing.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39978343/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39978343</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.036>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.036</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39978343</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jacob Parres-Gold</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew Levine</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benjamin Emert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrew Stuart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael B Elowitz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Contextual computation by competitive protein dimerization networks</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39978343</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.036</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Priorities for medical device regulatory approval: a report from the European Society of Cardiology Cardiovascular Round Table</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39977258/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The European Union (EU) Medical Device Regulation increased regulatory scrutiny to improve the safety and performance of new medical devices. An equally important goal is providing timely access to innovative devices to benefit patient care. The European Society of Cardiology strongly advocates for the evolution of the Medical Device Regulation system to facilitate priority access for innovative devices for unmet needs and orphan cardiovascular (CV) medical devices in EU countries. Although...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 20:ehaf069. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf069. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The European Union (EU) Medical Device Regulation increased regulatory scrutiny to improve the safety and performance of new medical devices. An equally important goal is providing timely access to innovative devices to benefit patient care. The European Society of Cardiology strongly advocates for the evolution of the Medical Device Regulation system to facilitate priority access for innovative devices for unmet needs and orphan cardiovascular (CV) medical devices in EU countries. Although device approval is currently executed by Notified Bodies in the EU, it will be advantageous in the mid-term to consider a single EU regulatory agency for devices. In the short term, steps can be taken to transform the current system into a more efficient, predictable, cost-effective, and user-friendly service. Key strategies include the following: enhancing predictability of the approval process through use of early scientific advice from regulators; establishing unique regulatory pathways for CV orphan, paediatric, and innovative devices; promoting more efficient (re)certification of essential legacy CV devices; improving transparency of sponsor interactions with Notified Bodies; expanding the roles of the Expert Panels to assist in the approval of CV devices; promoting global regulatory harmonization, considering streamlined authorization of CV medical technologies across selected jurisdictions; developing an efficient system to monitor device safety; and ensuring funding for data collection platforms. Some strategies that could help include considering a pilot programme for joint approval processes of selected devices in partnership with other regions (i.e. US Food and Drug Administration); developing priority pathways for accelerated access to innovative or orphan devices; and increasing recognition of the importance of early feasibility studies in the EU.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39977258/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39977258</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf069>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf069</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39977258</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Stephan Windecker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alan G Fraser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Piotr Szymanski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martine Gilard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas F Lüscher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Leila Abid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John Brennan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert Byrne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lia Crotti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Inga Drossart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer Franke</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mario Gabrielli Cossellu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ajay J Kirtane</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jana Kurucova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mitchell Krucoff</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gearóid McGauran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrick O Myers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Donal B O'Connor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Radosław Parma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul Piscoi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Archana Rao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrea Rappagliosi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giulio Stefanini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eigil Samset</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alphons Vincent</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ralph Stephan von Bardeleben</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Franz Weidinger</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Priorities for medical device regulatory approval: a report from the European Society of Cardiology Cardiovascular Round Table</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39977258</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf069</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Clinical Considerations for Competitive Sports Participation for Athletes With Cardiovascular Abnormalities: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39976316/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>This American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology scientific statement on clinical considerations for competitive sports participation for athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities or diseases is organized into 11 distinct sections focused on sports-specific topics or disease processes that are relevant when considering the potential risks of adverse cardiovascular events, including sudden cardiac arrest, during competitive sports participation. Task forces comprising international...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 20:S0735-1097(24)10722-X. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.025. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">This American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology scientific statement on clinical considerations for competitive sports participation for athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities or diseases is organized into 11 distinct sections focused on sports-specific topics or disease processes that are relevant when considering the potential risks of adverse cardiovascular events, including sudden cardiac arrest, during competitive sports participation. Task forces comprising international experts in sports cardiology and the respective topics covered were assigned to each section and prepared specific clinical considerations tables for practitioners to reference. Comprehensive literature review and an emphasis on shared decision-making were integral in the writing of all clinical considerations presented.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39976316/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39976316</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.025>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.025</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39976316</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jonathan H Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aaron L Baggish</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benjamin D Levine</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael J Ackerman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sharlene M Day</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth H Dineen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J Sawalla Guseh Ii</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andre La Gerche</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rachel Lampert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew W Martinez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Papadakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dermot M Phelan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keri M Shafer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Leadership Committee of the Council on Clinical Cardiology</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Council on Basic Cardiovascular Sciences</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Council on Cardiovascular Surgery and Anesthesia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American College of Cardiology</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Larry A Allen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mats Börjesson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alan C Braverman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Julie A Brothers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Silvia Castelletti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eugene H Chung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Timothy W Churchill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guido Claessen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Flavio D'Ascenzi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Douglas Darden</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter N Dean</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Neal W Dickert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jonathan A Drezner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katherine E Economy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thijs M H Eijsvogels</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael S Emery</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Susan P Etheridge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sabiha Gati</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Belinda Gray</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin Halle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kimberly G Harmon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey J Hsu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Richard J Kovacs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sheela Krishnan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark S Link</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin Maron</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Silvana Molossi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Antonio Pelliccia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jack C Salerno</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ankit B Shah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sanjay Sharma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tamanna K Singh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katie M Stewart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul D Thompson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Meagan M Wasfy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthias Wilhelm</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Clinical Considerations for Competitive Sports Participation for Athletes With Cardiovascular Abnormalities: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39976316</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.025</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fast Degradation of MecciRNAs by SUPV3L1/ELAC2 Provides a Novel Opportunity to Tackle Heart Failure With Exogenous MecciRNA</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973625/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: This study demonstrates the fast degradation of mecciRNAs and the associated regulations of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species release of mitochondrial permeability transition pore by mecciRNAs. HF conditions lead to dysregulated mecciRNA degradation, and exogenous mecciRNAs demonstrate treatment potential in mouse models of HF.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 20. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070840. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Circular RNAs derived from both nuclear and mitochondrial genomes are identified in animal cells. Mitochondria-encoded circular RNAs (mecciRNAs) are attracting more attention, and several members of mecciRNAs have already been recognized in regulating mitochondrial functions. Mitochondria dysfunctions are well-known to participate in heart failure (HF). This study was designed to investigate the RNA metabolism of mecciRNAs and the relevant roles and potential application of mecciRNAs in HF.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Compared with highly stable nuclear genome-encoded circular RNAs, the fast degradation feature of mecciRNAs is identified by RNA sequencing and a series of molecular, biochemical, and cellular experiments. The substantial protective effects of in vitro synthesized mecciRNAs were tested in both doxorubicin- and pressure overload-induced mouse models of HF.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: We discover that mecciRNAs are promptly degraded by an animal-conserved complex of helicase SUPV3L1 (suppressor of var1, 3-like protein 1) and endoribonuclease ELAC2 (elaC ribonuclease Z 2). MecciRNA degradation complex and mecciRNAs interact with mitochondrial permeability transition pore and its regulators including TRAP1 (TNF receptor-associated protein 1) and CypD (cyclophilin D). MecciRNAs regulate mitochondrial levels of TRAP1 and CypD to modulate the opening of mitochondrial permeability transition pore and the release of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species. Exogenously applied mecciRNAs interact with cytosolic TRAP1 and increase mitochondrial levels of TRAP1, and lead to a more closed state of mitochondrial permeability transition pore to constrain deleterious reactive oxygen species release. HF conditions lead to stimulated mecciRNA degradation, and administration of in vitro synthesized mecciRNAs exhibits substantial protective effects in both doxorubicin- and pressure overload-induced mouse models of HF.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: This study demonstrates the fast degradation of mecciRNAs and the associated regulations of mitochondrial reactive oxygen species release of mitochondrial permeability transition pore by mecciRNAs. HF conditions lead to dysregulated mecciRNA degradation, and exogenous mecciRNAs demonstrate treatment potential in mouse models of HF.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973625/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39973625</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070840>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070840</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39973625</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xu Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qinwei Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinya Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuqi Deng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaolin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peipei Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liang Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Likun Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ge Shan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Fast Degradation of MecciRNAs by SUPV3L1/ELAC2 Provides a Novel Opportunity to Tackle Heart Failure With Exogenous MecciRNA</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39973625</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070840</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Clinical Considerations for Competitive Sports Participation for Athletes With Cardiovascular Abnormalities: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973614/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>This American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology scientific statement on clinical considerations for competitive sports participation for athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities or diseases is organized into 11 distinct sections focused on sports-specific topics or disease processes that are relevant when considering the potential risks of adverse cardiovascular events, including sudden cardiac arrest, during competitive sports participation. Task forces comprising international...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 20. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001297. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">This American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology scientific statement on clinical considerations for competitive sports participation for athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities or diseases is organized into 11 distinct sections focused on sports-specific topics or disease processes that are relevant when considering the potential risks of adverse cardiovascular events, including sudden cardiac arrest, during competitive sports participation. Task forces comprising international experts in sports cardiology and the respective topics covered were assigned to each section and prepared specific clinical considerations tables for practitioners to reference. Comprehensive literature review and an emphasis on shared decision-making were integral in the writing of all clinical considerations presented.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973614/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39973614</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001297>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001297</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39973614</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jonathan H Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aaron L Baggish</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benjamin D Levine</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael J Ackerman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sharlene M Day</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth H Dineen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J Sawalla Guseh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andre La Gerche</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rachel Lampert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew W Martinez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Papadakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dermot M Phelan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keri M Shafer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Leadership Committee of the Council on Clinical Cardiology; Council on Basic Cardiovascular Sciences; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Cardiovascular Surgery and Anesthesia; Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease; and American College of Cardiology</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Clinical Considerations for Competitive Sports Participation for Athletes With Cardiovascular Abnormalities: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39973614</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001297</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bleeding and New Malignancy Diagnoses After Anticoagulation for Atrial Fibrillation: A Population-Based Cohort Study</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973613/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: In anticoagulated patients with AF, bleeding was strongly associated with new cancer diagnoses. Antecedent bleeding was associated with cancer diagnosis at an earlier stage. This highlights the importance of timely investigations in patients with bleeding after anticoagulation for AF, rather than attributing bleeding as an expected adverse effect.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Feb 20. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070865. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Bleeding after starting anticoagulation for atrial fibrillation (AF) may be the first sign of malignancy, especially in elderly individuals. There are no recommendations to guide investigations for malignancy after new-onset bleeding after anticoagulation for AF. Our objective was to determine the association of bleeding after starting oral anticoagulation for AF with new diagnoses of malignancy in a population-wide sample.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We conducted a population-based cohort study using linked administrative data sets of people ≥66 years of age who newly initiated warfarin or direct oral anticoagulants after diagnosis with AF between 2008 and 2022. Follow-up was 2 years after starting anticoagulation. We excluded patients with valvular disease, chronic dialysis, venous thromboembolism, previous cancer, or previously documented bleeding. Bleeding was identified from hospital/emergency department discharge records and physician billings, then handled as a time-varying covariate in cause-specific regression models while adjusting for baseline characteristics. The primary outcome was incident malignancy. We also determined the site of origin of the malignancy and the stage at diagnosis if indicated in the Ontario Cancer Registry. Analyses were repeated while limiting the exposure to specific bleeding sites.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among 119 480 people (mean age, 77.4 years; 52% male) who started anticoagulants, 26 037 (21.8%) had documented bleeding, and 5800 (4.9%) were diagnosed with malignancy within the next 2 years. Bleeding was associated with a higher hazard of cancer diagnosis with a hazard ratio (HR) of 4.0 (95% CI, 3.8-4.3). The HRs for any malignancy were 5.0 (95% CI, 4.6-5.5) for gastrointestinal, 5.0 (95% CI, 4.4-5.7) for genitourinary, 4.0 (95% CI, 3.5-4.6) for respiratory, 1.8 (95% CI, 1.4-2.2) for intracranial, and 1.5 (95% CI, 1.2-2.0) for nasopharyngeal bleeds. The HRs were substantially higher for cancers concordant with the bleeding site (gastrointestinal, 15.4; genitourinary, 11.8; respiratory, 10.1). Cancers were diagnosed at an earlier stage after bleeding (27.6% stage 4 after bleeding versus 31.3% without bleeding; <i>P</i>=0.029).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: In anticoagulated patients with AF, bleeding was strongly associated with new cancer diagnoses. Antecedent bleeding was associated with cancer diagnosis at an earlier stage. This highlights the importance of timely investigations in patients with bleeding after anticoagulation for AF, rather than attributing bleeding as an expected adverse effect.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973613/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39973613</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070865>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070865</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39973613</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kavi Grewal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuesong Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter C Austin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cynthia A Jackevicius</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Inbar Nardi-Admon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dennis T Ko</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Douglas S Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paaladinesh Thavendiranathan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Fradley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul Dorian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Husam Abdel-Qadir</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Bleeding and New Malignancy Diagnoses After Anticoagulation for Atrial Fibrillation: A Population-Based Cohort Study</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39973613</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070865</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>SCN10A-short gene therapy to restore conduction and protect against malignant cardiac arrhythmias</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973098/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: S10s gene therapy may be effective to treat cardiac conduction abnormalities and associated arrhythmias.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Feb 20:ehaf053. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf053. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Life-threatening arrhythmias are a well-established consequence of reduced cardiac sodium current (INa). Gene therapy approaches to increase INa have demonstrated potential benefits to prevent arrhythmias. However, the development of such therapies is hampered by the large size of sodium channels. In this study, SCN10A-short (S10s), a short transcript encoding the carboxy-terminal domain of the human neuronal sodium channel, was evaluated as a gene therapy target to increase INa and prevent arrhythmias.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Adeno-associated viral vector overexpressing S10s was injected into wild type and Scn5a-haploinsufficient mice on which patch-clamp studies, optical mapping, electrocardiogram analyses, and ischaemia reperfusion were performed. In vitro and in silico studies were conducted to further explore the effect of S10s gene therapy in the context of human hearts.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Cardiac S10s overexpression increased cellular INa, maximal action potential upstroke velocity, and action potential amplitude in Scn5a-haploinsufficient cardiomyocytes. S10s gene therapy rescues conduction slowing in Scn5a-haploinsufficient mice and prevented ventricular tachycardia induced by ischaemia-reperfusion in wild type mice. S10s overexpression increased maximal action potential upstroke velocity in human inducible pluripotent stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes and prevented inducible arrhythmias in simulated human heart models.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: S10s gene therapy may be effective to treat cardiac conduction abnormalities and associated arrhythmias.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39973098/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39973098</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf053>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf053</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39973098</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jianan Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arie O Verkerk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ronald Wilders</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingnan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kelly Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Adityo Prakosa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mathilde R Rivaud</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>E Madelief J Marsman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arie R Boender</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mischa Klerk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lianne Fokkert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Berend de Jonge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Klaus Neef</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Osne F Kirzner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Connie R Bezzina</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carol Ann Remme</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hanno L Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bastiaan J Boukens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Harsha D Devalla</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Natalia A Trayanova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vincent M Christoffels</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Phil Barnett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gerard J J Boink</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>SCN10A-short gene therapy to restore conduction and protect against malignant cardiac arrhythmias</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39973098</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf053</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Roadmap for alleviating the manifestations of ageing in the cardiovascular system</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39972009/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Ageing of the cardiovascular system is associated with frailty and various life-threatening diseases. As global populations grow older, age-related conditions increasingly determine healthspan and lifespan. The circulatory system not only supplies nutrients and oxygen to all tissues of the human body and removes by-products but also builds the largest interorgan communication network, thereby serving as a gatekeeper for healthy ageing. Therefore, elucidating organ-specific and cell-specific...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2025 Feb 19. doi: 10.1038/s41569-025-01130-5. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Ageing of the cardiovascular system is associated with frailty and various life-threatening diseases. As global populations grow older, age-related conditions increasingly determine healthspan and lifespan. The circulatory system not only supplies nutrients and oxygen to all tissues of the human body and removes by-products but also builds the largest interorgan communication network, thereby serving as a gatekeeper for healthy ageing. Therefore, elucidating organ-specific and cell-specific ageing mechanisms that compromise circulatory system functions could have the potential to prevent or ameliorate age-related cardiovascular diseases. In support of this concept, emerging evidence suggests that targeting the circulatory system might restore organ function. In this Roadmap, we delve into the organ-specific and cell-specific mechanisms that underlie ageing-related changes in the cardiovascular system. We raise unanswered questions regarding the optimal design of clinical trials, in which markers of biological ageing in humans could be assessed. We provide guidance for the development of gerotherapeutics, which will rely on the technological progress of the diagnostic toolbox to measure residual risk in elderly individuals. A major challenge in the quest to discover interventions that delay age-related conditions in humans is to identify molecular switches that can delay the onset of ageing changes. To overcome this roadblock, future clinical trials need to provide evidence that gerotherapeutics directly affect one or several hallmarks of ageing in such a manner as to delay, prevent, alleviate or treat age-associated dysfunction and diseases.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39972009/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39972009</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-025-01130-5>10.1038/s41569-025-01130-5</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39972009</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Luca Liberale</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Simon Tual-Chalot</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Simon Sedej</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stefano Ministrini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Georgios Georgiopoulos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Myriam Grunewald</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Magnus Bäck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marie-Luce Bochaton-Piallat</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Reinier A Boon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gustavo Campos Ramos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Menno P J de Winther</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Konstantinos Drosatos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul C Evans</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jane F Ferguson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sofia K Forslund-Startceva</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Claudia Goettsch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mauro Giacca</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Judith Haendeler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marinos Kallikourdis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel F J Ketelhuth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rory R Koenen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrick Lacolley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Esther Lutgens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pasquale Maffia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Satomi Miwa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Claudia Monaco</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fabrizio Montecucco</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giuseppe Danilo Norata</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elena Osto</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gavin D Richardson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Niels P Riksen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Oliver Soehnlein</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ioakim Spyridopoulos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sophie Van Linthout</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gemma Vilahur</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jolanda J Wentzel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vicente Andrés</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lina Badimon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Athanase Benetos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christoph J Binder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ralf P Brandes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Furman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vera Gorbunova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tomasz J Guzik</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph A Hill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas F Lüscher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>María Mittelbrunn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alessio Nencioni</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mihai G Netea</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>João F Passos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kimon S Stamatelopoulos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nektarios Tavernarakis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zoltan Ungvari</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph C Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James L Kirkland</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giovanni G Camici</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stefanie Dimmeler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guido Kroemer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mahmoud Abdellatif</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Konstantinos Stellos</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Roadmap for alleviating the manifestations of ageing in the cardiovascular system</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39972009</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-025-01130-5</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amara Yad Image: Myocardial Scar</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971411/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 25;85(7):782-783. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.004.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971411/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39971411</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.004>10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.004</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39971411</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shumpei Mori</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael C Fishbein</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kalyanam Shivkumar</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Amara Yad Image: Myocardial Scar</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39971411</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.004</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Standardized Definitions of Changes in Kidney Function in Trials of Heart Failure: JACC Expert Panel From the HF-ARC</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971410/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Perturbations in kidney function are frequently encountered in heart failure (HF) across its spectrum in both chronic and acute settings with distinct implications for patient management and prognosis. Lack of consensus on the threshold for clinically meaningful changes in kidney function has led to heterogeneity in the clinical characteristics and background therapies of individuals enrolled in clinical trials, and in multiple aspects of trial design. A meaningful and collaborative interaction...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 25;85(7):766-781. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.041.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Perturbations in kidney function are frequently encountered in heart failure (HF) across its spectrum in both chronic and acute settings with distinct implications for patient management and prognosis. Lack of consensus on the threshold for clinically meaningful changes in kidney function has led to heterogeneity in the clinical characteristics and background therapies of individuals enrolled in clinical trials, and in multiple aspects of trial design. A meaningful and collaborative interaction among the disciplines of cardiology and nephrology, clinical trialists, industry sponsors, and regulatory agencies is vital to the development of standardized definitions of changes in kidney function across HF settings. To achieve this critically important objective, the Heart Failure Collaboratory assembled experts in HF and nephrology, including key stakeholders in the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and industry, with the goal of developing initial recommendations for improved standardization of design and conduct of clinical trials in HF. Recommendations included how and when to measure baseline and changes in kidney function, discouraging the use of the term "acute kidney injury," and the consideration of urinary markers in the assessment of kidney function.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971410/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39971410</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.041>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.041</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39971410</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Anuradha Lala</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Steven Coca</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jason Feinman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carine E Hamo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mona Fiuzat</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William T Abraham</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher O'Connor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>JoAnn Lindenfeld</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James Januzzi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabella Cavagna</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John R Teerlink</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark J Sarnak</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chirag R Parikh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wendy McCallum</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marvin A Konstam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maria Rosa Costanzo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Standardized Definitions of Changes in Kidney Function in Trials of Heart Failure: JACC Expert Panel From the HF-ARC</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39971410</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.041</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Expert Curation of Genes Associated With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: What to Leave In, What to Leave Out</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971409/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 25;85(7):741-743. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.028.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971409/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39971409</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.028>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.028</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39971409</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mark V Sherrid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anjali T Owens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniele Massera</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Expert Curation of Genes Associated With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: What to Leave In, What to Leave Out</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39971409</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.028</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Genes Associated With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: A Reappraisal by the ClinGen Hereditary Cardiovascular Disease Gene Curation Expert Panel</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971408/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: We report 29 genes with definitive, strong, or moderate evidence of causation for HCM or isolated left ventricular hypertrophy, including sarcomere, sarcomere-associated, and syndromic conditions.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 25;85(7):727-740. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.010.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) is an inherited cardiac condition affecting ∼1 in 500 and exhibits marked genetic heterogeneity. Previously published in 2019, 57 HCM-associated genes were curated providing the first systematic evaluation of gene-disease validity.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: The authors report work by the Clinical Genome Resource Hereditary Cardiovascular Disease (HCVD) Gene Curation Expert Panel (GCEP) to reappraise the clinical validity of previously curated and new putative HCM genes.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: The Clinical Genome Resource systematic gene curation framework was used to reclassify the gene-disease relationships for HCM and related syndromic entities involving left ventricular hypertrophy. Genes previously curated were included if their classification was not definitive, and if the time since curation was >;2 to 3 years. New genes with literature assertions for HCM were included for initial evaluation. Existing genes were curated for new inheritance patterns where evidence existed. Curations were presented on twice monthly calls, with the HCVD GCEP composed of 29 individuals from 21 institutions across 6 countries.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Thirty-one genes were recurated and an additional 5 new potential HCM-associated genes were curated. Among the recurated genes, 17 (55%) genes changed classification: 1 limited and 4 disputed (from no known disease relationship), 9 disputed (from limited), and 3 definitive (from moderate). Among these, 3 (10%) genes had a clinically relevant upgrade, including TNNC1, a 9th sarcomere gene with definitive HCM association. With new evidence, 2 genes were curated for multiple inheritance patterns (TRIM63, disputed for autosomal dominant but moderate for autosomal recessive; ALPK3, strong for autosomal dominant and definitive for recessive). CSRP3 was curated for a semidominant mode of inheritance (definitive). Nine (29%) genes were downgraded to disputed, further discouraging clinical reporting of variants in these genes. Five genes recently reported to cause HCM were curated: RPS6KB1 and RBM20 (limited), KLHL24 and MT-TI (moderate), and FHOD3 (definitive).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: We report 29 genes with definitive, strong, or moderate evidence of causation for HCM or isolated left ventricular hypertrophy, including sarcomere, sarcomere-associated, and syndromic conditions.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971408/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39971408</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.010>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39971408</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sophie Hespe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amber Waddell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Babken Asatryan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emma Owens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Courtney Thaxton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mhy-Lanie Adduru</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kailyn Anderson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emily E Brown</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lily Hoffman-Andrews</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Jordan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katherine Josephs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Megan Mayers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stacey Peters</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fergus Stafford</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Richard D Bagnall</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lucas Bronicki</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bert Callewaert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>C Anwar A Chahal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cynthia A James</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Olga Jarinova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrew P Landstrom</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth M McNally</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brittney Murray</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura Muiño-Mosquera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Victoria Parikh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chloe Reuter</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Roddy Walsh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bess Wayburn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James S Ware</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jodie Ingles</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Genes Associated With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: A Reappraisal by the ClinGen Hereditary Cardiovascular Disease Gene Curation Expert Panel</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39971408</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heart Failure: Insights From a JACC Special Focus Issue</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971407/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Feb 25;85(7):683-684. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.001.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39971407/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39971407</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.001>10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.001</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39971407</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Harlan M Krumholz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Heart Failure: Insights From a JACC Special Focus Issue</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39971407</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2025.01.001</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bat-infecting merbecovirus HKU5-CoV lineage 2 can use human ACE2 as a cell entry receptor</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39970913/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Merbecoviruses comprise four viral species with remarkable genetic diversity: MERS-related coronavirus, Tylonycterisbat coronavirus HKU4, Pipistrellusbat coronavirus HKU5, and Hedgehog coronavirus 1. However, the potential human spillover risk of animal merbecoviruses remains to be investigated. Here, we reported the discovery of HKU5-CoV lineage 2 (HKU5-CoV-2) in bats that efficiently utilize human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) as a functional receptor and exhibits a broad host...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 12:S0092-8674(25)00144-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.042. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Merbecoviruses comprise four viral species with remarkable genetic diversity: MERS-related coronavirus, Tylonycterisbat coronavirus HKU4, Pipistrellusbat coronavirus HKU5, and Hedgehog coronavirus 1. However, the potential human spillover risk of animal merbecoviruses remains to be investigated. Here, we reported the discovery of HKU5-CoV lineage 2 (HKU5-CoV-2) in bats that efficiently utilize human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (ACE2) as a functional receptor and exhibits a broad host tropism. Cryo-EM analysis of HKU5-CoV-2 receptor-binding domain (RBD) and human ACE2 complex revealed an entirely distinct binding mode compared with other ACE2-utilizing merbecoviruses with RBD footprint largely shared with ACE2-using sarbecoviruses and NL63. Structural and functional analyses indicate that HKU5-CoV-2 has a better adaptation to human ACE2 than lineage 1 HKU5-CoV. Authentic HKU5-CoV-2 infected human ACE2-expressing cell lines and human respiratory and enteric organoids. This study reveals a distinct lineage of HKU5-CoVs in bats that efficiently use human ACE2 and underscores their potential zoonotic risk.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39970913/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39970913</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.042>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.042</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39970913</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jing Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chen Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianyi Dong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huiyu Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chunguang Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jia Su</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bei Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ben Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jingkun Jia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cheng-Bao Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiangyang He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kaiyi Pan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haofeng Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zishuo Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cong Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Libiao Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huan Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peng Zhou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Peng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zheng-Li Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Bat-infecting merbecovirus HKU5-CoV lineage 2 can use human ACE2 as a cell entry receptor</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39970913</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.042</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reprogrammable RNA-targeting CRISPR systems evolved from RNA toxin-antitoxins</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39970912/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Despite ongoing efforts to study CRISPR systems, the evolutionary origins giving rise to reprogrammable RNA-guided mechanisms remain poorly understood. Here, we describe an integrated sequence/structure evolutionary tracing approach to identify the ancestors of the RNA-targeting CRISPR-Cas13 system. We find that Cas13 likely evolved from AbiF, which is encoded by an abortive infection-linked gene that is stably associated with a conserved non-coding RNA (ncRNA). We further characterize a...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Feb 12:S0092-8674(25)00103-5. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.034. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite ongoing efforts to study CRISPR systems, the evolutionary origins giving rise to reprogrammable RNA-guided mechanisms remain poorly understood. Here, we describe an integrated sequence/structure evolutionary tracing approach to identify the ancestors of the RNA-targeting CRISPR-Cas13 system. We find that Cas13 likely evolved from AbiF, which is encoded by an abortive infection-linked gene that is stably associated with a conserved non-coding RNA (ncRNA). We further characterize a miniature Cas13, classified here as Cas13e, which serves as an evolutionary intermediate between AbiF and other known Cas13s. Despite this relationship, we show that their functions substantially differ. Whereas Cas13e is an RNA-guided RNA-targeting system, AbiF is a toxin-antitoxin (TA) system with an RNA antitoxin. We solve the structure of AbiF using cryoelectron microscopy (cryo-EM), revealing basic structural alterations that set Cas13s apart from AbiF. Finally, we map the key structural changes that enabled a non-guided TA system to evolve into an RNA-guided CRISPR system.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39970912/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39970912</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.034>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.034</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39970912</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shai Zilberzwige-Tal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Han Altae-Tran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Soumya Kannan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Max E Wilkinson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel Chau-Duy-Tam Vo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel Strebinger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>KeHuan K Edmonds</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chun-Chen Jerry Yao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kepler S Mears</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sergey A Shmakov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kira S Makarova</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rhiannon K Macrae</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eugene V Koonin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Feng Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Reprogrammable RNA-targeting CRISPR systems evolved from RNA toxin-antitoxins</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39970912</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.034</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Safety, Feasibility, and Diagnostic Yield of Invasive Coronary Function Testing: Netherlands Registry of Invasive Coronary Vasomotor Function Testing</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969865/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: This study found that a CFT was feasible and safe to perform in both tertiary and nontertiary centers with a high diagnostic yield.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2025 Feb 19:e245670. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5670. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">IMPORTANCE: Patients with angina and no obstructive coronary artery disease frequently have coronary vasomotor dysfunction as underlying pathophysiological mechanism, comprising epicardial spasm, microvascular spasm, and/or microcirculatory dysfunction. These endotypes can be diagnosed by invasive coronary function testing which has previously shown to be safe in tertiary and expert centers.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To determine the prevalence of vasomotor dysfunction in patients with angina and no obstructive coronary artery disease who were clinically referred for a coronary function test (CFT); and assess safety and feasibility of a CFT.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: This quality improvement study was performed using the Netherlands Registry of Invasive Coronary Vasomotor Function Testing (NL-CFT), a prospective, observational registry, in 15 participating hospitals (2 tertiary and 13 nontertiary). Patients with angina and no obstructive coronary artery disease who were referred for a clinically indicated CFT between December 2020 and January 2024 were included.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: A complete CFT consisted of acetylcholine spasm provocation testing and assessment of microcirculatory function. Prevalence of different endotypes based on test results and overall safety were assessed.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Among a total of 1207 patients included, 978 (81%) were female; and the mean (SD) age was 60 (10) years. The prevalence of coronary vasomotor dysfunction was very high (78%). There were 11 (0.9%) major and 10 (0.8%) minor complications reported. Of them, 3 major and all minor were definitely related to the coronary function test. No procedural death, myocardial infarction, or stroke was observed. No differences were found in the occurrence of complications between tertiary and nontertiary centers.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: This study found that a CFT was feasible and safe to perform in both tertiary and nontertiary centers with a high diagnostic yield.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969865/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39969865</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC11840684/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">PMC11840684</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5670>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5670</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39969865</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Caïa Crooijmans</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tijn P J Jansen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joan G Meeder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Janneke Woudstra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martijn Meuwissen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Annemiek M J De Vos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valeria Paradies</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Els G M Olde Bijvank</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patty Winkler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicola S Vos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karin Arkenbout</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pier Woudstra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin G Stoel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tim P Van de Hoef</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stijn C H Van den Oord</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jos W M G Widdershoven</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wouter Remkes</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aysun Cetinyurek-Yavuz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hester M Den Ruijter</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>N Charlotte Onland-Moret</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eric Boersma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marcel A M Beijk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yolande Appelman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jan J Piek</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Regina E Konst</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Angela H E M Maas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Niels Van Royen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aukelien C Dimitriu-Leen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Suzette E Elias-Smale</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter Damman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>NL-CFT Investigators</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Safety, Feasibility, and Diagnostic Yield of Invasive Coronary Function Testing: Netherlands Registry of Invasive Coronary Vasomotor Function Testing</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39969865</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>pmc:PMC11840684</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5670</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sex-Specific Association of Myocardial Fibrosis With Mortality in Patients With Aortic Stenosis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969863/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In this study, patients with severe AS who underwent AVR exhibited similar ECV% between sexes, while women had lower LGE. Increased myocardial fibrosis provided important prognostic value for both sexes.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2025 Feb 19:e245593. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5593. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">IMPORTANCE: Myocardial fibrosis in aortic stenosis (AS) may exhibit sex differences. However, its prognostic significance in women with AS remains unclear.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To investigate sex differences in myocardial fibrosis assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance (CMR) and evaluate its prognostic value in women and men with AS.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS: Patients with severe AS who underwent CMR before aortic valve replacement (AVR) were prospectively enrolled from 13 international sites between March 2011 and September 2021. Myocardial fibrosis was evaluated using extracellular volume fraction (ECV%) and late gadolinium enhancement (LGE). The main analysis was conducted on patients without obstructive coronary artery disease (CAD), defined as those with no history of myocardial infarction and no concomitant coronary artery bypass grafting. Data were analyzed from December 2023 to February 2024.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">EXPOSURES: Surgical or transcatheter AVR.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES: The primary outcome was post-AVR all-cause mortality and the secondary outcome was cardiovascular mortality.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Of 822 patients, 670 were without obstructive CAD (368 men [55%] and 302 women [45%]). Among these, women and men had a similar age (median, 72 years vs 71 years, respectively), comorbidities, and AS severity. ECV% was similar between sexes; however, women had less LGE (both infarct and noninfarct LGE). After a median follow-up of 3.7 (IQR, 2.1-4.7) years, there were 76 deaths (11.3%), including 29 adjudicated cardiovascular deaths, in patients without obstructive CAD. Increasing ECV% and LGE were associated with higher all-cause and cardiovascular mortality in both sexes. Cox analyses demonstrated that both ECV% and LGE were associated with higher all-cause mortality without significant interaction by sex (women: adjusted hazard ratio [HR], 1.08 per 1% ECV% increase; 95% CI, 1.04-1.12; P &lt; .001; men: adjusted HR, 1.01; 95% CI, 0.96-1.06; P = .66; P for interaction by sex = .09 and women: adjusted HR, 2.49 for the presence of LGE; 95% CI, 1.07-5.80; P = .03; men: adjusted HR, 1.82; 95% CI, 1.00-3.32; P = .04; P for interaction by sex = .68). In the entire population (n = 822), both noninfarct and infarct-related LGE were associated with increased mortality without significant interaction by sex.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE: In this study, patients with severe AS who underwent AVR exhibited similar ECV% between sexes, while women had lower LGE. Increased myocardial fibrosis provided important prognostic value for both sexes.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969863/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39969863</a> | PMC:<a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/PMC11840686/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">PMC11840686</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5593>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5593</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39969863</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Soongu Kwak</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anvesha Singh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Russell J Everett</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas A Treibel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jaehyun Lim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sungho Won</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michelle C Williams</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Krithika Loganathan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rong Bing</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Neil Craig</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Trisha Singh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shruti Joshi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Heesun Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Whal Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yong-Jin Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Calvin W L Chin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Miho Fukui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tarique Al Musa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marzia Rigolli</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lionel Tastet</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura E Dobson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephanie Wiesemann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vanessa M Ferreira</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gabriella Captur</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sahmin Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeanette Schulz-Menger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erik B Schelbert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marie-Annick Clavel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sung-Ji Park</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Costanza Pellegrini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin Hadamitzky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bernhard L Gerber</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David E Newby</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saul G Myerson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Phillipe Pibarot</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>João L Cavalcante</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gerry P McCann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>John P Greenwood</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James C Moon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marc R Dweck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seung-Pyo Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Sex-Specific Association of Myocardial Fibrosis With Mortality in Patients With Aortic Stenosis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39969863</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>pmc:PMC11840686</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5593</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Donning the Hijab-A Cardiology Fellow's Journey With Advocacy and Inclusion</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969858/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250221072030&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">JAMA Cardiol. 2025 Feb 19. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5667. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39969858/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250221072030&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39969858</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5667>10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5667</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39969858</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Najah Ali Khan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:source>JAMA cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Donning the Hijab-A Cardiology Fellow's Journey With Advocacy and Inclusion</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39969858</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2024.5667</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>