<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 16:11:10 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Systemic Deletion of ARRDC4 Improves Cardiac Reserve and Exercise Capacity in Diabetes</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38946541/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: ARRDC4 serves as a regulator of hyperglycemia-induced toxicities toward cardiac and skeletal muscle, revealing a new molecular framework that connects hyperglycemia to cardiac/skeletal myopathy to exercise intolerance.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jul 1. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323158. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Exercise intolerance is an independent predictor of poor prognosis in diabetes. The underlying mechanism of the association between hyperglycemia and exercise intolerance remains undefined. We recently demonstrated that the interaction between ARRDC4 (arrestin domain-containing protein 4) and GLUT1 (glucose transporter 1) regulates cardiac metabolism.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVE: To determine whether this mechanism broadly impacts diabetic complications, we investigated the role of ARRDC4 in the pathogenesis of diabetic cardiac and skeletal myopathy.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS AND RESULTS: High glucose promoted translocation of MondoA into the nucleus, which upregulated <i>Arrdc4</i> transcriptional expression, increased lysosomal GLUT1 trafficking, and blocked glucose transport in cardiomyocytes, forming a feedback mechanism. This role of <i>ARRDC4</i> was confirmed in human muscular cells from type 2 diabetic patients. Prolonged hyperglycemia upregulated myocardial <i>Arrdc4</i> expression in multiple types of mouse models of diabetes. We then analyzed hyperglycemia-induced cardiac and skeletal muscle abnormalities in insulin-deficient mice. Hyperglycemia increased advanced glycation end-products and elicited oxidative and endoplasmic reticulum stress leading to apoptosis in the heart and peripheral muscle. However, deletion of <i>Arrdc4</i> augmented tissue glucose transport and mitochondrial respiration, protecting the heart and muscle from tissue damage. Stress hemodynamic analysis and treadmill exhaustion test uncovered that <i>Arrdc4</i>-knockout mice had greater cardiac inotropic/chronotropic reserve with higher exercise endurance than wild-type (WT) animals under diabetes. While multiple organs were involved in the mechanism, cardiac-specific overexpression (beyond levels observed during diabetes) using adenoassociated virus suggests that high levels of myocardial <i>ARRDC4</i> have the potential to contribute to exercise intolerance by interfering with cardiac metabolism through its interaction with GLUT1 in diabetes. Importantly, the <i>ARRDC4</i> mutation mouse line exhibited greater exercise tolerance, showing the potential therapeutic impact on diabetic cardiomyopathy by disrupting the interaction between ARRDC4 and GLUT1.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: ARRDC4 serves as a regulator of hyperglycemia-induced toxicities toward cardiac and skeletal muscle, revealing a new molecular framework that connects hyperglycemia to cardiac/skeletal myopathy to exercise intolerance.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38946541/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38946541</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323158>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323158</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38946541</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yoshinobu Nakayama</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Satoru Kobayashi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aliya Masihuddin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Syed Amir Abdali</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>A M Pramodh Bandara Seneviratne</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sachiyo Ishii</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun Iida</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qiangrong Liang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun Yoshioka</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Systemic Deletion of ARRDC4 Improves Cardiac Reserve and Exercise Capacity in Diabetes</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38946541</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323158</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Temporal dynamics of woolly mammoth genome erosion prior to extinction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942016/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>A number of species have recently recovered from near-extinction. Although these species have avoided the immediate extinction threat, their long-term viability remains precarious due to the potential genetic consequences of population declines, which are poorly understood on a timescale beyond a few generations. Woolly mammoths (Mammuthus primigenius) became isolated on Wrangel Island around 10,000 years ago and persisted for over 200 generations before becoming extinct around 4,000 years ago....</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 17:S0092-8674(24)00577-4. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.033. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">A number of species have recently recovered from near-extinction. Although these species have avoided the immediate extinction threat, their long-term viability remains precarious due to the potential genetic consequences of population declines, which are poorly understood on a timescale beyond a few generations. Woolly mammoths (Mammuthus primigenius) became isolated on Wrangel Island around 10,000 years ago and persisted for over 200 generations before becoming extinct around 4,000 years ago. To study the evolutionary processes leading up to the mammoths' extinction, we analyzed 21 Siberian woolly mammoth genomes. Our results show that the population recovered quickly from a severe bottleneck and remained demographically stable during the ensuing six millennia. We find that mildly deleterious mutations gradually accumulated, whereas highly deleterious mutations were purged, suggesting ongoing inbreeding depression that lasted for hundreds of generations. The time-lag between demographic and genetic recovery has wide-ranging implications for conservation management of recently bottlenecked populations.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942016/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38942016</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.033>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.033</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38942016</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Marianne Dehasque</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hernán E Morales</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Díez-Del-Molino</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrícia Pečnerová</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J Camilo Chacón-Duque</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Foteini Kanellidou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Héloïse Muller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valerii Plotnikov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Albert Protopopov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexei Tikhonov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pavel Nikolskiy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gleb K Danilov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maddalena Giannì</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura van der Sluis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tom Higham</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter D Heintzman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nikolay Oskolkov</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>M Thomas P Gilbert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anders Götherström</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tom van der Valk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sergey Vartanyan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Love Dalén</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Temporal dynamics of woolly mammoth genome erosion prior to extinction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38942016</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.033</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The extracellular matrix integrates mitochondrial homeostasis</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942015/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cellular homeostasis is intricately influenced by stimuli from the microenvironment, including signaling molecules, metabolites, and pathogens. Functioning as a signaling hub within the cell, mitochondria integrate information from various intracellular compartments to regulate cellular signaling and metabolism. Multiple studies have shown that mitochondria may respond to various extracellular signaling events. However, it is less clear how changes in the extracellular matrix (ECM) can impact...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 24:S0092-8674(24)00638-X. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.057. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cellular homeostasis is intricately influenced by stimuli from the microenvironment, including signaling molecules, metabolites, and pathogens. Functioning as a signaling hub within the cell, mitochondria integrate information from various intracellular compartments to regulate cellular signaling and metabolism. Multiple studies have shown that mitochondria may respond to various extracellular signaling events. However, it is less clear how changes in the extracellular matrix (ECM) can impact mitochondrial homeostasis to regulate animal physiology. We find that ECM remodeling alters mitochondrial homeostasis in an evolutionarily conserved manner. Mechanistically, ECM remodeling triggers a TGF-β response to induce mitochondrial fission and the unfolded protein response of the mitochondria (UPR<sup>MT</sup>). At the organismal level, ECM remodeling promotes defense of animals against pathogens through enhanced mitochondrial stress responses. We postulate that this ECM-mitochondria crosstalk represents an ancient immune pathway, which detects infection- or mechanical-stress-induced ECM damage, thereby initiating adaptive mitochondria-based immune and metabolic responses.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942015/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38942015</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.057>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.057</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38942015</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hanlin Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>C Kimberly Tsui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gilberto Garcia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Larry K Joe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haolun Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ayane Maruichi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wudi Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sentibel Pandovski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter H Yoon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brant M Webster</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jenni Durieux</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Phillip A Frankino</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ryo Higuchi-Sanabria</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrew Dillin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>The extracellular matrix integrates mitochondrial homeostasis</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38942015</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.057</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Microglial-derived C1q integrates into neuronal ribonucleoprotein complexes and impacts protein homeostasis in the aging brain</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942014/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Neuroimmune interactions mediate intercellular communication and underlie critical brain functions. Microglia, CNS-resident macrophages, modulate the brain through direct physical interactions and the secretion of molecules. One such secreted factor, the complement protein C1q, contributes to complement-mediated synapse elimination in both developmental and disease models, yet brain C1q protein levels increase significantly throughout aging. Here, we report that C1q interacts with neuronal...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 24:S0092-8674(24)00639-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.058. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Neuroimmune interactions mediate intercellular communication and underlie critical brain functions. Microglia, CNS-resident macrophages, modulate the brain through direct physical interactions and the secretion of molecules. One such secreted factor, the complement protein C1q, contributes to complement-mediated synapse elimination in both developmental and disease models, yet brain C1q protein levels increase significantly throughout aging. Here, we report that C1q interacts with neuronal ribonucleoprotein (RNP) complexes in an age-dependent manner. Purified C1q protein undergoes RNA-dependent liquid-liquid phase separation (LLPS) in vitro, and the interaction of C1q with neuronal RNP complexes in vivo is dependent on RNA and endocytosis. Mice lacking C1q have age-specific alterations in neuronal protein synthesis in vivo and impaired fear memory extinction. Together, our findings reveal a biophysical property of C1q that underlies RNA- and age-dependent neuronal interactions and demonstrate a role of C1q in critical intracellular neuronal processes.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942014/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38942014</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.058>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.058</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38942014</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nicole Scott-Hewitt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthew Mahoney</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Youtong Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nils Korte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>T Yvanka de Soysa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel K Wilton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emily Knorr</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kevin Mastro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Allison Chang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Allison Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Melville</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Monica Schenone</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christina Hartigan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Beth Stevens</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Microglial-derived C1q integrates into neuronal ribonucleoprotein complexes and impacts protein homeostasis in the aging brain</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38942014</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.058</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stress-dependent condensate formation regulated by the ubiquitin-related modifier Urm1</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942013/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The ability of proteins and RNA to coalesce into phase-separated assemblies, such as the nucleolus and stress granules, is a basic principle in organizing membraneless cellular compartments. While the constituents of biomolecular condensates are generally well documented, the mechanisms underlying their formation under stress are only partially understood. Here, we show in yeast that covalent modification with the ubiquitin-like modifier Urm1 promotes the phase separation of a wide range of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 26:S0092-8674(24)00649-4. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.06.009. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The ability of proteins and RNA to coalesce into phase-separated assemblies, such as the nucleolus and stress granules, is a basic principle in organizing membraneless cellular compartments. While the constituents of biomolecular condensates are generally well documented, the mechanisms underlying their formation under stress are only partially understood. Here, we show in yeast that covalent modification with the ubiquitin-like modifier Urm1 promotes the phase separation of a wide range of proteins. We find that the drop in cellular pH induced by stress triggers Urm1 self-association and its interaction with both target proteins and the Urm1-conjugating enzyme Uba4. Urmylation of stress-sensitive proteins promotes their deposition into stress granules and nuclear condensates. Yeast cells lacking Urm1 exhibit condensate defects that manifest in reduced stress resilience. We propose that Urm1 acts as a reversible molecular "adhesive" to drive protective phase separation of functionally critical proteins under cellular stress.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38942013/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38942013</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.06.009>10.1016/j.cell.2024.06.009</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38942013</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Lucas V Cairo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoyu Hong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin B D Müller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patricia Yuste-Checa</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chandhuru Jagadeesan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andreas Bracher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sae-Hun Park</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Manajit Hayer-Hartl</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>F Ulrich Hartl</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Stress-dependent condensate formation regulated by the ubiquitin-related modifier Urm1</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38942013</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.06.009</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Weekly Journal Scan: a penULTIMATE frontier for optimal antiplatelet therapy after drug-eluting stenting in acute coronary syndromes?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941346/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 28:ehae367. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae367. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941346/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38941346</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae367>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae367</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38941346</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Giovanna Liuzzo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carlo Patrono</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Weekly Journal Scan: a penULTIMATE frontier for optimal antiplatelet therapy after drug-eluting stenting in acute coronary syndromes?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38941346</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae367</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Acute myocardial infarction and ischaemic stroke: differences and similarities in reperfusion therapies-a review</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941344/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and acute ischaemic stroke (AIS) share a number of similarities. However, important differences in pathophysiology demand a disease-tailored approach. In both conditions, fast treatment plays a crucial role as ischaemia and eventually infarction develop rapidly. Furthermore, in both fields, the introduction of fibrinolytic treatments historically preceded the implementation of endovascular techniques. However, in contrast to STEMI, only a minority...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 28:ehae371. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae371. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and acute ischaemic stroke (AIS) share a number of similarities. However, important differences in pathophysiology demand a disease-tailored approach. In both conditions, fast treatment plays a crucial role as ischaemia and eventually infarction develop rapidly. Furthermore, in both fields, the introduction of fibrinolytic treatments historically preceded the implementation of endovascular techniques. However, in contrast to STEMI, only a minority of AIS patients will eventually be considered eligible for reperfusion treatment. Non-invasive cerebral imaging always precedes cerebral angiography and thrombectomy, whereas coronary angiography is not routinely preceded by non-invasive cardiac imaging in patients with STEMI. In the late or unknown time window, the presence of specific patterns on brain imaging may help identify AIS patients who benefit most from reperfusion treatment. For STEMI, a uniform time window for reperfusion up to 12 h after symptom onset, based on old placebo-controlled trials, is still recommended in guidelines and generally applied. Bridging fibrinolysis preceding endovascular treatment still remains the mainstay of reperfusion treatment in AIS, while primary percutaneous coronary intervention is the strategy of choice in STEMI. Shortening ischaemic times by fine-tuning collaboration networks between ambulances, community hospitals, and tertiary care hospitals, optimizing bridging fibrinolysis, and reducing ischaemia-reperfusion injury are important topics for further research. The aim of this review is to provide insights into the common as well as diverging pathophysiology behind current reperfusion strategies and to explore new ways to enhance their clinical benefit.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941344/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38941344</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae371>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae371</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38941344</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Lauranne Scheldeman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter Sinnaeve</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory W Albers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robin Lemmens</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frans Van de Werf</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Acute myocardial infarction and ischaemic stroke: differences and similarities in reperfusion therapies-a review</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38941344</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae371</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A focus on three hot topics: atrial fibrillation, obesity, and climate change</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941334/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 28;45(24):2105-2108. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae380.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941334/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38941334</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae380>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae380</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38941334</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>A focus on three hot topics: atrial fibrillation, obesity, and climate change</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38941334</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae380</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Weekly Journal Scan: an ounce of PREVENTion is worth more than a pound of stents</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941317/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 28:ehae385. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae385. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38941317/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38941317</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae385>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae385</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38941317</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rocco Vergallo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Leonarda Galiuto</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Weekly Journal Scan: an ounce of PREVENTion is worth more than a pound of stents</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38941317</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae385</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Association of Atrial Fibrillation Burden and Mortality Among Patients With Cardiac Implantable Electronic Devices</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38940005/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: After adjustment for potential confounding factors, presence of AF was associated with higher mortality than no AF in our cohort of patients with cardiac implantable electronic devices. Among those with AF, nonparoxysmal AF was associated with the greatest risk of mortality.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 28. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069757. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Current estimates of atrial fibrillation (AF)-associated mortality rely on claims- or clinical-derived diagnoses of AF, limit AF to a binary entity, or are confounded by comorbidities. The objective of the present study is to assess the association between device-recognized AF and mortality among patients with cardiac implantable electronic devices capable of sensitive and continuous atrial arrhythmia detection. Secondary outcomes include relative mortality among cohorts with no AF, paroxysmal AF, persistent AF, and permanent AF.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Using the deidentified Optum Clinformatics US claims database (2015 to 2020) linked to the Medtronic CareLink database, we identified individuals with a cardiac implantable electronic device who transmitted data ≥6 months after implantation. AF burden was assessed during the first 6 months after implantation (baseline period). Subsequent mortality, assessed from claims data, was compared between patients with and those without AF, with adjustment for age, geographic region, insurance type, Charlson Comorbidity Index, and implantation year.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Of 21 391 patients (age, 72.9±10.9 years; 56.3% male) analyzed, 7798 (36.5%) had device-recognized AF. During a mean of 22.4±12.9 months (median, 20.1 [12.8-29.7] months) of follow-up, the overall incidence of mortality was 13.5%. Patients with AF had higher adjusted all-cause mortality than patients without AF (hazard ratio, 1.29 [95% CI, 1.20-1.39]; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). Among those with AF, patients with nonparoxysmal AF had the greatest risk of mortality (persistent AF versus paroxysmal AF: hazard ratio, 1.36 [95% CI, 1.18-1.58]; <i>P</i>&lt;.001; permanent AF versus paroxysmal AF: hazard ratio, 1.23 [95% CI, 1.14-1.34]; <i>P</i>&lt;.001).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: After adjustment for potential confounding factors, presence of AF was associated with higher mortality than no AF in our cohort of patients with cardiac implantable electronic devices. Among those with AF, nonparoxysmal AF was associated with the greatest risk of mortality.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38940005/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38940005</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069757>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069757</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38940005</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Graham Peigh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiani Zhou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah C Rosemas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anthony I Roberts</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Colleen Longacre</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katherine Trinh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tanvi Nayak</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dana Soderlund</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rod S Passman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Association of Atrial Fibrillation Burden and Mortality Among Patients With Cardiac Implantable Electronic Devices</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38940005</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069757</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Waitlist Outcomes for Pediatric Heart Transplantation in the Current Era: An Analysis of the Pediatric Heart Transplant Society Database</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939965/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: There is significant variability in WM among status-1A patients. Potential refinements to current allocation system should factor in the increased WM risk we identified in patients supported by extracorporeal membrane oxygenation or mechanical ventilation, single ventricle congenital heart disease on VAD support and small children with congenital heart disease, restrictive cardiomyopathy, or hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 28. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068189. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Waitlist mortality (WM) remains elevated in pediatric heart transplantation. Allocation policy is a potential tool to help improve WM. This study aims to identify patients at highest risk for WM to potentially inform future allocation policy changes.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: The Pediatric Heart Transplant Society database was queried for patients &lt;18 years of age indicated for heart transplantation between January 1, 2010 to December 31, 2021. <i>Waitlist mortality</i> was defined as death while awaiting transplant or removal from the waitlist due to clinical deterioration. Because WM is low after the first year, analysis was limited to the first 12 months on the heart transplant list. Kaplan-Meier analysis and log-rank testing was conducted to compare unadjusted survival between groups. Cox proportional hazard models were created to determine risk factors for WM. Subgroup analysis was performed for status 1A patients based on body surface area (BSA) at time of listing, cardiac diagnosis, and presence of mechanical circulatory support.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: In total 5974 children met study criteria of which 3928 were status 1A, 1012 were status 1B, 963 were listed status 2, and 65 were listed status 7. Because of the significant burden of WM experienced by 1A patients, further analysis was performed in only patients indicated as 1A. Within that group of patients, those with smaller size and lower eGFR had higher WM, whereas those patients without congenital heart disease or support from a ventricular assist device (VAD) at time of listing had decreased WM. In the smallest size cohort, cardiac diagnoses other than dilated cardiomyopathy were risk factors for WM. Previous cardiac surgery was a risk factor in the 0.3 to 0.7 m<sup>2</sup> and >;0.7 m<sup>2</sup> BSA groups. VAD support was associated with lower WM other than in the single ventricle cohort, where VAD was associated with higher WM. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation and mechanical ventilation were associated with increased risk of WM in all cohorts.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: There is significant variability in WM among status-1A patients. Potential refinements to current allocation system should factor in the increased WM risk we identified in patients supported by extracorporeal membrane oxygenation or mechanical ventilation, single ventricle congenital heart disease on VAD support and small children with congenital heart disease, restrictive cardiomyopathy, or hypertrophic cardiomyopathy.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939965/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38939965</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068189>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068189</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38939965</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ryan J Butts</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Leah Toombs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James K Kirklin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kurt R Schumacher</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer Conway</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shawn C West</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott Auerbach</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Neha Bansal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hong Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ryan S Cantor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Deipanjan Nandi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David M Peng</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Waitlist Outcomes for Pediatric Heart Transplantation in the Current Era: An Analysis of the Pediatric Heart Transplant Society Database</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38939965</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.068189</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Therapeutic Efficacy of Mexiletine for Long QT Syndrome Type 2: Evidence From Human Induced Pluripotent Stem Cell-Derived Cardiomyocytes, Transgenic Rabbits, and Patients</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939955/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Mexiletine significantly shortens cardiac repolarization in LQT2 human induced pluripotent stem cells, in the LQT2 rabbit model, and in the majority of patients with LQT2. Furthermore, mexiletine showed antiarrhythmic efficacy. Mexiletine should therefore be considered a valid therapeutic option to be added to conventional therapies in higher-risk patients with LQT2.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 28. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068959. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Despite major advances in the clinical management of long QT syndrome, some patients are not fully protected by beta-blocker therapy. Mexiletine is a well-known sodium channel blocker, with proven efficacy in patients with sodium channel-mediated long QT syndrome type 3. Our aim was to evaluate the efficacy of mexiletine in long QT syndrome type 2 (LQT2) using cardiomyocytes derived from patient-specific human induced pluripotent stem cells, a transgenic LQT2 rabbit model, and patients with LQT2.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Heart rate-corrected field potential duration, a surrogate for QTc, was measured in human induced pluripotent stem cells from 2 patients with LQT2 (KCNH2-p.A561V, KCNH2-p.R366X) before and after mexiletine using a multiwell multi-electrode array system. Action potential duration at 90% repolarization (APD<sub>90</sub>) was evaluated in cardiomyocytes isolated from transgenic LQT2 rabbits (KCNH2-p.G628S) at baseline and after mexiletine application. Mexiletine was given to 96 patients with LQT2. Patients were defined as responders in the presence of a QTc shortening ≥40 ms. Antiarrhythmic efficacy of mexiletine was evaluated by a Poisson regression model.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: After acute treatment with mexiletine, human induced pluripotent stem cells from both patients with LQT2 showed a significant shortening of heart rate-corrected field potential duration compared with dimethyl sulfoxide control. In cardiomyocytes isolated from LQT2 rabbits, acute mexiletine significantly shortened APD<sub>90</sub> (∆APD shortening 113 ms), indicating a strong mexiletine-mediated shortening across different LQT2 model systems. Mexiletine was given to 96 patients with LQT2 either chronically (n=60) or after the acute oral drug test (n=36): 65% of the patients taking mexiletine only chronically and 75% of the patients who performed the acute oral test were responders. There was a significant correlation between basal QTc and ∆QTc during the test (<i>r</i>= -0.8; <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). The oral drug test correctly predicted long-term effect in 93% of the patients. Mexiletine reduced the mean yearly event rate from 0.10 (95% CI, 0.07-0.14) to 0.04 (95% CI, 0.02-0.08), with an incidence rate ratio of 0.40 (95% CI, 0.16-0.84), reflecting a 60% reduction in the event rate (<i>P</i>=0.01).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Mexiletine significantly shortens cardiac repolarization in LQT2 human induced pluripotent stem cells, in the LQT2 rabbit model, and in the majority of patients with LQT2. Furthermore, mexiletine showed antiarrhythmic efficacy. Mexiletine should therefore be considered a valid therapeutic option to be added to conventional therapies in higher-risk patients with LQT2.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939955/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38939955</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068959>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068959</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38939955</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Lia Crotti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Raquel Neves</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Federica Dagradi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giulia Musu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Federica Giannetti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J Martijn Bos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Miriam Barbieri</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paolo Cerea</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fulvio L F Giovenzana</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Margherita Torchio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Manuela Mura</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Massimiliano Gnecchi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giulio Conte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Angelo Auricchio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Luca Sala</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katja E Odening</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael J Ackerman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter J Schwartz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Therapeutic Efficacy of Mexiletine for Long QT Syndrome Type 2: Evidence From Human Induced Pluripotent Stem Cell-Derived Cardiomyocytes, Transgenic Rabbits, and Patients</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38939955</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.068959</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tadalafil for Treatment of Combined Postcapillary and Precapillary Pulmonary Hypertension in Patients With Heart Failure and Preserved Ejection Fraction: A Randomized Controlled Phase 3 Study</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939948/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: The PASSION trial, terminated prematurely due to study medication supply disruption, does not support tadalafil use in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension, with potential safety concerns and no observed benefits in primary and secondary end points.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 28. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069340. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: We assessed the efficacy and safety of tadalafil, a phosphodiesterase type 5 inhibitor, in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: In the double-blind PASSION study (Phosphodiesterase-5 Inhibition in Patients With Heart Failure With Preserved Ejection Fraction and Combined Post- and Pre-Capillary Pulmonary Hypertension), patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension were randomized 1:1 to receive tadalafil at a target dose of 40 mg or placebo. The primary end point was the time to the first composite event of adjudicated heart failure hospitalization or all-cause death. Secondary end points included all-cause mortality and improvements in New York Heart Association functional class or ≥10% improvement in 6-minute walking distance from baseline.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Initially targeting 372 patients, the study was terminated early because of disruption in study medication supply. At that point, 125 patients had been randomized (placebo: 63; tadalafil: 62,). Combined primary end-point events occurred in 20 patients (32%) assigned to placebo and 17 patients (27%) assigned to tadalafil (hazard ratio, 1.02 [95% CI, 0.52-2.01]; <i>P</i>=0.95). There was a possible signal of higher all-cause mortality in the tadalafil group (hazard ratio, 5.10 [95% CI, 1.10-23.69]; <i>P</i>=0.04). No significant between-group differences were observed in other secondary end points. Serious adverse events occurred in 29 participants (48%) in the tadalafil group and 35 (56%) in the placebo group.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: The PASSION trial, terminated prematurely due to study medication supply disruption, does not support tadalafil use in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and combined postcapillary and precapillary pulmonary hypertension, with potential safety concerns and no observed benefits in primary and secondary end points.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">REGISTRATION: URL: https://www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/; Unique identifier: 2017-003688-37. URL: https://drks.de; Unique identifier: DRKS -DRKS00014595.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939948/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38939948</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069340>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069340</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38939948</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Marius M Hoeper</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Britta Oerke</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Max Wissmüller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hanno Leuchte</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christian Opitz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Halank</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hans-Juergen Seyfarth</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephan Baldus</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Johann Bauersachs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Böhm</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hossein-Ardeschir Ghofrani</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stavros Konstantinides</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karen M Olsson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rolf Wachter</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carolyn S P Lam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Behnaz Aminossadati</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephan Rosenkranz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Tadalafil for Treatment of Combined Postcapillary and Precapillary Pulmonary Hypertension in Patients With Heart Failure and Preserved Ejection Fraction: A Randomized Controlled Phase 3 Study</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38939948</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.069340</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Anti-Arrhythmic Mechanisms of Epidural Blockade After Myocardial Infarction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939925/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: TEA does not compromise right ventricular function in infarcted hearts. Its antiarrhythmic mechanisms are mediated by increases in ventricular effective refractory period and ARIs, decreases in S(max), and reductions in border zone electrophysiological heterogeneities. TEA improves parasympathetic function, which may independently underlie some of its observed antiarrhythmic mechanisms. This study provides novel insights into the antiarrhythmic mechanisms of TEA while highlighting...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 28. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.324058. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Thoracic epidural anesthesia (TEA) has been shown to reduce the burden of ventricular tachycardia in small case series of patients with refractory ventricular tachycardia and cardiomyopathy. However, its electrophysiological and autonomic effects in diseased hearts remain unclear, and its use after myocardial infarction is limited by concerns for potential right ventricular dysfunction.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Myocardial infarction was created in Yorkshire pigs (N=22) by left anterior descending coronary artery occlusion. Six weeks after myocardial infarction, an epidural catheter was placed at the C7-T1 vertebral level for injection of 2% lidocaine. Right and left ventricular hemodynamics were recorded using Millar pressure-conductance catheters, and ventricular activation recovery intervals (ARIs), a surrogate of action potential durations, by a 56-electrode sock and 64-electrode basket catheter. Hemodynamics and ARIs, baroreflex sensitivity and intrinsic cardiac neural activity, and ventricular effective refractory periods and slope of restitution (S<sub>max</sub>) were assessed before and after TEA. Ventricular tachyarrhythmia inducibility was assessed by programmed electrical stimulation.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: TEA reduced inducibility of ventricular tachyarrhythmias by 70%. TEA did not affect right ventricular-systolic pressure or contractility although left ventricular-systolic pressure and contractility decreased modestly. Global and regional ventricular ARIs increased, including in scar and border zone regions post-TEA. TEA reduced ARI dispersion specifically in border zone regions. Ventricular effective refractory periods prolonged significantly at critical sites of arrhythmogenesis, and S<sub>max</sub> was reduced. Interestingly, TEA significantly improved cardiac vagal function, as measured by both baroreflex sensitivity and intrinsic cardiac neural activity.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: TEA does not compromise right ventricular function in infarcted hearts. Its antiarrhythmic mechanisms are mediated by increases in ventricular effective refractory period and ARIs, decreases in S<sub>max</sub>, and reductions in border zone electrophysiological heterogeneities. TEA improves parasympathetic function, which may independently underlie some of its observed antiarrhythmic mechanisms. This study provides novel insights into the antiarrhythmic mechanisms of TEA while highlighting its applicability to the clinical setting.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38939925/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38939925</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.324058>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.324058</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38939925</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jonathan D Hoang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valerie Y H van Weperen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ki-Woon Kang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Neil R Jani</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mohammed A Swid</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christopher A Chan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zulfiqar Ali Lokhandwala</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert L Lux</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marmar Vaseghi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Anti-Arrhythmic Mechanisms of Epidural Blockade After Myocardial Infarction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38939925</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.324058</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Transcatheter treatment of pure aortic regurgitation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38937627/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2024 Jun 27. doi: 10.1038/s41569-024-01059-1. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38937627/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38937627</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-024-01059-1>10.1038/s41569-024-01059-1</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38937627</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Marco Barbanti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giulia Laterra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Francesco Maisano</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Transcatheter treatment of pure aortic regurgitation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38937627</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-024-01059-1</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Autoimmune diseases and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38937626/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Autoimmune diseases are associated with a dramatically increased risk of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease and its clinical manifestations. The increased risk is consistent with the notion that atherogenesis is modulated by both protective and disease-promoting immune mechanisms. Notably, traditional cardiovascular risk factors such as dyslipidaemia and hypertension alone do not explain the increased risk of cardiovascular disease associated with autoimmune diseases. Several mechanisms have...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2024 Jun 27. doi: 10.1038/s41569-024-01045-7. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Autoimmune diseases are associated with a dramatically increased risk of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease and its clinical manifestations. The increased risk is consistent with the notion that atherogenesis is modulated by both protective and disease-promoting immune mechanisms. Notably, traditional cardiovascular risk factors such as dyslipidaemia and hypertension alone do not explain the increased risk of cardiovascular disease associated with autoimmune diseases. Several mechanisms have been implicated in mediating the autoimmunity-associated cardiovascular risk, either directly or by modulating the effect of other risk factors in a complex interplay. Aberrant leukocyte function and pro-inflammatory cytokines are central to both disease entities, resulting in vascular dysfunction, impaired resolution of inflammation and promotion of chronic inflammation. Similarly, loss of tolerance to self-antigens and the generation of autoantibodies are key features of autoimmunity but are also implicated in the maladaptive inflammatory response during atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease. Therefore, immunomodulatory therapies are potential efficacious interventions to directly reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease, and biomarkers of autoimmune disease activity could be relevant tools to stratify patients with autoimmunity according to their cardiovascular risk. In this Review, we discuss the pathophysiological aspects of the increased cardiovascular risk associated with autoimmunity and highlight the many open questions that need to be answered to develop novel therapies that specifically address this unmet clinical need.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38937626/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38937626</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-024-01045-7>10.1038/s41569-024-01045-7</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38937626</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Florentina Porsch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christoph J Binder</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Autoimmune diseases and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38937626</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-024-01045-7</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Preclinical proof of principle for orally delivered Th17 antagonist miniproteins</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38936360/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Interleukin (IL)-23 and IL-17 are well-validated therapeutic targets in autoinflammatory diseases. Antibodies targeting IL-23 and IL-17 have shown clinical efficacy but are limited by high costs, safety risks, lack of sustained efficacy, and poor patient convenience as they require parenteral administration. Here, we present designed miniproteins inhibiting IL-23R and IL-17 with antibody-like, low picomolar affinities at a fraction of the molecular size. The minibinders potently block cell...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 23:S0092-8674(24)00631-7. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.052. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Interleukin (IL)-23 and IL-17 are well-validated therapeutic targets in autoinflammatory diseases. Antibodies targeting IL-23 and IL-17 have shown clinical efficacy but are limited by high costs, safety risks, lack of sustained efficacy, and poor patient convenience as they require parenteral administration. Here, we present designed miniproteins inhibiting IL-23R and IL-17 with antibody-like, low picomolar affinities at a fraction of the molecular size. The minibinders potently block cell signaling in vitro and are extremely stable, enabling oral administration and low-cost manufacturing. The orally administered IL-23R minibinder shows efficacy better than a clinical anti-IL-23 antibody in mouse colitis and has a favorable pharmacokinetics (PK) and biodistribution profile in rats. This work demonstrates that orally administered de novo-designed minibinders can reach a therapeutic target past the gut epithelial barrier. With high potency, gut stability, and straightforward manufacturability, de novo-designed minibinders are a promising modality for oral biologics.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38936360/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38936360</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.052>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.052</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38936360</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Stephanie Berger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Franziska Seeger</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ta-Yi Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Merve Aydin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huilin Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel Rosenblum</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laure Guenin-Macé</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Caleb Glassman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lauren Arguinchona</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Catherine Sniezek</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alyssa Blackstone</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lauren Carter</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rashmi Ravichandran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maggie Ahlrichs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Murphy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ingrid Swanson Pultz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alex Kang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Asim K Bera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lance Stewart</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>K Christopher Garcia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shruti Naik</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jamie B Spangler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Florian Beigel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Matthias Siebeck</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Roswitha Gropp</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Baker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Preclinical proof of principle for orally delivered Th17 antagonist miniproteins</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38936360</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.052</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Amplification editing enables efficient and precise duplication of DNA from short sequence to megabase and chromosomal scale</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38936359/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Duplication is a foundation of molecular evolution and a driver of genomic and complex diseases. Here, we develop a genome editing tool named Amplification Editing (AE) that enables programmable DNA duplication with precision at chromosomal scale. AE can duplicate human genomes ranging from 20 bp to 100 Mb, a size comparable to human chromosomes. AE exhibits activity across various cell types, encompassing diploid, haploid, and primary cells. AE exhibited up to 73.0% efficiency for 1 Mb and 3.4%...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 19:S0092-8674(24)00637-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.056. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Duplication is a foundation of molecular evolution and a driver of genomic and complex diseases. Here, we develop a genome editing tool named Amplification Editing (AE) that enables programmable DNA duplication with precision at chromosomal scale. AE can duplicate human genomes ranging from 20 bp to 100 Mb, a size comparable to human chromosomes. AE exhibits activity across various cell types, encompassing diploid, haploid, and primary cells. AE exhibited up to 73.0% efficiency for 1 Mb and 3.4% for 100 Mb duplications, respectively. Whole-genome sequencing and deep sequencing of the junctions of edited sequences confirm the precision of duplication. AE can create chromosomal microduplications within disease-relevant regions in embryonic stem cells, indicating its potential for generating cellular and animal models. AE is a precise and efficient tool for chromosomal engineering and DNA duplication, broadening the landscape of precision genome editing from an individual genetic locus to the chromosomal scale.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38936359/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38936359</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.056>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.056</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38936359</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ruiwen Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhou He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yajing Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiangkun Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinyu Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guoquan Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yizhou Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pan Gao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuhan Lu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junyi Duan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shangwu Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Na Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kaitao Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bei Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuchen Xia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hao Yin</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Amplification editing enables efficient and precise duplication of DNA from short sequence to megabase and chromosomal scale</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38936359</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.056</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Great debate: device-detected subclinical atrial fibrillation should be treated like clinical atrial fibrillation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38935554/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 27:ehae365. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae365. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38935554/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38935554</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae365>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae365</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38935554</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Prashanthan Sanders</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emma Svennberg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Søren Z Diederichsen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Harry J G M Crijns</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pier D Lambiase</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giuseppe Boriani</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabelle C Van Gelder</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Great debate: device-detected subclinical atrial fibrillation should be treated like clinical atrial fibrillation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38935554</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae365</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Associations of Urban Blue and Green Spaces With Coronary Artery Calcification in Black Individuals and Disadvantaged Neighborhoods</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38934130/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Longitudinally, shorter distance to a river and greater green space cover were associated with less CAC among Black participants and those in deprived neighborhoods. Shorter distance to a park was associated with increased odds of CAC among participants in deprived neighborhoods. Black participants residing in more deprived neighborhoods showed lower odds of CAC in association with greater exposure to river and green space cover.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 27. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067992. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Proximity to urban blue and green spaces has been associated with improved cardiovascular health; however, few studies have examined the role of race and socioeconomic status in these associations.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Data were from the CARDIA study (Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults). We included longitudinal measurements (1985-1986 to 2010-2011) of blue and green spaces, including percentage of blue space cover, distance to the nearest river, green space cover, and distance to the nearest major park. Presence of coronary artery calcification (CAC) was measured with noncontrast cardiac computed tomography in 2010 to 2011. The associations of blue and green spaces with CAC were assessed with generalized estimating equation regression with adjustment for demographics, individual and neighborhood socioeconomic status, health-related behaviors, and other health conditions. We conducted stratified analyses by race and neighborhood deprivation score to investigate whether the association varied according to social determinants of health.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: The analytic sample included 1365 Black and 1555 White participants with a mean±SD age of 50.1±3.6 years. Among Black participants, shorter distance to a river and greater green space cover were associated with lower odds of CAC (per interquartile range decrease [1.45 km] to the river: odds ratio [OR], 0.90 [95% CI, 0.84-0.96]; per 10%-point increase of green space cover: OR, 0.85 [95% CI, 0.75-0.95]). Among participants in deprived neighborhoods, greater green space cover was associated with lower odds of CAC (per a 10%-point increase: OR, 0.89 [95% CI, 0.80-0.99]), whereas shorter distance to the park was associated with higher odds of CAC (per an interquartile range decrease [5.3 km]: OR, 1.07 [95% CI, 1.00-1.15]). Black participants in deprived neighborhoods had lower odds of CAC with shorter distance to a river (per an interquartile range decrease: OR, 0.90 [95% CI, 0.82-0.98]) and greater green space cover (per a 10%-point increase: OR, 0.85 [95% CI, 0.75-0.97]). There was no statistical interaction between the blue and green spaces and race or neighborhood characteristics in association with CAC.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Longitudinally, shorter distance to a river and greater green space cover were associated with less CAC among Black participants and those in deprived neighborhoods. Shorter distance to a park was associated with increased odds of CAC among participants in deprived neighborhoods. Black participants residing in more deprived neighborhoods showed lower odds of CAC in association with greater exposure to river and green space cover.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38934130/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38934130</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067992>10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067992</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38934130</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kyeezu Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brian T Joyce</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yinan Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Drew R Nannini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Penny Gordon-Larsen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ankeet Bhatt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kelley Gabriel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James M Shikany</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ming Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aimin Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Orna Reges</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mercedes R Carnethon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Donald M Lloyd-Jones</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kai Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lifang Hou</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Associations of Urban Blue and Green Spaces With Coronary Artery Calcification in Black Individuals and Disadvantaged Neighborhoods</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38934130</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.067992</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Improving Outcomes After Post-Cardiac Arrest Brain Injury: A Scientific Statement From the International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38934122/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240701121108&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>This scientific statement presents a conceptual framework for the pathophysiology of post-cardiac arrest brain injury, explores reasons for previous failure to translate preclinical data to clinical practice, and outlines potential paths forward. Post-cardiac arrest brain injury is characterized by 4 distinct but overlapping phases: ischemic depolarization, reperfusion repolarization, dysregulation, and recovery and repair. Previous research has been challenging because of the limitations of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2024 Jun 27. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001219. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">This scientific statement presents a conceptual framework for the pathophysiology of post-cardiac arrest brain injury, explores reasons for previous failure to translate preclinical data to clinical practice, and outlines potential paths forward. Post-cardiac arrest brain injury is characterized by 4 distinct but overlapping phases: ischemic depolarization, reperfusion repolarization, dysregulation, and recovery and repair. Previous research has been challenging because of the limitations of laboratory models; heterogeneity in the patient populations enrolled; overoptimistic estimation of treatment effects leading to suboptimal sample sizes; timing and route of intervention delivery; limited or absent evidence that the intervention has engaged the mechanistic target; and heterogeneity in postresuscitation care, prognostication, and withdrawal of life-sustaining treatments. Future trials must tailor their interventions to the subset of patients most likely to benefit and deliver this intervention at the appropriate time, through the appropriate route, and at the appropriate dose. The complexity of post-cardiac arrest brain injury suggests that monotherapies are unlikely to be as successful as multimodal neuroprotective therapies. Biomarkers should be developed to identify patients with the targeted mechanism of injury, to quantify its severity, and to measure the response to therapy. Studies need to be adequately powered to detect effect sizes that are realistic and meaningful to patients, their families, and clinicians. Study designs should be optimized to accelerate the evaluation of the most promising interventions. Multidisciplinary and international collaboration will be essential to realize the goal of developing effective therapies for post-cardiac arrest brain injury.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38934122/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240701121108&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38934122</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001219>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001219</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38934122</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Gavin D Perkins</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert Neumar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cindy H Hsu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karen G Hirsch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anders Aneman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lance B Becker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keith Couper</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clifton W Callaway</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cornelia W E Hoedemaekers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shir Lynn Lim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>William Meurer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Theresa Olasveengen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mypinder S Sekhon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Markus Skrifvars</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jasmeet Soar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Min-Shan Tsai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bhuma Vengamma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jerry P Nolan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Improving Outcomes After Post-Cardiac Arrest Brain Injury: A Scientific Statement From the International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38934122</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001219</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>