<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 02:47:13 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>The year in cardiovascular medicine 2024: the top 10 papers in thrombosis and antithrombotic treatment</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40084811/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Mar 14:ehaf126. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf126. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40084811/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40084811</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf126>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf126</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40084811</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Felicita Andreotti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jurriën M Ten Berg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michelle L O'Donoghue</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>The year in cardiovascular medicine 2024: the top 10 papers in thrombosis and antithrombotic treatment</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40084811</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf126</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Simultaneous CRISPR screening and spatial transcriptomics reveal intracellular, intercellular, and functional transcriptional circuits</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40081369/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Pooled optical screens have enabled the study of cellular interactions, morphology, or dynamics at massive scale, but they have not yet leveraged the power of highly plexed single-cell resolved transcriptomic readouts to inform molecular pathways. Here, we present a combination of imaging spatial transcriptomics with parallel optical detection of in situ amplified guide RNAs (Perturb-FISH). Perturb-FISH recovers intracellular effects that are consistent with single-cell RNA-sequencing-based...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Mar 10:S0092-8674(25)00197-7. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.012. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Pooled optical screens have enabled the study of cellular interactions, morphology, or dynamics at massive scale, but they have not yet leveraged the power of highly plexed single-cell resolved transcriptomic readouts to inform molecular pathways. Here, we present a combination of imaging spatial transcriptomics with parallel optical detection of in situ amplified guide RNAs (Perturb-FISH). Perturb-FISH recovers intracellular effects that are consistent with single-cell RNA-sequencing-based readouts of perturbation effects (Perturb-seq) in a screen of lipopolysaccharide response in cultured monocytes, and it uncovers intercellular and density-dependent regulation of the innate immune response. Similarly, in three-dimensional xenograft models, Perturb-FISH identifies tumor-immune interactions altered by genetic knockout. When paired with a functional readout in a separate screen of autism spectrum disorder risk genes in human-induced pluripotent stem cell (hIPSC) astrocytes, Perturb-FISH shows common calcium activity phenotypes and their associated genetic interactions and dysregulated molecular pathways. Perturb-FISH is thus a general method for studying the genetic and molecular associations of spatial and functional biology at single-cell resolution.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40081369/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40081369</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.012>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.012</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40081369</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Loϊc Binan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aiping Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Serwah A Danquah</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vera Valakh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brooke Simonton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jon Bezney</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Robert T Manguso</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kathleen B Yates</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ralda Nehme</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Brian Cleary</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samouil L Farhi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Simultaneous CRISPR screening and spatial transcriptomics reveal intracellular, intercellular, and functional transcriptional circuits</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40081369</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.012</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Crop root bacterial and viral genomes reveal unexplored species and microbiome patterns</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40081368/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Reference genomes of root microbes are essential for metagenomic analyses and mechanistic studies of crop root microbiomes. By combining high-throughput bacterial cultivation with metagenomic sequencing, we constructed comprehensive bacterial and viral genome collections from the roots of wheat, rice, maize, and Medicago. The crop root bacterial genome collection (CRBC) significantly expands the quantity and phylogenetic diversity of publicly available crop root bacterial genomes, with 6,699...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Mar 10:S0092-8674(25)00198-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.013. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Reference genomes of root microbes are essential for metagenomic analyses and mechanistic studies of crop root microbiomes. By combining high-throughput bacterial cultivation with metagenomic sequencing, we constructed comprehensive bacterial and viral genome collections from the roots of wheat, rice, maize, and Medicago. The crop root bacterial genome collection (CRBC) significantly expands the quantity and phylogenetic diversity of publicly available crop root bacterial genomes, with 6,699 bacterial genomes (68.9% from isolates) and 1,817 undefined species, expanding crop root bacterial diversity by 290.6%. The crop root viral genome collection (CRVC) contains 9,736 non-redundant viral genomes, with 1,572 previously unreported genus-level clusters in crop root microbiomes. From these, we identified conserved bacterial functions enriched in root microbiomes across soils and host species and uncovered previously unexplored bacteria-virus connections in crop root ecosystems. Together, the CRBC and CRVC serve as valuable resources for investigating microbial mechanisms and applications, supporting sustainable agriculture.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40081368/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40081368</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.013>10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.013</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40081368</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rui Dai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jingying Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fang Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haoran Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jing-Mei Qian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shani Cheskis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weidong Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Binglei Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Honghui Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lotte J U Pronk</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marnix H Medema</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ronnie de Jonge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Corné M J Pieterse</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Asaf Levy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Klaus Schlaeppi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Bai</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Crop root bacterial and viral genomes reveal unexplored species and microbiome patterns</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40081368</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.02.013</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Advances in Our Understanding of Cardiovascular Diseases After Preeclampsia</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080539/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Preeclampsia is a syndrome of hypertension in association with target organ dysfunction, including proteinuria, which manifests during pregnancy and the immediate postpartum period. The pathophysiology of preeclampsia originates from impaired trophoblastic invasion of the placental resulting in malperfusion and involves multiple mechanistic pathways that include anti-angiogenic factors, endothelial dysfunction, and immune dysregulation. Preeclampsia caries an increased risk of subclinical...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):583-593. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325581. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Preeclampsia is a syndrome of hypertension in association with target organ dysfunction, including proteinuria, which manifests during pregnancy and the immediate postpartum period. The pathophysiology of preeclampsia originates from impaired trophoblastic invasion of the placental resulting in malperfusion and involves multiple mechanistic pathways that include anti-angiogenic factors, endothelial dysfunction, and immune dysregulation. Preeclampsia caries an increased risk of subclinical cardiovascular disease including left ventricular remodeling, diastolic dysfunction, coronary artery calcification, peripheral vascular abnormalities, and microvascular dysfunction and clinical cardiovascular disease including stroke, heart failure, myocardial infarction, and death from a cardiovascular cause. This review will highlight several common mechanistic pathways shared between preeclampsia and cardiovascular diseases that provide insight into potential targets for risk reduction and disease process mitigation that can be examined in future trials.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080539/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080539</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325581>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325581</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080539</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Malamo E Countouris</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Natalie A Bello</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Advances in Our Understanding of Cardiovascular Diseases After Preeclampsia</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080539</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325581</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Understanding Thoracic Aortic Disease in Women</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080538/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Multifaceted disparities exist between men and women with thoracic aortic aneurysm and dissection. Despite a higher prevalence of thoracic aortic aneurysm and dissection among men, women experience disproportionately accelerated aneurysmal expansion, greater risks of rupture or dissection, and acute aortic syndromes that occur at relatively smaller diameters. In the context of acute type A aortic dissection, they also experience more complications, increased out-of-hospital mortality, delays in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):606-617. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325681. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Multifaceted disparities exist between men and women with thoracic aortic aneurysm and dissection. Despite a higher prevalence of thoracic aortic aneurysm and dissection among men, women experience disproportionately accelerated aneurysmal expansion, greater risks of rupture or dissection, and acute aortic syndromes that occur at relatively smaller diameters. In the context of acute type A aortic dissection, they also experience more complications, increased out-of-hospital mortality, delays in presentation and diagnosis, and worse postoperative survival. These gaps are largely driven by sex differences in vascular aging and remodeling, which include arterial stiffening associated with the hormonal changes that occur during menopause. Furthermore, the increased risk of acute type A aortic dissection during pregnancy in women with thoracic aortic disease necessitates a multidisciplinary approach to peripartum counseling and surveillance. Despite significant recent improvements in early postoperative outcomes, other disparities persist, emphasizing the need for sex-specific research, patient counseling, routine monitoring, and surgical thresholds to bridge the gap in outcomes of thoracic aortic care between sexes. Elucidating the underlying mechanisms of aortic aging and its difference between men and women, as well as moving toward personalized management protocols, will give rise to improved outcomes in the treatment of thoracic aortopathy.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080538/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080538</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325681>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325681</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080538</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bana Samman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mimi X Deng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer C Y Chung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maral Ouzounian</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Understanding Thoracic Aortic Disease in Women</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080538</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325681</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Introduction to the Compendium on Lifelong Care in Women: Applying a Sex- and Gender-Lens to Practice</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080537/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):551-552. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326335. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080537/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080537</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326335>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326335</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080537</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kathryn J Lindley</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Introduction to the Compendium on Lifelong Care in Women: Applying a Sex- and Gender-Lens to Practice</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080537</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.326335</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lifelong Care of Females With Congenital Heart Disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080536/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Medical and surgical advancements of the past 70 years have resulted in a remarkable shift in the natural history of congenital heart disease (CHD) such that survival to adulthood is expected for >;90% of children born with congenital heart defects, including those with complex CHD. There are now more adults than children living with CHD, a majority of them are female. As significant strides have been made in the management of adult patients with CHD, there has been an evolving understanding of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):553-565. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325596. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Medical and surgical advancements of the past 70 years have resulted in a remarkable shift in the natural history of congenital heart disease (CHD) such that survival to adulthood is expected for >;90% of children born with congenital heart defects, including those with complex CHD. There are now more adults than children living with CHD, a majority of them are female. As significant strides have been made in the management of adult patients with CHD, there has been an evolving understanding of the important role inherent sex-specific differences play in impacting long-term outcomes for females with CHD including differences in sexual and reproductive health, risk and incidence of acquired cardiovascular disease, and health surveillance. Notably, care for the female CHD patient is a continuum that is not isolated to discrete stages but cumulative of health exposures and experiences over a lifetime. This review aims to provide a brief overview of the current understanding of the unique health needs and considerations for females with CHD over their lifetime for both the pediatric and adult provider to help identify opportunities for care optimization, continue to raise awareness of the necessity of lifelong care and advocate for the critical need of research that prospectively evaluates pregnancy and other health-related exposures on long-term quality of life and survival for females with CHD.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080536/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080536</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325596>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325596</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080536</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Rose Tompkins</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Prashanth Venkatesh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Adam J Small</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dan G Halpern</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Lifelong Care of Females With Congenital Heart Disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080536</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325596</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Strategies for Overcoming Barriers in Access to Cardiovascular Care for Women</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080535/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Women face unique barriers to equitable health care. To ensure access to quality cardiovascular care across the lifespan of women, several systemic and social challenges need to be addressed. With the understanding that women often direct health care decisions, not only for themselves but for their family unit as well, a holistic approach to address health care barriers is warranted. This review aims to highlight key barriers to equitable health care access for women and propose potential...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):628-641. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325544. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Women face unique barriers to equitable health care. To ensure access to quality cardiovascular care across the lifespan of women, several systemic and social challenges need to be addressed. With the understanding that women often direct health care decisions, not only for themselves but for their family unit as well, a holistic approach to address health care barriers is warranted. This review aims to highlight key barriers to equitable health care access for women and propose potential strategies to overcome these barriers. This review is structured around 5 key areas in which there are gender- or sex-specific barriers to optimal outcomes: (1) insurance-related barriers, (2) geographic and social barriers, (3) health care delivery capacity and workforce issues, (4) quality and accountability measures, and (5) global health challenges. More research is needed on the sustainability, costs, and sex- and gender-specific outcomes of these solutions to drive transformative change.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080535/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080535</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325544>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325544</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080535</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Deirdre J Mattina</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael C Honigberg</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zainab Mahmoud</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karen E Joynt Maddox</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Strategies for Overcoming Barriers in Access to Cardiovascular Care for Women</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080535</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325544</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Influence of Primary Neurologic Disease on Cardiovascular Health in Females</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080534/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Neurocardiology is an interdisciplinary field that examines the complex interactions between the nervous and the cardiovascular systems, exploring how neurological processes, such as autonomic nervous system regulation and brain-heart communication impact heart function and contribute to cardiovascular health and disease. Although much of the focus on cardiovascular health has centered on traditional risk factors, the influence of the nervous system, especially in females, is increasingly...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):618-627. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325545. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Neurocardiology is an interdisciplinary field that examines the complex interactions between the nervous and the cardiovascular systems, exploring how neurological processes, such as autonomic nervous system regulation and brain-heart communication impact heart function and contribute to cardiovascular health and disease. Although much of the focus on cardiovascular health has centered on traditional risk factors, the influence of the nervous system, especially in females, is increasingly recognized as a key determinant of cardiovascular outcomes. This article reviews existing literature on the neurological mechanisms that impact cardiovascular function in females. Specifically, we analyze how primary neurological disorders including cerebrovascular disease, headache disorders, and multiple sclerosis have specific downstream effects on cardiac function. By understanding the complex relationship between neurological and cardiovascular health, this review highlights the need for sex-specific approaches to prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of cardiovascular disease in females, ultimately encouraging the discovery of more effective care strategies and improving health outcomes.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080534/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080534</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325545>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325545</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080534</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Khadija Awais Ali</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Deborah L G Kerrigan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jillian Molli Berkman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Influence of Primary Neurologic Disease on Cardiovascular Health in Females</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080534</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325545</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The 2024 US Medical Eligibility Criteria for Contraceptive Use: Application to Practice in the Care of Patients With Cardiac Disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080533/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of maternal mortality in the United States, with the majority of deaths stemming from preventable causes. Contraception is one of the tools that can be utilized to prevent mortality and morbidity associated with unplanned pregnancy in patients with underlying congenital or acquired heart disease. There are a wide range of contraceptive methods available. While some methods, especially those containing estrogen, may be associated with increased risks in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):566-582. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.325682. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of maternal mortality in the United States, with the majority of deaths stemming from preventable causes. Contraception is one of the tools that can be utilized to prevent mortality and morbidity associated with unplanned pregnancy in patients with underlying congenital or acquired heart disease. There are a wide range of contraceptive methods available. While some methods, especially those containing estrogen, may be associated with increased risks in certain cardiac disease states, intrauterine devices, implants, and progestin-only methods may be safely used by the vast majority of patients with cardiac disease. Furthermore, intrauterine devices and implants are the most effective reversible contraceptive methods available. This review provides a summary of the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention 2024 Medical Eligibility Criteria for Contraceptive Use as it applies to cardiac disease states. This review emphasizes the importance of contraceptive counseling and aims to familiarize the reader with the various forms of contraception available to patients, as well as the risks and benefits of each method in patients with different types of cardiac disease.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080533/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080533</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.325682>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.325682</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080533</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kayle Shapero</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tessa Madden</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>The 2024 US Medical Eligibility Criteria for Contraceptive Use: Application to Practice in the Care of Patients With Cardiac Disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080533</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.125.325682</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sex-Specific Factors Influencing Obesity in Women: Bridging the Gap Between Science and Clinical Practice</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080532/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Obesity in women is a significant public health issue with serious implications for cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome and cardiovascular disease. This complex challenge is influenced by physiological, hormonal, socioeconomic, and cultural factors. Women face unique weight management challenges due to hormonal changes during pregnancy, perimenopause, and menopause, which affect fat distribution and increase cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome risk. Current clinical guidelines often...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 14;136(6):594-605. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325535. Epub 2025 Mar 13.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Obesity in women is a significant public health issue with serious implications for cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome and cardiovascular disease. This complex challenge is influenced by physiological, hormonal, socioeconomic, and cultural factors. Women face unique weight management challenges due to hormonal changes during pregnancy, perimenopause, and menopause, which affect fat distribution and increase cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome risk. Current clinical guidelines often overlook these sex-specific factors, potentially limiting the effectiveness of obesity management strategies in women. This review explores the sex-specific aspects of obesity's pathophysiology, epidemiological trends, and associated comorbidities, focusing on cardiovascular and metabolic complications. This review synthesizes literature on obesity in women, emphasizing sex-specific factors influencing its development and progression. It examines the limitations of body mass index as an obesity measure and explores alternative classification methods. Additionally it investigates the relationship between obesity and comorbidities such as diabetes, hypertension, and dyslipidemia, with a focus on postmenopausal women. Obesity in women is linked to increased risks of cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome and cardiovascular disease. Hormonal fluctuations throughout life contribute to weight gain and fat distribution patterns specific to women, increasing cardiovascular disease risk. Effective obesity management strategies in women must account for these sex-specific variations. Postmenopausal women are particularly affected by obesity-related complications. Lifestyle interventions, pharmacotherapy, and bariatric surgery have shown efficacy in weight management, though success rates vary. Addressing obesity in women requires a comprehensive approach that considers sex-specific physiological factors, life-stage challenges, and sociocultural barriers. Integrating precision medicine and emerging therapies offers potential for more personalized and effective interventions. Personalized strategies that consider women's biological and life-stage challenges can enhance obesity management and improve cardiovascular outcomes. Future research and clinical practice should focus on developing tailored strategies that address women's unique vulnerabilities to obesity and its associated health risks and on validating sex-specific interventions to improve obesity management in women.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080532/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080532</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325535>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325535</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080532</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hazem Ayesh</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samar A Nasser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Keith C Ferdinand</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Barbara Gisella Carranza Leon</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Sex-Specific Factors Influencing Obesity in Women: Bridging the Gap Between Science and Clinical Practice</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080532</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325535</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Focus on amyloidosis, peripartum cardiomyopathy, and heart failure prediction by artificial intelligence applied to ECG</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080072/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Mar 13;46(11):987-990. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf084.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40080072/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40080072</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf084>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf084</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40080072</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Focus on amyloidosis, peripartum cardiomyopathy, and heart failure prediction by artificial intelligence applied to ECG</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40080072</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf084</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An update on the ESC Council on Cardiovascular Genomics: out from the niche into the open</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079516/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Mar 13:ehaf068. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf068. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079516/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40079516</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf068>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf068</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40079516</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Stefan Kääb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Antoine Bondue</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>An update on the ESC Council on Cardiovascular Genomics: out from the niche into the open</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40079516</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf068</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaders in cardiology: Holger Thiele</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079513/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Mar 13:ehaf010. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf010. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079513/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40079513</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf010>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40079513</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Judith Ozkan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Leaders in cardiology: Holger Thiele</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40079513</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>TAVI or TAVR: it is time to use a single standardized acronym for percutaneous aortic valve implantation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079495/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Mar 13:ehaf048. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf048. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079495/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40079495</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf048>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf048</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40079495</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ciro Indolfi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giovanni Esposito</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas F Lüscher</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>TAVI or TAVR: it is time to use a single standardized acronym for percutaneous aortic valve implantation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40079495</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf048</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>March2 Alleviates Aortic Aneurysm/Dissection by Regulating PKM2 Polymerization</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079144/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: Our findings demonstrated that March2 is a novel endogenous defender that prevents AAD by inhibiting vascular smooth muscle cell apoptosis, suggesting that March2 represents a potential therapeutic target for AAD.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2025 Mar 13. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325049. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Aortic aneurysm/dissection (AAD) is a life-threatening disease lacking effective pharmacological treatment. Protein ubiquitination plays a pivotal role in cardiovascular diseases. However, the possible contribution of the E3 ubiquitin ligase March2 (membrane-associated RING finger protein 2) to the cause of AAD remains elusive.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Integrated single-cell RNA sequencing analysis was conducted in human AAD tissues. Based on the screening results, we generated a mouse line of smooth muscle cell-specific March2 knockout. β-Aminopropionitrile monofumarate was used to establish AAD. Cleavage under targets and tagmentation and cleavage under targets and tagmentation-quantitative polymerase chain reaction were performed to identify possible target genes for histone H3K18 lactylation.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: March2 expression was downregulated in aorta from patients with AAD or β-aminopropionitrile monofumarate-induced AAD mice. β-Aminopropionitrile monofumarate-induced AAD was significantly accentuated in March2 global (March2<sup>-/-</sup>) and vascular smooth muscle cell-specific deletion (March2<sup>fl/fl</sup>; Tagln<sup>Cre</sup>) mice, whereas the AAD pathology was rescued by rAAV9-SM22α-March2 (recombinant adeno-associated virus serotype 9 expressing Flag-tagged March2 under SM22α promoter). March2 interacted with PKM2 (pyruvate kinase M2) to promote K33-linked polyubiquitination. Deficiency of March2 lessened PKM2 dimer-to-tetramer conversion in AAD and overtly exacerbated AAD-induced histone H3K18 lactylation in vascular smooth muscle cells by fostering glucose metabolism reprogramming, thereby promoting p53-driven apoptotic transcriptional response-a hallmark of AAD pathogenesis. TEPP-46, a PKM2-specific activator, pronouncedly alleviated March2 deficiency-deteriorated AAD pathology.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: Our findings demonstrated that March2 is a novel endogenous defender that prevents AAD by inhibiting vascular smooth muscle cell apoptosis, suggesting that March2 represents a potential therapeutic target for AAD.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079144/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40079144</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325049>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325049</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40079144</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yiran E Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuolin Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Litao Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuxin Du</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lin Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haoran Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tingfang Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jie Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shengjun Xiong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yayu Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qijun Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rongjun Zou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ling Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zheyun Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lixin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junbo Ge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun Ren</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingmei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>March2 Alleviates Aortic Aneurysm/Dissection by Regulating PKM2 Polymerization</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40079144</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.325049</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Direct-to-Consumer Genetic Testing for Cardiovascular Disease: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079117/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Despite insufficient evidence to support direct-to-consumer genetic testing in routine clinical care, cardiovascular clinicians increasingly face questions about its utility and interpretation because individuals can purchase these tests directly from laboratories. A burgeoning marketplace offers an expanding array of testing options. In many cases, direct-to-consumer genetic testing advertises information that could inform one's risk of heritable disease, including insight into having a genetic...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Circulation</b>. 2025 Mar 13. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001304. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite insufficient evidence to support direct-to-consumer genetic testing in routine clinical care, cardiovascular clinicians increasingly face questions about its utility and interpretation because individuals can purchase these tests directly from laboratories. A burgeoning marketplace offers an expanding array of testing options. In many cases, direct-to-consumer genetic testing advertises information that could inform one's risk of heritable disease, including insight into having a genetic predisposition to cardiovascular disease or data about gene-drug interactions that could affect response to cardiovascular medications. Navigating clinical questions about direct-to-consumer genetic testing involves understanding the evolution and oversight of the marketplace; the scope of direct-to-consumer genetic testing offerings; and the risks, benefits, and limitations of said testing. In this American Heart Association scientific statement, we summarize the state of the direct-to-consumer genetic testing industry, review types of cardiovascular genetic information that may be included in direct-to-consumer genetic testing, describe approaches to evaluate test quality, and provide resources for clinicians navigating questions about direct-to-consumer genetic testing. If direct-to-consumer genetic test information is used in clinical care, care should be taken to assess the limitations of the test, to contextualize the information specifically to the patient, and to corroborate potentially actionable monogenic findings.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40079117/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40079117</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000001304>10.1161/CIR.0000000000001304</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40079117</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Leland E Hull</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Aaron W Aday</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Quan M Bui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jasmine A Luzum</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>James M Muchira</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hannah Wand</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>C Anwar A Chahal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mina K Chung</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anne E Kwitek</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Silvana Molossi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pradeep Natarajan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>American Heart Association Data Science and Precision Medicine Committee of the Council on Genomic and Precision Medicine and Council of Clinical Cardiology; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Lifestyle and Cardiometabolic Health; and Council on Peripheral Vascular Disease</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation</dc:source>
<dc:title>Direct-to-Consumer Genetic Testing for Cardiovascular Disease: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40079117</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001304</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reply: The Impact of Patiromer on Heart Failure Treatment With Angiotensin Inhibitors and MRAs</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074478/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Mar 18;85(10):e115. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.029.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074478/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40074478</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.029>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.029</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40074478</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Bertram Pitt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey Budden</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stefan D Anker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Javed Butler</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Reply: The Impact of Patiromer on Heart Failure Treatment With Angiotensin Inhibitors and MRAs</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40074478</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.029</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Impact of Patiromer on Heart Failure Treatment With Angiotensin Inhibitors and MRAs</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074477/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Mar 18;85(10):e113. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.09.1248.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074477/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40074477</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.09.1248>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.09.1248</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40074477</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Wei-Zhen Tang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qin-Yu Cai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yun-Ren Pan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tai-Hang Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying-Bo Li</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>The Impact of Patiromer on Heart Failure Treatment With Angiotensin Inhibitors and MRAs</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40074477</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.09.1248</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reply: Urinary Metal Levels and Coronary Artery Calcification: Potential Confounders</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074476/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Mar 18;85(10):e111. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.050.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074476/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40074476</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.050>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.050</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40074476</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Katlyn E McGraw</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Steven Shea</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ana Navas-Acien</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tiffany R Sanchez</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Reply: Urinary Metal Levels and Coronary Artery Calcification: Potential Confounders</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40074476</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.050</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Environmental Metal Exposure and Cardiovascular Disease Risk</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074475/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250314224710&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Mar 18;85(10):e109. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.127.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40074475/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250314224710&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">40074475</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.127>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.127</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:40074475</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jixuan Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zili Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Environmental Metal Exposure and Cardiovascular Disease Risk</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:40074475</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.127</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>