<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;ff=20250126011322
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;ff=20250126011322" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 06:13:23 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Designed mosaic nanoparticles enhance cross-reactive immune responses in mice</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855201/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Nanoparticle vaccines displaying combinations of SARS-like betacoronavirus (sarbecovirus) receptor-binding domains (RBDs) could protect against SARS-CoV-2 variants and spillover of zoonotic sarbecoviruses into humans. Using a computational approach, we designed variants of SARS-CoV-2 RBDs and selected 7 natural sarbecovirus RBDs, each predicted to fold properly and abrogate antibody responses to variable epitopes. RBDs were attached to 60-mer nanoparticles to make immunogens displaying two...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 16:S0092-8674(24)01428-4. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.015. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Nanoparticle vaccines displaying combinations of SARS-like betacoronavirus (sarbecovirus) receptor-binding domains (RBDs) could protect against SARS-CoV-2 variants and spillover of zoonotic sarbecoviruses into humans. Using a computational approach, we designed variants of SARS-CoV-2 RBDs and selected 7 natural sarbecovirus RBDs, each predicted to fold properly and abrogate antibody responses to variable epitopes. RBDs were attached to 60-mer nanoparticles to make immunogens displaying two (mosaic-2<sub>COM</sub>s), five (mosaic-5<sub>COM</sub>), or seven (mosaic-7<sub>COM</sub>) different RBDs for comparisons with mosaic-8b, which elicited cross-reactive antibodies and protected animals from sarbecovirus challenges. Naive and COVID-19 pre-vaccinated mice immunized with mosaic-7<sub>COM</sub> elicited antibodies targeting conserved RBD epitopes, and their sera exhibited higher binding and neutralization titers against sarbecoviruses than mosaic-8b. Mosaic-2<sub>COM</sub>s and mosaic-5<sub>COM</sub> elicited higher antibody potencies against some SARS-CoV-2 variants than mosaic-7<sub>COM</sub>. However, mosaic-7<sub>COM</sub> elicited more potent responses against zoonotic sarbecoviruses and highly mutated Omicrons, supporting its use to protect against SARS-CoV-2 variants and zoonotic sarbecoviruses.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855201/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855201</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.015>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.015</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855201</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Eric Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alexander A Cohen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Luis F Caldera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer R Keeffe</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Annie V Rorick</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yusuf M Adia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Priyanthi N P Gnanapragasam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pamela J Bjorkman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arup K Chakraborty</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Designed mosaic nanoparticles enhance cross-reactive immune responses in mice</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855201</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.015</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>A pair of LysM receptors mediates symbiosis and immunity discrimination in Marchantia</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855200/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Most land plants form symbioses with microbes to acquire nutrients but also must restrict infection by pathogens. Here, we show that a single pair of lysin-motif-containing receptor-like kinases, MpaLYR and MpaCERK1, mediates both immunity and symbiosis in the liverwort Marchantia paleacea. MpaLYR has a higher affinity for long-chain (CO7) versus short-chain chitin oligomers (CO4). Although both CO7 and CO4 can activate symbiosis-related genes, CO7 triggers stronger immune responses than CO4 in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 17:S0092-8674(24)01466-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.024. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Most land plants form symbioses with microbes to acquire nutrients but also must restrict infection by pathogens. Here, we show that a single pair of lysin-motif-containing receptor-like kinases, MpaLYR and MpaCERK1, mediates both immunity and symbiosis in the liverwort Marchantia paleacea. MpaLYR has a higher affinity for long-chain (CO7) versus short-chain chitin oligomers (CO4). Although both CO7 and CO4 can activate symbiosis-related genes, CO7 triggers stronger immune responses than CO4 in a dosage-dependent manner. CO4 can inhibit CO7-induced strong immune responses, recapitulating the early response to inoculation with the symbiont arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi. We show that phosphate starvation of plants increases their production of strigolactone, which stimulates CO4/CO5 secretion from mycorrhizal fungi, thereby prioritizing symbiosis over immunity. Thus, a single pair of LysM receptors mediates dosage-dependent perception of different chitin oligomers to discern symbiotic and pathogenic microbes in M. paleacea, which may facilitate terrestrialization.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855200/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855200</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.024>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.024</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855200</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Xinhang Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dapeng Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaowei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuang Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaojie Jia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zilin Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hao Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huiling Dai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xi Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhixin Qian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ran Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Miaolian Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peng Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nan Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ertao Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>A pair of LysM receptors mediates symbiosis and immunity discrimination in Marchantia</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855200</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.024</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Comparative proteomic landscapes elucidate human preimplantation development and failure</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855199/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Understanding mammalian preimplantation development, particularly in humans, at the proteomic level remains limited. Here, we applied our comprehensive solution of ultrasensitive proteomic technology to measure the proteomic profiles of oocytes and early embryos and identified nearly 8,000 proteins in humans and over 6,300 proteins in mice. We observed distinct proteomic dynamics before and around zygotic genome activation (ZGA) between the two species. Integrative analysis with translatomic...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 17:S0092-8674(24)01470-3. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.028. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Understanding mammalian preimplantation development, particularly in humans, at the proteomic level remains limited. Here, we applied our comprehensive solution of ultrasensitive proteomic technology to measure the proteomic profiles of oocytes and early embryos and identified nearly 8,000 proteins in humans and over 6,300 proteins in mice. We observed distinct proteomic dynamics before and around zygotic genome activation (ZGA) between the two species. Integrative analysis with translatomic data revealed extensive divergence between translation activation and protein accumulation. Multi-omic analysis indicated that ZGA transcripts often contribute to protein accumulation in blastocysts. Using mouse embryos, we identified several transcriptional regulators critical for early development, thereby linking ZGA to the first lineage specification. Furthermore, single-embryo proteomics of poor-quality embryos from over 100 patient couples provided insights into preimplantation development failure. Our study may contribute to reshaping the framework of mammalian preimplantation development and opening avenues for addressing human infertility.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855199/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855199</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.028>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.028</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855199</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Wencheng Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Juan Meng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yan Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Gu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenjun Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ziyi Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoyu Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zihong Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yonggen Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guiquan Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junfeng Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huiping Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haiyan Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xi Dong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuefeng Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yidi Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chen Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liangshan Mu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhen Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Comparative proteomic landscapes elucidate human preimplantation development and failure</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855199</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.028</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Assembly and architecture of endogenous NMDA receptors in adult cerebral cortex and hippocampus</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855198/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The cerebral cortex and hippocampus are crucial brain regions for learning and memory, which depend on activity-induced synaptic plasticity involving N-methyl-ᴅ-aspartate receptors (NMDARs). However, subunit assembly and molecular architecture of endogenous NMDARs (eNMDARs) in the brain remain elusive. Using conformation- and subunit-dependent antibodies, we purified eNMDARs from adult rat cerebral cortex and hippocampus. Three major subtypes of GluN1-N2A-N2B, GluN1-N2B, and GluN1-N2A eNMDARs...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 17:S0092-8674(25)00033-9. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.004. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The cerebral cortex and hippocampus are crucial brain regions for learning and memory, which depend on activity-induced synaptic plasticity involving N-methyl-ᴅ-aspartate receptors (NMDARs). However, subunit assembly and molecular architecture of endogenous NMDARs (eNMDARs) in the brain remain elusive. Using conformation- and subunit-dependent antibodies, we purified eNMDARs from adult rat cerebral cortex and hippocampus. Three major subtypes of GluN1-N2A-N2B, GluN1-N2B, and GluN1-N2A eNMDARs were resolved by cryoelectron microscopy (cryo-EM) at the resolution up to 4.2 Å. The particle ratio of these three subtypes was 9:7:4, indicating that about half of GluN2A and GluN2B subunits are incorporated into the tri-heterotetramers. Structural analysis revealed the asymmetric architecture of the GluN1-N2A-N2B receptor throughout the extracellular to the transmembrane layers. Moreover, the conformational variations between GluN1-N2B and GluN1-N2A-N2B receptors revealed the distinct biophysical properties across different eNMDAR subtypes. Our findings imply the structural and functional complexity of eNMDARs and shed light on structure-based therapeutic design targeting these eNMDARs in vivo.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855198/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855198</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.004>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.004</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855198</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ming Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Juan Feng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chun Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nan Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chaozhi Jin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jian Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qun Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lihua Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Boshuang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yidi Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fei Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shujia Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Assembly and architecture of endogenous NMDA receptors in adult cerebral cortex and hippocampus</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855198</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.004</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cardiometabolic benefits of a non-industrialized-type diet are linked to gut microbiome modulation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855197/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Industrialization adversely affects the gut microbiome and predisposes individuals to chronic non-communicable diseases. We tested a microbiome restoration strategy comprising a diet that recapitulated key characteristics of non-industrialized dietary patterns (restore diet) and a bacterium rarely found in industrialized microbiomes (Limosilactobacillus reuteri) in a randomized controlled feeding trial in healthy Canadian adults. The restore diet, despite reducing gut microbiome diversity,...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 20:S0092-8674(24)01477-6. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.034. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Industrialization adversely affects the gut microbiome and predisposes individuals to chronic non-communicable diseases. We tested a microbiome restoration strategy comprising a diet that recapitulated key characteristics of non-industrialized dietary patterns (restore diet) and a bacterium rarely found in industrialized microbiomes (Limosilactobacillus reuteri) in a randomized controlled feeding trial in healthy Canadian adults. The restore diet, despite reducing gut microbiome diversity, enhanced the persistence of L. reuteri strain from rural Papua New Guinea (PB-W1) and redressed several microbiome features altered by industrialization. The diet also beneficially altered microbiota-derived plasma metabolites implicated in the etiology of chronic non-communicable diseases. Considerable cardiometabolic benefits were observed independently of L. reuteri administration, several of which could be accurately predicted by baseline and diet-responsive microbiome features. The findings suggest that a dietary intervention targeted toward restoring the gut microbiome can improve host-microbiome interactions that likely underpin chronic pathologies, which can guide dietary recommendations and the development of therapeutic and nutritional strategies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855197/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855197</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.034>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.034</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855197</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Fuyong Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anissa M Armet</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Katri Korpela</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junhong Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rodrigo Margain Quevedo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Francesco Asnicar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Benjamin Seethaler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianna B S Rusnak</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Janis L Cole</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhihong Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shuang Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaohang Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Adele Gagnon</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Edward C Deehan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>João F Mota</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey A Bakal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Russell Greiner</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dan Knights</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicola Segata</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stephan C Bischoff</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laurie Mereu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andrea M Haqq</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Catherine J Field</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liang Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carla M Prado</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jens Walter</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cardiometabolic benefits of a non-industrialized-type diet are linked to gut microbiome modulation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855197</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.034</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rational multienzyme architecture design with iMARS</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855196/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Biocatalytic cascades with spatial proximity can orchestrate multistep pathways to form metabolic highways, which enhance the overall catalytic efficiency. However, the effect of spatial organization on catalytic activity is poorly understood, and multienzyme architectural engineering with predictable performance remains unrealized. Here, we developed a standardized framework, called iMARS, to rapidly design the optimal multienzyme architecture by integrating high-throughput activity tests and...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 17:S0092-8674(24)01471-5. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.029. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Biocatalytic cascades with spatial proximity can orchestrate multistep pathways to form metabolic highways, which enhance the overall catalytic efficiency. However, the effect of spatial organization on catalytic activity is poorly understood, and multienzyme architectural engineering with predictable performance remains unrealized. Here, we developed a standardized framework, called iMARS, to rapidly design the optimal multienzyme architecture by integrating high-throughput activity tests and structural analysis. The approach showed potential for industrial-scale applications, with artificial fusion enzymes designed by iMARS significantly improving the production of resveratrol by 45.1-fold and raspberry ketone by 11.3-fold in vivo, as well as enhancing ergothioneine synthesis in fed-batch fermentation. In addition, iMARS greatly enhanced the in vitro catalytic efficiency of the multienzyme complexes for PET plastic depolymerization and vanillin biosynthesis. As a generalizable and flexible strategy at molecular level, iMARS could greatly facilitate green chemistry, synthetic biology, and biomanufacturing.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855196/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855196</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.029>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.029</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855196</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jiawei Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xingyu Ouyang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shiyu Meng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bowen Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liangxu Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chaofeng Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hengrun Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haotian Zheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yihan Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ting Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi-Lei Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jun Ni</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Rational multienzyme architecture design with iMARS</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855196</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.029</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Centromeric chromatin clearings demarcate the site of kinetochore formation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855195/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The centromere is the chromosomal locus that recruits the kinetochore, directing faithful propagation of the genome during cell division. Using cryo-ET on human mitotic chromosomes, we reveal a distinctive architecture at the centromere: clustered 20- to 25-nm nucleosome-associated complexes within chromatin clearings that delineate them from surrounding chromatin. Centromere components CENP-C and CENP-N are each required for the integrity of the complexes, while CENP-C is also required to...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 23:S0092-8674(24)01467-3. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.025. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The centromere is the chromosomal locus that recruits the kinetochore, directing faithful propagation of the genome during cell division. Using cryo-ET on human mitotic chromosomes, we reveal a distinctive architecture at the centromere: clustered 20- to 25-nm nucleosome-associated complexes within chromatin clearings that delineate them from surrounding chromatin. Centromere components CENP-C and CENP-N are each required for the integrity of the complexes, while CENP-C is also required to maintain the chromatin clearing. We find that CENP-C is required in mitosis, not just for kinetochore assembly, likely reflecting its role in organizing the inner kinetochore during chromosome segregation. We further visualize the scaffold of the fibrous corona, a structure amplified at unattached kinetochores, revealing crescent-shaped parallel arrays of fibrils extending >;1 μm. Thus, we reveal how the organization of centromeric chromatin creates a clearing at the site of kinetochore formation as well as the nature of kinetochore amplification mediated by corona fibrils.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855195/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855195</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.025>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.025</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855195</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Kathryn Kixmoeller</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ekaterina V Tarasovetc</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elie Mer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi-Wei Chang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ben E Black</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Centromeric chromatin clearings demarcate the site of kinetochore formation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855195</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.025</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>High-resolution spatially resolved proteomics of complex tissues based on microfluidics and transfer learning</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855194/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Despite recent advances in imaging- and antibody-based methods, achieving in-depth, high-resolution protein mapping across entire tissues remains a significant challenge in spatial proteomics. Here, we present parallel-flow projection and transfer learning across omics data (PLATO), an integrated framework combining microfluidics with deep learning to enable high-resolution mapping of thousands of proteins in whole tissue sections. We validated the PLATO framework by profiling the spatial...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 20:S0092-8674(24)01436-3. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.023. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Despite recent advances in imaging- and antibody-based methods, achieving in-depth, high-resolution protein mapping across entire tissues remains a significant challenge in spatial proteomics. Here, we present parallel-flow projection and transfer learning across omics data (PLATO), an integrated framework combining microfluidics with deep learning to enable high-resolution mapping of thousands of proteins in whole tissue sections. We validated the PLATO framework by profiling the spatial proteome of the mouse cerebellum, identifying 2,564 protein groups in a single run. We then applied PLATO to rat villus and human breast cancer samples, achieving a spatial resolution of 25 μm and uncovering proteomic dynamics associated with disease states. This approach revealed spatially distinct tumor subtypes, identified key dysregulated proteins, and provided novel insights into the complexity of the tumor microenvironment. We believe that PLATO represents a transformative platform for exploring spatial proteomic regulation and its interplay with genetic and environmental factors.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855194/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855194</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.023>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.023</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855194</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Beiyu Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruiqiao He</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kun Pang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guibin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ning Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wenzhuo Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xin Sui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huajing Teng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianxin Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Junjie Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zewen Jiang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jinyang Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhenqiang Zuo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weihu Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peifeng Ji</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fangqing Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>High-resolution spatially resolved proteomics of complex tissues based on microfluidics and transfer learning</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855194</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.023</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Structure-guided discovery of viral proteins that inhibit host immunity</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855193/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Viruses encode proteins that inhibit host defenses, but sifting through the millions of available viral sequences for immune-modulatory proteins has been so far impractical. Here, we develop a process to systematically screen virus-encoded proteins for inhibitors that physically bind host immune proteins. Focusing on Thoeris and CBASS, bacterial defense systems that are the ancestors of eukaryotic Toll/interleukin-1 receptor (TIR) and cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) immunity, we discover seven...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 20:S0092-8674(24)01478-8. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.035. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Viruses encode proteins that inhibit host defenses, but sifting through the millions of available viral sequences for immune-modulatory proteins has been so far impractical. Here, we develop a process to systematically screen virus-encoded proteins for inhibitors that physically bind host immune proteins. Focusing on Thoeris and CBASS, bacterial defense systems that are the ancestors of eukaryotic Toll/interleukin-1 receptor (TIR) and cyclic GMP-AMP synthase (cGAS) immunity, we discover seven families of Thoeris and CBASS inhibitors, encompassing thousands of genes widespread in phages. Verified inhibitors exhibit extensive physical interactions with the respective immune protein counterpart, with all inhibitors blocking the active site of the immune protein. Remarkably, a phage-encoded inhibitor of bacterial TIR proteins can bind and inhibit distantly related human and plant immune TIRs, and a phage-derived inhibitor of bacterial cGAS-like enzymes can inhibit the human cGAS. Our results demonstrate that phages are a reservoir for immune-modulatory proteins capable of inhibiting bacterial, animal, and plant immunity.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855193/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855193</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.035>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.035</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855193</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Erez Yirmiya</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samuel J Hobbs</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Azita Leavitt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ilya Osterman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Carmel Avraham</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dina Hochhauser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Barak Madhala</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marharyta Skovorodka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joel M J Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hunter C Toyoda</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Igor Chebotar</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Maxim Itkin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sergey Malitsky</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gil Amitai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Philip J Kranzusch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rotem Sorek</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Structure-guided discovery of viral proteins that inhibit host immunity</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855193</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.035</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cell Line: 2014-2024</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855153/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 23;188(2):569-572. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.026.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855153/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855153</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.026>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.026</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855153</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Cell editorial team</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cell Line: 2014-2024</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855153</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.026</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rings of death: How NINJ1 executes plasma membrane rupture</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855152/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Plasma membrane rupture during lytic cell death was previously believed to occur through passive osmosis that burst open the membrane. Recent publications, including one in this issue of Cell, suggest that plasma membrane rupture is an active process mediated by ninjurin-1 (NINJ1) oligomers that dissolve membranes and/or assemble large pores.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 23;188(2):277-279. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.030.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Plasma membrane rupture during lytic cell death was previously believed to occur through passive osmosis that burst open the membrane. Recent publications, including one in this issue of Cell, suggest that plasma membrane rupture is an active process mediated by ninjurin-1 (NINJ1) oligomers that dissolve membranes and/or assemble large pores.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855152/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855152</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.030>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.030</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855152</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Zhonghua Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tsan Sam Xiao</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Rings of death: How NINJ1 executes plasma membrane rupture</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855152</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.030</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cell after 50</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855151/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 23;188(2):273-274. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.033.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39855151/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39855151</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.033>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.033</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39855151</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>John W Pham</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cell after 50</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39855151</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.033</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The relationship between cannabis and cardiovascular disease: clearing the haze</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39849111/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cannabis has been consumed for centuries, but global regulatory changes over the past three decades have increased the availability and consumption of cannabis. Cannabinoids are touted to have therapeutic potential for many diseases and could be a replacement for opioids for analgesia and sedation. However, cannabinoids can cause substantial adverse cardiovascular events that would mitigate any potential benefit. The endocannabinoid system regulates mood, satiety and memory, and modulates the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2025 Jan 23. doi: 10.1038/s41569-025-01121-6. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cannabis has been consumed for centuries, but global regulatory changes over the past three decades have increased the availability and consumption of cannabis. Cannabinoids are touted to have therapeutic potential for many diseases and could be a replacement for opioids for analgesia and sedation. However, cannabinoids can cause substantial adverse cardiovascular events that would mitigate any potential benefit. The endocannabinoid system regulates mood, satiety and memory, and modulates the cardiovascular system. The link between cannabinoids and cardiovascular disease, which used to be limited to evidence from preclinical studies, case reports and case series, is now evident in epidemiological studies. Cannabinoids adversely affect the cardiovascular system, causing myocardial infarction, cerebrovascular accidents, arrhythmia and heart failure. The effects of novel cannabinoids are unknown, and synthetic cannabinoids have the potential to cause even more substantial harm than traditional cannabinoids. Therefore, with the increasing availability and use of cannabis, the acute and chronic effects of this drug are becoming apparent.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39849111/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39849111</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-025-01121-6>10.1038/s41569-025-01121-6</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39849111</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mark Chandy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nerea Jimenez-Tellez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph C Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>The relationship between cannabis and cardiovascular disease: clearing the haze</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39849111</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-025-01121-6</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Integration of 168,000 samples reveals global patterns of the human gut microbiome</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848248/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The factors shaping human microbiome variation are a major focus of biomedical research. While other fields have used large sequencing compendia to extract insights requiring otherwise impractical sample sizes, the microbiome field has lacked a comparably sized resource for the 16S rRNA gene amplicon sequencing commonly used to quantify microbiome composition. To address this gap, we processed 168,464 publicly available human gut microbiome samples with a uniform pipeline. We use this compendium...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 16:S0092-8674(24)01430-2. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.017. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The factors shaping human microbiome variation are a major focus of biomedical research. While other fields have used large sequencing compendia to extract insights requiring otherwise impractical sample sizes, the microbiome field has lacked a comparably sized resource for the 16S rRNA gene amplicon sequencing commonly used to quantify microbiome composition. To address this gap, we processed 168,464 publicly available human gut microbiome samples with a uniform pipeline. We use this compendium to evaluate geographic and technical effects on microbiome variation. We find that regions such as Central and Southern Asia differ significantly from the more thoroughly characterized microbiomes of Europe and Northern America and that composition alone can be used to predict a sample's region of origin. We also find strong associations between microbiome variation and technical factors such as primers and DNA extraction. We anticipate this growing work, the Human Microbiome Compendium, will enable advanced applied and methodological research.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848248/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39848248</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.017>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.017</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39848248</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Richard J Abdill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Samantha P Graham</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Vincent Rubinetti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mansooreh Ahmadian</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Parker Hicks</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ashwin Chetty</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniel McDonald</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pamela Ferretti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth Gibbons</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marco Rossi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Arjun Krishnan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frank W Albert</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Casey S Greene</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sean Davis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ran Blekhman</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Integration of 168,000 samples reveals global patterns of the human gut microbiome</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39848248</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.017</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Massively parallel reporter assay investigates shared genetic variants of eight psychiatric disorders</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848247/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>A meta-genome-wide association study across eight psychiatric disorders has highlighted the genetic architecture of pleiotropy in major psychiatric disorders. However, mechanisms underlying pleiotropic effects of the associated variants remain to be explored. We conducted a massively parallel reporter assay to decode the regulatory logic of variants with pleiotropic and disorder-specific effects. Pleiotropic variants differ from disorder-specific variants by exhibiting chromatin accessibility...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 20:S0092-8674(24)01435-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.022. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">A meta-genome-wide association study across eight psychiatric disorders has highlighted the genetic architecture of pleiotropy in major psychiatric disorders. However, mechanisms underlying pleiotropic effects of the associated variants remain to be explored. We conducted a massively parallel reporter assay to decode the regulatory logic of variants with pleiotropic and disorder-specific effects. Pleiotropic variants differ from disorder-specific variants by exhibiting chromatin accessibility that extends across diverse cell types in the neuronal lineage and by altering motifs for transcription factors with higher connectivity in protein-protein interaction networks. We mapped pleiotropic and disorder-specific variants to putative target genes using functional genomics approaches and CRISPR perturbation. In vivo CRISPR perturbation of a pleiotropic and a disorder-specific gene suggests that pleiotropy may involve the regulation of genes expressed broadly across neuronal cell types and with higher network connectivity.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848247/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39848247</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.022>10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.022</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39848247</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sool Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jessica C McAfee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiseok Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alejandro Gomez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Austin T Ledford</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Declan Clarke</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hyunggyu Min</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mark B Gerstein</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alan P Boyle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrick F Sullivan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Adriana S Beltran</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hyejung Won</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Massively parallel reporter assay investigates shared genetic variants of eight psychiatric disorders</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39848247</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.12.022</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Receptor binding, structure, and tissue tropism of cattle-infecting H5N1 avian influenza virus hemagglutinin</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848246/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The ongoing circulation of highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) A (H5N1) viruses, particularly clade 2.3.4.4b strains, poses a significant threat to animal and public health. Recent outbreaks in cattle highlight concerns about cross-species transmission and zoonotic spillover. Here, we found that the hemagglutinin (HA) protein from a cattle-infecting H5N1 virus has acquired slight binding to human-like α2-6-linked receptors while still exhibiting a strong preference for avian-like...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2025 Jan 22:S0092-8674(25)00048-0. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.019. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The ongoing circulation of highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) A (H5N1) viruses, particularly clade 2.3.4.4b strains, poses a significant threat to animal and public health. Recent outbreaks in cattle highlight concerns about cross-species transmission and zoonotic spillover. Here, we found that the hemagglutinin (HA) protein from a cattle-infecting H5N1 virus has acquired slight binding to human-like α2-6-linked receptors while still exhibiting a strong preference for avian-like α2-3-linked sialic acid receptors. Immunohistochemical staining revealed HA binding to bovine pulmonary and mammary tissues, aligning with clinical observations. HA also binds effectively to human conjunctival, tracheal, and mammary tissues, indicating a risk for human transmission, notably in cases of conjunctivitis. High-resolution cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) structures of this H5 HA in complex with either α2-3 or α2-6 receptors elucidate the molecular mechanisms underlying its receptor-binding properties. These findings provide critical insights into the tropism and transmission potential of this emerging pathogen.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39848246/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39848246</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.019>10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.019</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39848246</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hao Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tianjiao Hao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pu Han</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haichen Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xu Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaomei Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuxuan Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiamin Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ying Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiyue Jin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuefeng Duan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wei Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuhai Bi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ronghua Jin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ningli Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>George F Gao</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Receptor binding, structure, and tissue tropism of cattle-infecting H5N1 avian influenza virus hemagglutinin</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39848246</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2025.01.019</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Fatal coronary embolism in infective endocarditis: a case of sudden circulatory collapse</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39847400/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2025 Jan 23:ehaf014. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf014. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39847400/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39847400</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf014>10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf014</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39847400</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shinichi Yamanaka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hideaki Suzuki</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Satoshi Yasuda</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Fatal coronary embolism in infective endocarditis: a case of sudden circulatory collapse</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39847400</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf014</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Can Outpatient Worsening Heart Failure Serve as an Endpoint in Clinical Trials of Transthyretin Amyloidosis?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846939/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Jan 16:S0735-1097(24)10558-X. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.126. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846939/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39846939</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.126>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.126</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39846939</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Richard K Cheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Douglas Leedy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frederick L Ruberg</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Can Outpatient Worsening Heart Failure Serve as an Endpoint in Clinical Trials of Transthyretin Amyloidosis?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39846939</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.126</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Associations of Short-Term Ozone Exposure With Hypoxia and Arterial Stiffness</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846938/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: O(3) exposure may reduce oxygen availability, prompting compensatory increases in red blood cells and hemoglobin, which exacerbate arterial stiffening. These findings provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying O(3)-induced cardiovascular injury.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Jan 16:S0735-1097(24)10559-1. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.044. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Epidemiological studies reported associations between ozone (O<sub>3</sub>) exposure and cardiovascular diseases, yet the biological mechanisms remain underexplored. Hypoxia is a shared pathogenesis of O<sub>3</sub>-associated diseases; therefore, we hypothesized that O<sub>3</sub> exposure may induce changes in hypoxia-related markers, leading to adverse cardiovascular effects.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: This study aimed to investigate associations of short-term O<sub>3</sub> exposure with hypoxic biomarkers and arterial stiffness.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: We conducted a panel study involving 210 young healthy residents in 2 cities at different altitudes on the Qinghai-Tibetan Plateau in China, where O<sub>3</sub> concentrations are high and particulate pollution is low. Participants underwent 4 repeated visits to assess ambient O<sub>3</sub> exposure levels, hypoxic biomarkers, and arterial stiffness. We applied linear mixed-effects models to assess the associations of O<sub>3</sub> exposure (lag1 to lag1-7 days) with hypoxic biomarkers and arterial stiffness, adjusted for confounders. Mediation analyses explored the hypoxia's role in O<sub>3</sub>-related arterial stiffness changes. We further examined effect modification by residence altitude and the robustness of results by including PM<sub>2.5</sub> (particulate matter ≤2.5 μm in aerodynamic diameter) or NO<sub>2</sub> in 2-pollutant models.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: O<sub>3</sub> exposure 1 to 7 days before visits was significantly associated with changes in multiple hypoxic biomarkers. A 10-ppb increase in O<sub>3</sub> exposure was linked to significant decreases in oxygen saturation (SpO<sub>2</sub>) and increases in red blood cell count (RBC), hemoglobin concentration, and hematocrit, with maximum changes by -0.42%, 0.92%, 0.97%, and 1.92%, respectively. Laboratory analysis of mRNA and protein markers consistently indicated that O<sub>3</sub> exposure activated the hypoxia-inducible factor 1 (HIF-1) signaling pathway. Additionally, a 10-ppb increase in O<sub>3</sub> corresponded to a 1.04% to 1.33% increase in carotid-femoral pulse wave velocity (cfPWV), indicating increased arterial stiffness. RBC, hemoglobin concentration, and hematocrit increases significantly mediated the O<sub>3</sub>-cfPWV association, whereas the SpO<sub>2</sub> reduction had an insignificant mediating effect. Associations of O<sub>3</sub> with hypoxic biomarkers varied by altitude. The higher altitude group showed delayed associations with SpO₂ and HIF-1 expression but stronger associations with RBC indices. These associations remained robust after adjusting for copollutants.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: O<sub>3</sub> exposure may reduce oxygen availability, prompting compensatory increases in red blood cells and hemoglobin, which exacerbate arterial stiffening. These findings provide new insights into the mechanisms underlying O<sub>3</sub>-induced cardiovascular injury.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846938/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39846938</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.044>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.044</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39846938</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Qiaoyi Hua</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xin Meng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wu Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yifan Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruiwei Xu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yunxiu Shi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jiajianghui Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xueling Meng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ailin Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qianqian Chai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mengshuang Sheng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuan Yao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yunfei Fan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ruohong Qiao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yi Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Teng Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yidan Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoyu Cui</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yaqi Yu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haonan Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rui Tang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Meilin Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Bu Duo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Danzeng Dunzhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhuo Ga</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lei Hou</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yingjun Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jing Shang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qi Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xinghua Qiu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chunxiang Ye</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jicheng Gong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tong Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Associations of Short-Term Ozone Exposure With Hypoxia and Arterial Stiffness</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39846938</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.11.044</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Pathogenetic Link Between Ozone Pollution and Cardiovascular Disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846937/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2025 Jan 17:S0735-1097(24)10658-4. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.011. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846937/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39846937</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.011>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.011</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39846937</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Alexandra Schneider</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kai Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Susanne Breitner</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>The Pathogenetic Link Between Ozone Pollution and Cardiovascular Disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39846937</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.011</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Worsening of Heart Failure in Outpatients With Transthyretin Amyloidosis and Cardiomyopathy in the APOLLO-B Trial</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846936/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20250126011322&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: During APOLLO-B, outpatient worsening HF in patients with transthyretin amyloidosis with cardiomyopathy was frequent, prognostic, and reduced by patisiran.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Dec 16:S0735-1097(24)10297-5. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.097. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND: Outpatient worsening heart failure (HF), defined by initiation or intensification of diuretics, is adversely prognostic for patients with either reduced or preserved ejection fraction.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">OBJECTIVES: This study sought to investigate the prognostic value of outpatient worsening HF in transthyretin amyloidosis with cardiomyopathy and the effect of patisiran treatment.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Post hoc analyses of the APOLLO-B trial (NCT03997383) evaluated the associations between outpatient worsening HF (defined by oral diuretic initiation or intensification), measures of disease progression, and a composite endpoint of all-cause mortality and cardiovascular (CV) events. We further examined the effect of patisiran on outpatient worsening HF over 24 months (ie, during the double-blind and open-label extension periods).</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: In APOLLO-B, 144 (40.1%) patients had no event, 157 (43.7%) had outpatient worsening HF, 13 (3.6%) required an urgent HF visit, 118 (32.9%) had a CV hospitalization, and 47 (13.1%) died. Outpatient worsening HF was associated with an increased risk of all-cause mortality and CV events (HR: 2.21; 95% CI: 1.58-3.08), as well as a greater deterioration in 6-minute walk test distance, Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire-Overall Summary score, and NYHA functional class and a greater increase in N-terminal prohormone of B-type natriuretic peptide. Addition of outpatient diuretic initiation or intensification to the composite endpoint of all-cause mortality and CV events increased the overall number of patients having an event from 141 to 215 (a 52% increase). Patisiran reduced the risk of outpatient worsening HF (HR: 0.70; 95% CI: 0.51-0.96) over 24 months.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: During APOLLO-B, outpatient worsening HF in patients with transthyretin amyloidosis with cardiomyopathy was frequent, prognostic, and reduced by patisiran.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39846936/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20250126011322&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">39846936</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.097>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.097</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:39846936</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Marianna Fontana</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mathew S Maurer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Julian D Gillmore</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shaun Bender</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Patrick Y Jay</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Scott D Solomon</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2025-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Worsening of Heart Failure in Outpatients With Transthyretin Amyloidosis and Cardiomyopathy in the APOLLO-B Trial</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:39846936</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.10.097</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>