<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 06:11:10 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Mitral, aortic, and tricuspid valve disease: new light shed on mechanisms, risk stratification, and treatment optimization</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484402/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Mar 14;45(11):857-860. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae146.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484402/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484402</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae146>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae146</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484402</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Mitral, aortic, and tricuspid valve disease: new light shed on mechanisms, risk stratification, and treatment optimization</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484402</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae146</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Mechanisms in Brain Fluid Biology</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484035/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The brain is a complex organ, fundamentally changing across the day to perform basic functions like sleep, thought, and regulating whole-body physiology. This requires a complex symphony of nutrients, hormones, ions, neurotransmitters and more to be properly distributed across the brain to maintain homeostasis throughout 24 hours. These solutes are distributed both by the blood and by cerebrospinal fluid. Cerebrospinal fluid contents are distinct from the general circulation because of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):711-726. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323516. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The brain is a complex organ, fundamentally changing across the day to perform basic functions like sleep, thought, and regulating whole-body physiology. This requires a complex symphony of nutrients, hormones, ions, neurotransmitters and more to be properly distributed across the brain to maintain homeostasis throughout 24 hours. These solutes are distributed both by the blood and by cerebrospinal fluid. Cerebrospinal fluid contents are distinct from the general circulation because of regulation at brain barriers including the choroid plexus, glymphatic system, and blood-brain barrier. In this review, we discuss the overlapping circadian (≈24-hour) rhythms in brain fluid biology and at the brain barriers. Our goal is for the reader to gain both a fundamental understanding of brain barriers alongside an understanding of the interactions between these fluids and the circadian timing system. Ultimately, this review will provide new insight into how alterations in these finely tuned clocks may lead to pathology.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484035/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484035</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323516>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323516</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484035</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Velia S Vizcarra</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ryann M Fame</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lauren M Hablitz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Mechanisms in Brain Fluid Biology</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484035</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323516</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Hypertension: Causes and Consequences of Circadian Rhythms in Blood Pressure</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484034/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Hypertension is extremely common, affecting approximately 1 in every 2 adults globally. Chronic hypertension is the leading modifiable risk factor for cardiovascular disease and premature mortality worldwide. Despite considerable efforts to define mechanisms that underlie hypertension, a potentially major component of the disease, the role of circadian biology has been relatively overlooked in both preclinical models and humans. Although the presence of daily and circadian patterns has been...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):810-832. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323515. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Hypertension is extremely common, affecting approximately 1 in every 2 adults globally. Chronic hypertension is the leading modifiable risk factor for cardiovascular disease and premature mortality worldwide. Despite considerable efforts to define mechanisms that underlie hypertension, a potentially major component of the disease, the role of circadian biology has been relatively overlooked in both preclinical models and humans. Although the presence of daily and circadian patterns has been observed from the level of the genome to the whole organism, the functional and structural impact of biological rhythms, including mechanisms such as circadian misalignment, remains relatively poorly defined. Here, we review the impact of daily rhythms and circadian systems in regulating blood pressure and the onset, progression, and consequences of hypertension. There is an emphasis on the impact of circadian biology in relation to vascular disease and end-organ effects that, individually or in combination, contribute to complex phenotypes such as cognitive decline and the loss of cardiac and brain health. Despite effective treatment options for some individuals, control of blood pressure remains inadequate in a substantial portion of the hypertensive population. Greater insight into circadian biology may form a foundation for novel and more widely effective molecular therapies or interventions to help in the prevention, treatment, and management of hypertension and its related pathophysiology.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484034/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484034</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323515>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323515</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484034</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Frank M Faraci</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frank A J L Scheer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Hypertension: Causes and Consequences of Circadian Rhythms in Blood Pressure</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484034</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323515</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Clock and Hypoxia</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484033/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The timing of life on Earth is remarkable: between individuals of the same species, a highly similar temporal pattern is observed, with shared periods of activity and inactivity each day. At the individual level, this means that over the course of a single day, a person alternates between two states. They are either upright, active, and communicative or they lie down in a state of (un)consciousness called sleep where even the characteristic of neuronal signals in the brain shows distinctive...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):618-634. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323518. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The timing of life on Earth is remarkable: between individuals of the same species, a highly similar temporal pattern is observed, with shared periods of activity and inactivity each day. At the individual level, this means that over the course of a single day, a person alternates between two states. They are either upright, active, and communicative or they lie down in a state of (un)consciousness called sleep where even the characteristic of neuronal signals in the brain shows distinctive properties. The circadian clock governs both of these time stamps-activity and (apparent) inactivity-making them come and go consistently at the same approximate time each day. This behavior thus represents the meeting of two pervasive systems: the circadian clock and metabolism. In this article, we will describe what is known about how the circadian clock anticipates daily changes in oxygen usage, how circadian clock regulation may relate to normal physiology, and to hypoxia and ischemia that can result from pathologies such as myocardial infarction and stroke.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484033/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484033</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323518>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323518</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484033</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Francesca Sartor</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Borja Ferrero-Bordera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey Haspel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Markus Sperandio</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paul M Holloway</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martha Merrow</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Clock and Hypoxia</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484033</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323518</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Effects on Vascular Immunopathologies</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484032/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Circadian rhythms exert a profound impact on most aspects of mammalian physiology, including the immune and cardiovascular systems. Leukocytes engage in time-of-day-dependent interactions with the vasculature, facilitating the emigration to and the immune surveillance of tissues. This review provides an overview of circadian control of immune-vascular interactions in both the steady state and cardiovascular diseases such as atherosclerosis and infarction. Circadian rhythms impact both the immune...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):791-809. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323619. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Circadian rhythms exert a profound impact on most aspects of mammalian physiology, including the immune and cardiovascular systems. Leukocytes engage in time-of-day-dependent interactions with the vasculature, facilitating the emigration to and the immune surveillance of tissues. This review provides an overview of circadian control of immune-vascular interactions in both the steady state and cardiovascular diseases such as atherosclerosis and infarction. Circadian rhythms impact both the immune and vascular facets of these interactions, primarily through the regulation of chemoattractant and adhesion molecules on immune and endothelial cells. Misaligned light conditions disrupt this rhythm, generally exacerbating atherosclerosis and infarction. In cardiovascular diseases, distinct circadian clock genes, while functioning as part of an integrated circadian system, can have proinflammatory or anti-inflammatory effects on these immune-vascular interactions. Here, we discuss the mechanisms and relevance of circadian rhythms in vascular immunopathologies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484032/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484032</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323619>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323619</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484032</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Qun Zeng</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Valeria Maria Oliva</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>María Ángeles Moro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christoph Scheiermann</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Effects on Vascular Immunopathologies</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484032</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323619</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stroke in the Time of Circadian Medicine</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484031/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Time-of-day significantly influences the severity and incidence of stroke. Evidence has emerged not only for circadian governance over stroke risk factors, but also for important determinants of clinical outcome. In this review, we provide a comprehensive overview of the interplay between chronobiology and cerebrovascular disease. We discuss circadian regulation of pathophysiological mechanisms underlying stroke onset or tolerance as well as in vascular dementia. This includes cell death...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):770-790. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323508. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Time-of-day significantly influences the severity and incidence of stroke. Evidence has emerged not only for circadian governance over stroke risk factors, but also for important determinants of clinical outcome. In this review, we provide a comprehensive overview of the interplay between chronobiology and cerebrovascular disease. We discuss circadian regulation of pathophysiological mechanisms underlying stroke onset or tolerance as well as in vascular dementia. This includes cell death mechanisms, metabolism, mitochondrial function, and inflammation/immunity. Furthermore, we present clinical evidence supporting the link between disrupted circadian rhythms and increased susceptibility to stroke and dementia. We propose that circadian regulation of biochemical and physiological pathways in the brain increase susceptibility to damage after stroke in sleep and attenuate treatment effectiveness during the active phase. This review underscores the importance of considering circadian biology for understanding the pathology and treatment choice for stroke and vascular dementia and speculates that considering a patient's chronotype may be an important factor in developing precision treatment following stroke.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484031/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484031</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323508>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323508</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484031</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Philipp Mergenthaler</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joyce S Balami</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ain A Neuhaus</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amin Mottahedin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gregory W Albers</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter M Rothwell</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey L Saver</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin E Young</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alastair M Buchan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Stroke in the Time of Circadian Medicine</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484031</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323508</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Mechanisms in Cardiovascular and Cerebrovascular Disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484030/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):615-617. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324462. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484030/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484030</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324462>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324462</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484030</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Eng H Lo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Frank M Faraci</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Mechanisms in Cardiovascular and Cerebrovascular Disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484030</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324462</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Rhythms in Cardiovascular Metabolism</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484029/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Energetic demand and nutrient supply fluctuate as a function of time-of-day, in alignment with sleep-wake and fasting-feeding cycles. These daily rhythms are mirrored by 24-hour oscillations in numerous cardiovascular functional parameters, including blood pressure, heart rate, and myocardial contractility. It is, therefore, not surprising that metabolic processes also fluctuate over the course of the day, to ensure temporal needs for ATP, building blocks, and metabolism-based signaling...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):635-658. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323520. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Energetic demand and nutrient supply fluctuate as a function of time-of-day, in alignment with sleep-wake and fasting-feeding cycles. These daily rhythms are mirrored by 24-hour oscillations in numerous cardiovascular functional parameters, including blood pressure, heart rate, and myocardial contractility. It is, therefore, not surprising that metabolic processes also fluctuate over the course of the day, to ensure temporal needs for ATP, building blocks, and metabolism-based signaling molecules are met. What has become increasingly clear is that in addition to classic signal-response coupling (termed reactionary mechanisms), cardiovascular-relevant cells use autonomous circadian clocks to temporally orchestrate metabolic pathways in preparation for predicted stimuli/stresses (termed anticipatory mechanisms). Here, we review current knowledge regarding circadian regulation of metabolism, how metabolic rhythms are synchronized with cardiovascular function, and whether circadian misalignment/disruption of metabolic processes contribute toward the pathogenesis of cardiovascular disease.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484029/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484029</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323520>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323520</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484029</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Hind Lal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Suresh Kumar Verma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yajing Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Min Xie</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin E Young</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Rhythms in Cardiovascular Metabolism</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484029</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323520</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Regulation of Cardiac Arrhythmias and Electrophysiology</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484028/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Circadian rhythms in physiology and behavior are ≈24-hour biological cycles regulated by internal biological clocks (ie, circadian clocks) that optimize organismal homeostasis in response to predictable environmental changes. These clocks are present in virtually all cells in the body, including cardiomyocytes. Many decades ago, clinicians and researchers became interested in studying daily patterns of triggers for sudden cardiac death, the incidence of sudden cardiac death, and cardiac...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):659-674. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323513. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Circadian rhythms in physiology and behavior are ≈24-hour biological cycles regulated by internal biological clocks (ie, circadian clocks) that optimize organismal homeostasis in response to predictable environmental changes. These clocks are present in virtually all cells in the body, including cardiomyocytes. Many decades ago, clinicians and researchers became interested in studying daily patterns of triggers for sudden cardiac death, the incidence of sudden cardiac death, and cardiac arrhythmias. This review highlights historical and contemporary studies examining the role of day/night rhythms in the timing of cardiovascular events, delves into changes in the timing of these events over the last few decades, and discusses cardiovascular disease-specific differences in the timing of cardiovascular events. The current understanding of the environmental, behavioral, and circadian mechanisms that regulate cardiac electrophysiology is examined with a focus on the circadian regulation of cardiac ion channels and ion channel regulatory genes. Understanding the contribution of environmental, behavioral, and circadian rhythms on arrhythmia susceptibility and the incidence of sudden cardiac death will be essential in developing future chronotherapies.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484028/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484028</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323513>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323513</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484028</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Brian P Delisle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Abhilash Prabhat</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Don E Burgess</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Makoto Ono</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Karyn A Esser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth A Schroder</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Regulation of Cardiac Arrhythmias and Electrophysiology</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484028</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323513</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Rhythms of the Blood-Brain Barrier and Drug Delivery</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484027/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is a critical interface separating the central nervous system from the peripheral circulation, ensuring brain homeostasis and function. Recent research has unveiled a profound connection between the BBB and circadian rhythms, the endogenous oscillations synchronizing biological processes with the 24-hour light-dark cycle. This review explores the significance of circadian rhythms in the context of BBB functions, with an emphasis on substrate passage through the BBB....</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):727-747. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323521. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The blood-brain barrier (BBB) is a critical interface separating the central nervous system from the peripheral circulation, ensuring brain homeostasis and function. Recent research has unveiled a profound connection between the BBB and circadian rhythms, the endogenous oscillations synchronizing biological processes with the 24-hour light-dark cycle. This review explores the significance of circadian rhythms in the context of BBB functions, with an emphasis on substrate passage through the BBB. Our discussion includes efflux transporters and the molecular timing mechanisms that regulate their activities. A significant focus of this review is the potential implications of chronotherapy, leveraging our knowledge of circadian rhythms for improving drug delivery to the brain. Understanding the temporal changes in BBB can lead to optimized timing of drug administration, to enhance therapeutic efficacy for neurological disorders while reducing side effects. By elucidating the interplay between circadian rhythms and drug transport across the BBB, this review offers insights into innovative therapeutic interventions.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484027/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484027</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323521>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323521</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484027</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Mari Kim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Richard F Keep</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shirley L Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Rhythms of the Blood-Brain Barrier and Drug Delivery</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484027</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323521</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Biology and the Neurovascular Unit</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484026/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Mammalian physiology and cellular function are subject to significant oscillations over the course of every 24-hour day. It is likely that these daily rhythms will affect function as well as mechanisms of disease in the central nervous system. In this review, we attempt to survey and synthesize emerging studies that investigate how circadian biology may influence the neurovascular unit. We examine how circadian clocks may operate in neural, glial, and vascular compartments, review how circadian...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):748-769. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323514. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Mammalian physiology and cellular function are subject to significant oscillations over the course of every 24-hour day. It is likely that these daily rhythms will affect function as well as mechanisms of disease in the central nervous system. In this review, we attempt to survey and synthesize emerging studies that investigate how circadian biology may influence the neurovascular unit. We examine how circadian clocks may operate in neural, glial, and vascular compartments, review how circadian mechanisms regulate cell-cell signaling, assess interactions with aging and vascular comorbidities, and finally ask whether and how circadian effects and disruptions in rhythms may influence the risk and progression of pathophysiology in cerebrovascular disease. Overcoming identified challenges and leveraging opportunities for future research might support the development of novel circadian-based treatments for stroke.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484026/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484026</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323514>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323514</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484026</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Wenlu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Steffen Tiedt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennifer H Lawrence</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mary E Harrington</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Erik S Musiek</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Eng H Lo</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Biology and the Neurovascular Unit</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484026</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323514</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian and Diurnal Regulation of Cerebral Blood Flow</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484025/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Circadian and diurnal variation in cerebral blood flow directly contributes to the diurnal variation in the risk of stroke, either through factors that trigger stroke or due to impaired compensatory mechanisms. Cerebral blood flow results from the integration of systemic hemodynamics, including heart rate, cardiac output, and blood pressure, with cerebrovascular regulatory mechanisms, including cerebrovascular reactivity, autoregulation, and neurovascular coupling. We review the evidence for the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):695-710. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323049. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Circadian and diurnal variation in cerebral blood flow directly contributes to the diurnal variation in the risk of stroke, either through factors that trigger stroke or due to impaired compensatory mechanisms. Cerebral blood flow results from the integration of systemic hemodynamics, including heart rate, cardiac output, and blood pressure, with cerebrovascular regulatory mechanisms, including cerebrovascular reactivity, autoregulation, and neurovascular coupling. We review the evidence for the circadian and diurnal variation in each of these mechanisms and their integration, from the detailed evidence for mechanisms underlying the nocturnal nadir and morning surge in blood pressure to identifying limited available evidence for circadian and diurnal variation in cerebrovascular compensatory mechanisms. We, thus, identify key systemic hemodynamic factors related to the diurnal variation in the risk of stroke but particularly identify the need for further research focused on cerebrovascular regulatory mechanisms.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484025/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484025</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323049>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323049</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484025</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Alastair J S Webb</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elizabeth B Klerman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emiri T Mandeville</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian and Diurnal Regulation of Cerebral Blood Flow</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484025</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323049</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Circadian Influences on Myocardial Ischemia-Reperfusion Injury and Heart Failure</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484024/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The impact of circadian rhythms on cardiovascular function and disease development is well established, with numerous studies in genetically modified animals emphasizing the circadian molecular clock's significance in the pathogenesis and pathophysiology of myocardial ischemia and heart failure progression. However, translational preclinical studies targeting the heart's circadian biology are just now emerging and are leading to the development of a novel field of medicine termed circadian...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 15;134(6):675-694. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323522. Epub 2024 Mar 14.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The impact of circadian rhythms on cardiovascular function and disease development is well established, with numerous studies in genetically modified animals emphasizing the circadian molecular clock's significance in the pathogenesis and pathophysiology of myocardial ischemia and heart failure progression. However, translational preclinical studies targeting the heart's circadian biology are just now emerging and are leading to the development of a novel field of medicine termed circadian medicine. In this review, we explore circadian molecular mechanisms and novel therapies, including (1) intense light, (2) small molecules modulating the circadian mechanism, and (3) chronotherapies such as cardiovascular drugs and meal timings. These promise significant clinical translation in circadian medicine for cardiovascular disease. (4) Additionally, we address the differential functioning of the circadian mechanism in males versus females, emphasizing the consideration of biological sex, gender, and aging in circadian therapies for cardiovascular disease.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38484024/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38484024</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323522>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323522</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38484024</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tobias Eckle</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Júlia Bertazzo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tarak Nath Khatua</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Seyed Reza Fatemi Tabatabaei</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Naghmeh Moori Bakhtiari</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lori A Walker</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tami A Martino</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Circadian Influences on Myocardial Ischemia-Reperfusion Injury and Heart Failure</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38484024</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323522</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Titin-Based Force Modulates Cardiac Thick and Thin Filaments</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38482667/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Mar 14. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323988. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38482667/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38482667</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323988>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323988</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38482667</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Anthony L Hessel</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michel N Kuehn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nichlas M Engels</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Devin L Nissen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Johanna K Freundt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weikang Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas C Irving</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wolfgang A Linke</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Titin-Based Force Modulates Cardiac Thick and Thin Filaments</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38482667</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323988</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Modelling pre-eclampsia and its cardiovascular effects</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38480793/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2024 Mar 13. doi: 10.1038/s41569-024-01006-0. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38480793/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38480793</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-024-01006-0>10.1038/s41569-024-01006-0</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38480793</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Sol Olivera</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Delyth Graham</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Modelling pre-eclampsia and its cardiovascular effects</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38480793</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-024-01006-0</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>An epigenome editing approach induces durable silencing of Pcsk9</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38480792/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Nat Rev Cardiol. 2024 Mar 13. doi: 10.1038/s41569-024-01011-3. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38480792/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38480792</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-024-01011-3>10.1038/s41569-024-01011-3</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38480792</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Irene Fernández-Ruiz</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:source>Nature reviews. Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>An epigenome editing approach induces durable silencing of Pcsk9</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38480792</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1038/s41569-024-01011-3</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Reply: Probing Sleep-Related Hypoxia's Impact on RV Dysfunction and PAH Survival: Uncertainties Clarified?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479961/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Mar 19;83(11):e109. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.014.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479961/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38479961</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.014>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.014</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38479961</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Megan M Lowery</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nicholas S Hill</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lu Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Reena Mehra</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Reply: Probing Sleep-Related Hypoxia's Impact on RV Dysfunction and PAH Survival: Uncertainties Clarified?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38479961</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.014</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Probing Sleep-Related Hypoxia's Impact on RV Dysfunction and PAH Survival: Uncertainties Clarified?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479960/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Mar 19;83(11):e107. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.035.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479960/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38479960</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.035>10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.035</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38479960</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Zhihua Huang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anqi Duan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qin Luo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhihong Liu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Probing Sleep-Related Hypoxia's Impact on RV Dysfunction and PAH Survival: Uncertainties Clarified?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38479960</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.035</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>RYR2 Variant and Sudden Death in Patients With Dilated Cardiomyopathy</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479959/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Mar 19;83(11):1105-1107. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.011.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479959/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38479959</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.011>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.011</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38479959</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Yael Ben-Haim</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martin Bird</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>David Johnson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Saidi Mohiddin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liliana Favaloro</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeppe Dyrberg Andersen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mary N Sheppard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alan Pittman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marta Futema</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Elijah R Behr</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>RYR2 Variant and Sudden Death in Patients With Dilated Cardiomyopathy</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38479959</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.011</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Restrictive Covenants and Noncompetes: An ACC Advocacy Journey</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479958/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Mar 19;83(11):1100-1104. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.002.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479958/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38479958</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.002>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.002</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38479958</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>B Hadley Wilson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Joseph E Marine</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>J Jeffrey Marshall</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Restrictive Covenants and Noncompetes: An ACC Advocacy Journey</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38479958</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.002</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Histological Typing in Patients With Cardiac Amyloidosis: JACC Review Topic of the Week</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479957/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240315021110&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cardiac amyloidosis is increasingly recognized as a treatable form of heart failure. Highly effective specific therapies have recently become available for the 2 most frequent forms of cardiac amyloidosis: immunoglobulin light chain amyloidosis and transthyretin (ATTR) amyloidosis. Nevertheless, initiation of specific therapies requires recognition of cardiac amyloidosis and appropriate characterization of the amyloid type. Although noninvasive diagnosis is possible for ATTR cardiac amyloidosis,...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Mar 19;83(11):1085-1099. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.010.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cardiac amyloidosis is increasingly recognized as a treatable form of heart failure. Highly effective specific therapies have recently become available for the 2 most frequent forms of cardiac amyloidosis: immunoglobulin light chain amyloidosis and transthyretin (ATTR) amyloidosis. Nevertheless, initiation of specific therapies requires recognition of cardiac amyloidosis and appropriate characterization of the amyloid type. Although noninvasive diagnosis is possible for ATTR cardiac amyloidosis, histological demonstration and typing of amyloid deposits is still required for a substantial number of patients with ATTR and in all patients with light chain amyloidosis and other rarer forms of cardiac amyloidosis. Amyloid histological typing can be performed using different techniques: mass spectrometry, immunohistochemistry, and immunoelectron microscopy. This review describes which patients require histological confirmation of cardiac amyloidosis along with when and how to type amyloid deposits in histologic specimens. Furthermore, it covers the characteristics and limitations of the different typing methods that are available in clinical practice.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38479957/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240315021110&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38479957</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.010>10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38479957</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Esther Gonzalez-Lopez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ellen D McPhail</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Clara Salas-Anton</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Fernando Dominguez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Morie A Gertz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Angela Dispenzieri</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Surendra Dasari</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Paolo Milani</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Laura Verga</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Martha Grogan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Giovanni Palladini</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pablo Garcia-Pavia</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:source>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</dc:source>
<dc:title>Histological Typing in Patients With Cardiac Amyloidosis: JACC Review Topic of the Week</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38479957</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.jacc.2024.01.010</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>