<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>心血管高分期刊</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240607060948
    <description>心血管高分期刊: Latest results from PubMed</description>
<atom:link href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/rss-feed/?feed_id=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414&amp;utm_source=Chrome&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;ff=20240607060948" rel="self"></atom:link>
<docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
<generator>PubMed RSS feeds (2.18.0.post9+e462414)</generator>
<language>en</language>
<lastbuilddate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 10:09:51 +0000</lastbuilddate>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<ttl>120</ttl>
<item>
<title>Focus on emerging cancer drugs, artificial intelligence applied to imaging, and a new therapeutic target in heart failure</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843882/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 7;45(22):1959-1962. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae353.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843882/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843882</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae353>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae353</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843882</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Filippo Crea</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Focus on emerging cancer drugs, artificial intelligence applied to imaging, and a new therapeutic target in heart failure</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843882</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae353</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Discovery of antimicrobial peptides in the global microbiome with machine learning</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843834/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Novel antibiotics are urgently needed to combat the antibiotic-resistance crisis. We present a machine-learning-based approach to predict antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) within the global microbiome and leverage a vast dataset of 63,410 metagenomes and 87,920 prokaryotic genomes from environmental and host-associated habitats to create the AMPSphere, a comprehensive catalog comprising 863,498 non-redundant peptides, few of which match existing databases. AMPSphere provides insights into the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 May 30:S0092-8674(24)00522-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.013. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Novel antibiotics are urgently needed to combat the antibiotic-resistance crisis. We present a machine-learning-based approach to predict antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) within the global microbiome and leverage a vast dataset of 63,410 metagenomes and 87,920 prokaryotic genomes from environmental and host-associated habitats to create the AMPSphere, a comprehensive catalog comprising 863,498 non-redundant peptides, few of which match existing databases. AMPSphere provides insights into the evolutionary origins of peptides, including by duplication or gene truncation of longer sequences, and we observed that AMP production varies by habitat. To validate our predictions, we synthesized and tested 100 AMPs against clinically relevant drug-resistant pathogens and human gut commensals both in vitro and in vivo. A total of 79 peptides were active, with 63 targeting pathogens. These active AMPs exhibited antibacterial activity by disrupting bacterial membranes. In conclusion, our approach identified nearly one million prokaryotic AMP sequences, an open-access resource for antibiotic discovery.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843834/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843834</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.013>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.013</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843834</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Célio Dias Santos-Júnior</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marcelo D T Torres</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yiqian Duan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Álvaro Rodríguez Del Río</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Thomas S B Schmidt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Chong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anthony Fullam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Michael Kuhn</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chengkai Zhu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Amy Houseman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jelena Somborski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anna Vines</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xing-Ming Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peer Bork</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jaime Huerta-Cepas</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cesar de la Fuente-Nunez</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Luis Pedro Coelho</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Discovery of antimicrobial peptides in the global microbiome with machine learning</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843834</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.013</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The ribotoxic stress response drives UV-mediated cell death</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843833/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>While ultraviolet (UV) radiation damages DNA, eliciting the DNA damage response (DDR), it also damages RNA, triggering transcriptome-wide ribosomal collisions and eliciting a ribotoxic stress response (RSR). However, the relative contributions, timing, and regulation of these pathways in determining cell fate is unclear. Here we use time-resolved phosphoproteomic, chemical-genetic, single-cell imaging, and biochemical approaches to create a chronological atlas of signaling events activated in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 May 31:S0092-8674(24)00527-0. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.018. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">While ultraviolet (UV) radiation damages DNA, eliciting the DNA damage response (DDR), it also damages RNA, triggering transcriptome-wide ribosomal collisions and eliciting a ribotoxic stress response (RSR). However, the relative contributions, timing, and regulation of these pathways in determining cell fate is unclear. Here we use time-resolved phosphoproteomic, chemical-genetic, single-cell imaging, and biochemical approaches to create a chronological atlas of signaling events activated in cells responding to UV damage. We discover that UV-induced apoptosis is mediated by the RSR kinase ZAK and not through the DDR. We identify two negative-feedback modules that regulate ZAK-mediated apoptosis: (1) GCN2 activation limits ribosomal collisions and attenuates ZAK-mediated RSR and (2) ZAK activity leads to phosphodegron autophosphorylation and its subsequent degradation. These events tune ZAK's activity to collision levels to establish regimes of homeostasis, tolerance, and death, revealing its key role as the cellular sentinel for nucleic acid damage.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843833/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843833</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.018>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.018</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843833</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Niladri K Sinha</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Connor McKenney</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Zhong Y Yeow</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jeffrey J Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ki Hong Nam</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Tomer M Yaron-Barir</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jared L Johnson</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Emily M Huntsman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Lewis C Cantley</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Alban Ordureau</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sergi Regot</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rachel Green</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>The ribotoxic stress response drives UV-mediated cell death</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843833</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.018</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Capturing totipotency in human cells through spliceosomal repression</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843832/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The cleavage of zygotes generates totipotent blastomeres. In human 8-cell blastomeres, zygotic genome activation (ZGA) occurs to initiate the ontogenesis program. However, capturing and maintaining totipotency in human cells pose significant challenges. Here, we realize culturing human totipotent blastomere-like cells (hTBLCs). We find that splicing inhibition can transiently reprogram human pluripotent stem cells into ZGA-like cells (ZLCs), which subsequently transition into stable hTBLCs after...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 Jun 3:S0092-8674(24)00519-1. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.010. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The cleavage of zygotes generates totipotent blastomeres. In human 8-cell blastomeres, zygotic genome activation (ZGA) occurs to initiate the ontogenesis program. However, capturing and maintaining totipotency in human cells pose significant challenges. Here, we realize culturing human totipotent blastomere-like cells (hTBLCs). We find that splicing inhibition can transiently reprogram human pluripotent stem cells into ZGA-like cells (ZLCs), which subsequently transition into stable hTBLCs after long-term passaging. Distinct from reported 8-cell-like cells (8CLCs), both ZLCs and hTBLCs widely silence pluripotent genes. Interestingly, ZLCs activate a particular group of ZGA-specific genes, and hTBLCs are enriched with pre-ZGA-specific genes. During spontaneous differentiation, hTBLCs re-enter the intermediate ZLC stage and further generate epiblast (EPI)-, primitive endoderm (PrE)-, and trophectoderm (TE)-like lineages, effectively recapitulating human pre-implantation development. Possessing both embryonic and extraembryonic developmental potency, hTBLCs can autonomously generate blastocyst-like structures in vitro without external cell signaling. In summary, our study provides key criteria and insights into human cell totipotency.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843832/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843832</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.010>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.010</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843832</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Shiyu Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Min Yang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Shen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Li Ding</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuehui Lyu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kexin Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jennie Ong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peng Du</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Capturing totipotency in human cells through spliceosomal repression</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843832</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.010</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Heterologous survey of 130 DNA transposons in human cells highlights their functional divergence and expands the genome engineering toolbox</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843831/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Experimental studies on DNA transposable elements (TEs) have been limited in scale, leading to a lack of understanding of the factors influencing transposition activity, evolutionary dynamics, and application potential as genome engineering tools. We predicted 130 active DNA TEs from 102 metazoan genomes and evaluated their activity in human cells. We identified 40 active (integration-competent) TEs, surpassing the cumulative number (20) of TEs found previously. With this unified comparative...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;"><b>Cell</b>. 2024 May 29:S0092-8674(24)00516-6. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.007. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Experimental studies on DNA transposable elements (TEs) have been limited in scale, leading to a lack of understanding of the factors influencing transposition activity, evolutionary dynamics, and application potential as genome engineering tools. We predicted 130 active DNA TEs from 102 metazoan genomes and evaluated their activity in human cells. We identified 40 active (integration-competent) TEs, surpassing the cumulative number (20) of TEs found previously. With this unified comparative data, we found that the Tc1/mariner superfamily exhibits elevated activity, potentially explaining their pervasive horizontal transfers. Further functional characterization of TEs revealed additional divergence in features such as insertion bias. Remarkably, in CAR-T therapy for hematological and solid tumors, Mariner2_AG (MAG), the most active DNA TE identified, largely outperformed two widely used vectors, the lentiviral vector and the TE-based vector SB100X. Overall, this study highlights the varied transposition features and evolutionary dynamics of DNA TEs and increases the TE toolbox diversity.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843831/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843831</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.007>10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.007</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843831</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Tongtong Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Shengjun Tan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Na Tang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yuanqing Li</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chenze Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Jing Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yanyan Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hui Gao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yujia Cai</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Wen Sun</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Chenxin Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Liangzheng Fu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Huijing Ma</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yachao Wu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xiaoxuan Hu</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Xuechun Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter Gee</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Weihua Yan</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yahui Zhao</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Qiang Chen</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Baocheng Guo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Haoyi Wang</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Yong E Zhang</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Cell</dc:source>
<dc:title>Heterologous survey of 130 DNA transposons in human cells highlights their functional divergence and expands the genome engineering toolbox</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843831</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1016/j.cell.2024.05.007</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Myocardial Inflammation in Heart Failure With Reduced and Preserved Ejection Fraction</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843295/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Heart failure (HF) is characterized by a progressive decline in cardiac function and represents one of the largest health burdens worldwide. Clinically, 2 major types of HF are distinguished based on the left ventricular ejection fraction (EF): HF with reduced EF and HF with preserved EF. While both types share several risk factors and features of adverse cardiac remodeling, unique hallmarks beyond ejection fraction that distinguish these etiologies also exist. These differences may explain the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1752-1766. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323659. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Heart failure (HF) is characterized by a progressive decline in cardiac function and represents one of the largest health burdens worldwide. Clinically, 2 major types of HF are distinguished based on the left ventricular ejection fraction (EF): HF with reduced EF and HF with preserved EF. While both types share several risk factors and features of adverse cardiac remodeling, unique hallmarks beyond ejection fraction that distinguish these etiologies also exist. These differences may explain the fact that approved therapies for HF with reduced EF are largely ineffective in patients suffering from HF with preserved EF. Improving our understanding of the distinct cellular and molecular mechanisms is crucial for the development of better treatment strategies. This article reviews the knowledge of the immunologic mechanisms underlying HF with reduced and preserved EF and discusses how the different immune profiles elicited may identify attractive therapeutic targets for these conditions. We review the literature on the reported mechanisms of adverse cardiac remodeling in HF with reduced and preserved EF, as well as the immune mechanisms involved. We discuss how the knowledge gained from preclinical models of the complex syndrome of HF as well as from clinical data obtained from patients may translate to a better understanding of HF and result in specific treatments for these conditions in humans.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843295/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843295</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323659>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323659</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843295</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Pilar Alcaide</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Marinos Kallikourdis</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Ramona Emig</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sumanth D Prabhu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Myocardial Inflammation in Heart Failure With Reduced and Preserved Ejection Fraction</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843295</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323659</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Repair of the Infarcted Heart: Cellular Effectors, Molecular Mechanisms and Therapeutic Opportunities</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843294/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>The adult mammalian heart has limited endogenous regenerative capacity and heals through the activation of inflammatory and fibrogenic cascades that ultimately result in the formation of a scar. After infarction, massive cardiomyocyte death releases a broad range of damage-associated molecular patterns that initiate both myocardial and systemic inflammatory responses. TLRs (toll-like receptors) and NLRs (NOD-like receptors) recognize damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) and transduce...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1718-1751. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323658. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">The adult mammalian heart has limited endogenous regenerative capacity and heals through the activation of inflammatory and fibrogenic cascades that ultimately result in the formation of a scar. After infarction, massive cardiomyocyte death releases a broad range of damage-associated molecular patterns that initiate both myocardial and systemic inflammatory responses. TLRs (toll-like receptors) and NLRs (NOD-like receptors) recognize damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) and transduce downstream proinflammatory signals, leading to upregulation of cytokines (such as interleukin-1, TNF-α [tumor necrosis factor-α], and interleukin-6) and chemokines (such as CCL2 [CC chemokine ligand 2]) and recruitment of neutrophils, monocytes, and lymphocytes. Expansion and diversification of cardiac macrophages in the infarcted heart play a major role in the clearance of the infarct from dead cells and the subsequent stimulation of reparative pathways. Efferocytosis triggers the induction and release of anti-inflammatory mediators that restrain the inflammatory reaction and set the stage for the activation of reparative fibroblasts and vascular cells. Growth factor-mediated pathways, neurohumoral cascades, and matricellular proteins deposited in the provisional matrix stimulate fibroblast activation and proliferation and myofibroblast conversion. Deposition of a well-organized collagen-based extracellular matrix network protects the heart from catastrophic rupture and attenuates ventricular dilation. Scar maturation requires stimulation of endogenous signals that inhibit fibroblast activity and prevent excessive fibrosis. Moreover, in the mature scar, infarct neovessels acquire a mural cell coat that contributes to the stabilization of the microvascular network. Excessive, prolonged, or dysregulated inflammatory or fibrogenic cascades accentuate adverse remodeling and dysfunction. Moreover, inflammatory leukocytes and fibroblasts can contribute to arrhythmogenesis. Inflammatory and fibrogenic pathways may be promising therapeutic targets to attenuate heart failure progression and inhibit arrhythmia generation in patients surviving myocardial infarction.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843294/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843294</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323658>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323658</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843294</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Ingo Hilgendorf</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Stefan Frantz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nikolaos G Frangogiannis</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Repair of the Infarcted Heart: Cellular Effectors, Molecular Mechanisms and Therapeutic Opportunities</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843294</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323658</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dissecting and Visualizing the Functional Diversity of Cardiac Macrophages</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843293/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Cardiac macrophages represent a functionally diverse population of cells involved in cardiac homeostasis, repair, and remodeling. With recent advancements in single-cell technologies, it is possible to elucidate specific macrophage subsets based on transcriptional signatures and cell surface protein expression to gain a deep understanding of macrophage diversity in the heart. The use of fate-mapping technologies and parabiosis studies have provided insight into the ontogeny and dynamics of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1791-1807. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323817. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Cardiac macrophages represent a functionally diverse population of cells involved in cardiac homeostasis, repair, and remodeling. With recent advancements in single-cell technologies, it is possible to elucidate specific macrophage subsets based on transcriptional signatures and cell surface protein expression to gain a deep understanding of macrophage diversity in the heart. The use of fate-mapping technologies and parabiosis studies have provided insight into the ontogeny and dynamics of macrophages identifying subsets derived from embryonic and adult definitive hematopoietic progenitors that include tissue-resident and bone marrow monocyte-derived macrophages, respectively. Within the heart, these subsets have distinct tissue niches and functional roles in the setting of homeostasis and disease, with cardiac resident macrophages representing a protective cell population while bone marrow monocyte-derived cardiac macrophages have a context-dependent effect, triggering both proinflammatory tissue injury, but also promoting reparative functions. With the increased understanding of the clinical relevance of cardiac macrophage subsets, there has been an increasing need to detect and measure cardiac macrophage compositions in living animals and patients. New molecular tracers compatible with positron emission tomography/computerized tomography and positron emission tomography/ magnetic resonance imaging have enabled investigators to noninvasively and serially visualize cardiac macrophage subsets within the heart to define associations with disease and measure treatment responses. Today, advancements within this thriving field are poised to fuel an era of clinical translation.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843293/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843293</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323817>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323817</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843293</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Megan Holt</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Julia Lin</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Markus Cicka</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anthony Wong</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Slava Epelman</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kory J Lavine</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Dissecting and Visualizing the Functional Diversity of Cardiac Macrophages</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843293</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323817</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Autoimmune Myocarditis, Old Dogs and New Tricks</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843292/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Autoimmunity significantly contributes to the pathogenesis of myocarditis, underscored by its increased frequency in autoimmune diseases such as systemic lupus erythematosus and polymyositis. Even in cases of myocarditis caused by viral infections, dysregulated immune responses contribute to pathogenesis. However, whether triggered by existing autoimmune conditions or viral infections, the precise antigens and immunologic pathways driving myocarditis remain incompletely understood. The emergence...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1767-1790. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323816. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Autoimmunity significantly contributes to the pathogenesis of myocarditis, underscored by its increased frequency in autoimmune diseases such as systemic lupus erythematosus and polymyositis. Even in cases of myocarditis caused by viral infections, dysregulated immune responses contribute to pathogenesis. However, whether triggered by existing autoimmune conditions or viral infections, the precise antigens and immunologic pathways driving myocarditis remain incompletely understood. The emergence of myocarditis associated with immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy, commonly used for treating cancer, has afforded an opportunity to understand autoimmune mechanisms in myocarditis, with autoreactive T cells specific for cardiac myosin playing a pivotal role. Despite their self-antigen recognition, cardiac myosin-specific T cells can be present in healthy individuals due to bypassing the thymic selection stage. In recent studies, novel modalities in suppressing the activity of pathogenic T cells including cardiac myosin-specific T cells have proven effective in treating autoimmune myocarditis. This review offers an overview of the current understanding of heart antigens, autoantibodies, and immune cells as the autoimmune mechanisms underlying various forms of myocarditis, along with the latest updates on clinical management and prospects for future research.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843292/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843292</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323816>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323816</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843292</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Taejoon Won</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Evelyn J Song</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Hannah M Kalinoski</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Javid J Moslehi</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniela Čiháková</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Autoimmune Myocarditis, Old Dogs and New Tricks</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843292</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323816</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Intersection of Immunology and Metabolism in Myocardial Disease</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843291/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Immunometabolism is an emerging field at the intersection of immunology and metabolism. Immune cell activation plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of cardiovascular diseases and is integral for regeneration during cardiac injury. We currently possess a limited understanding of the processes governing metabolic interactions between immune cells and cardiomyocytes. The impact of this intercellular crosstalk can manifest as alterations to the steady state flux of metabolites and impact...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1824-1840. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323660. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Immunometabolism is an emerging field at the intersection of immunology and metabolism. Immune cell activation plays a critical role in the pathogenesis of cardiovascular diseases and is integral for regeneration during cardiac injury. We currently possess a limited understanding of the processes governing metabolic interactions between immune cells and cardiomyocytes. The impact of this intercellular crosstalk can manifest as alterations to the steady state flux of metabolites and impact cardiac contractile function. Although much of our knowledge is derived from acute inflammatory response, recent work emphasizes heterogeneity and flexibility in metabolism between cardiomyocytes and immune cells during pathological states, including ischemic, cardiometabolic, and cancer-associated disease. Metabolic adaptation is crucial because it influences immune cell activation, cytokine release, and potential therapeutic vulnerabilities. This review describes current concepts about immunometabolic regulation in the heart, focusing on intercellular crosstalk and intrinsic factors driving cellular regulation. We discuss experimental approaches to measure the cardio-immunologic crosstalk, which are necessary to uncover unknown mechanisms underlying the immune and cardiac interface. Deeper insight into these axes holds promise for therapeutic strategies that optimize cardioimmunology crosstalk for cardiac health.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843291/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843291</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323660>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323660</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843291</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Edward B Thorp</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Anja Karlstaedt</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Intersection of Immunology and Metabolism in Myocardial Disease</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843291</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323660</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interface Between Cardioimmunology, Myocardial Health, and Disease: A Compendium</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843290/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1661-1662. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324871. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843290/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843290</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324871>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324871</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843290</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Gustavo Campos Ramos</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Daniela Čiháková</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christoph Maack</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sumanth D Prabhu</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Interface Between Cardioimmunology, Myocardial Health, and Disease: A Compendium</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843290</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.324871</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Exploring T Cell Receptor Repertoires in Myocardial Diseases</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843289/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Mounting experimental and clinical evidence has revealed that adaptive immune mechanisms targeting myocardial antigens are triggered by different forms of cardiac injury and impact disease progression. B and T lymphocytes recognize specific antigens via unique adaptive immune receptors generated through a somatic rearrangement process that generates a potential repertoire of 10^(19) unique receptors. While the adaptive immune receptor repertoire diversity provides the basis for immunologic...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1808-1823. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323661. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Mounting experimental and clinical evidence has revealed that adaptive immune mechanisms targeting myocardial antigens are triggered by different forms of cardiac injury and impact disease progression. B and T lymphocytes recognize specific antigens via unique adaptive immune receptors generated through a somatic rearrangement process that generates a potential repertoire of 10<sup>19</sup> unique receptors. While the adaptive immune receptor repertoire diversity provides the basis for immunologic specificity, making sense of it can be a challenging task. In the present review, we discuss key aspects underlying the generation of TCRs (T cell receptors) and emerging tools for their study in the context of myocardial diseases. Moreover, we outline how exploring TCR repertoires could lead to a deeper understanding of myocardial pathophysiological principles and potentially serve as diagnostic tools.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843289/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843289</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323661>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323661</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843289</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>DiyaaElDin Ashour</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Kenz Le Gouge</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Peter P Rainer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Encarnita Mariotti-Ferrandiz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gustavo Campos Ramos</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Exploring T Cell Receptor Repertoires in Myocardial Diseases</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843289</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323661</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Revisiting Cardiac Biology in the Era of Single Cell and Spatial Omics</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843288/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Throughout our lifetime, each beat of the heart requires the coordinated action of multiple cardiac cell types. Understanding cardiac cell biology, its intricate microenvironments, and the mechanisms that govern their function in health and disease are crucial to designing novel therapeutical and behavioral interventions. Recent advances in single-cell and spatial omics technologies have significantly propelled this understanding, offering novel insights into the cellular diversity and function...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1681-1702. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323672. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Throughout our lifetime, each beat of the heart requires the coordinated action of multiple cardiac cell types. Understanding cardiac cell biology, its intricate microenvironments, and the mechanisms that govern their function in health and disease are crucial to designing novel therapeutical and behavioral interventions. Recent advances in single-cell and spatial omics technologies have significantly propelled this understanding, offering novel insights into the cellular diversity and function and the complex interactions of cardiac tissue. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the cellular landscape of the heart, bridging the gap between suspension-based and emerging in situ approaches, focusing on the experimental and computational challenges, comparative analyses of mouse and human cardiac systems, and the rising contextualization of cardiac cells within their niches. As we explore the heart at this unprecedented resolution, integrating insights from both mouse and human studies will pave the way for novel diagnostic tools and therapeutic interventions, ultimately improving outcomes for patients with cardiovascular diseases.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843288/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843288</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323672>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323672</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843288</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Jack A Palmer</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Nadia Rosenthal</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Sarah A Teichmann</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Monika Litvinukova</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Revisiting Cardiac Biology in the Era of Single Cell and Spatial Omics</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843288</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323672</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cardiac Fibroblastic Niches in Homeostasis and Inflammation</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843287/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Fibroblasts are essential for building and maintaining the structural integrity of all organs. Moreover, fibroblasts can acquire an inflammatory phenotype to accommodate immune cells in specific niches and to provide migration, differentiation, and growth factors. In the heart, balancing of fibroblast activity is critical for cardiac homeostasis and optimal organ function during inflammation. Fibroblasts sustain cardiac homeostasis by generating local niche environments that support housekeeping...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1703-1717. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323892. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Fibroblasts are essential for building and maintaining the structural integrity of all organs. Moreover, fibroblasts can acquire an inflammatory phenotype to accommodate immune cells in specific niches and to provide migration, differentiation, and growth factors. In the heart, balancing of fibroblast activity is critical for cardiac homeostasis and optimal organ function during inflammation. Fibroblasts sustain cardiac homeostasis by generating local niche environments that support housekeeping functions and by actively engaging in intercellular cross talk. During inflammatory perturbations, cardiac fibroblasts rapidly switch to an inflammatory state and actively communicate with infiltrating immune cells to orchestrate immune cell migration and activity. Here, we summarize the current knowledge on the molecular landscape of cardiac fibroblasts, focusing on their dual role in promoting tissue homeostasis and modulating immune cell-cardiomyocyte interaction. In addition, we discuss potential future avenues for manipulating cardiac fibroblast activity during myocardial inflammation.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843287/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843287</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323892>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323892</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843287</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Nadine Cadosch</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Cristina Gil-Cruz</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Christian Perez-Shibayama</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Burkhard Ludewig</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>Cardiac Fibroblastic Niches in Homeostasis and Inflammation</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843287</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.124.323892</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Emerging Field of Cardioimmunology: Past, Present and Foreseeable Future</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843286/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>Over the past 30 years, the field of cardioimmunology has moved from being dismissed as a field that was chasing an epiphenomenon of little biological consequence to a scientific discipline that is providing important new insights into the immunologic basis for hypertension, atherosclerosis, myocarditis, pericarditis, autoimmune heart disease, and heart failure. In this article, we will review the conceptual insights and technical breakthroughs that have allowed the field to move forward, as...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Circ Res. 2024 Jun 7;134(12):1663-1680. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323656. Epub 2024 Jun 6.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">Over the past 30 years, the field of cardioimmunology has moved from being dismissed as a field that was chasing an epiphenomenon of little biological consequence to a scientific discipline that is providing important new insights into the immunologic basis for hypertension, atherosclerosis, myocarditis, pericarditis, autoimmune heart disease, and heart failure. In this article, we will review the conceptual insights and technical breakthroughs that have allowed the field to move forward, as well as the clinical trials in the cardioimmunology space, to provide a historical context for the articles that will appear in the compendium that is focused on the interface between cardioimmunology, myocardial function, and disease.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38843286/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38843286</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323656>10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323656</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38843286</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Douglas L Mann</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>Circulation research</dc:source>
<dc:title>The Emerging Field of Cardioimmunology: Past, Present and Foreseeable Future</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38843286</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.123.323656</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Risk prediction by ambulatory blood pressure monitoring in non-diabetic and diabetic patients: better than office measurements</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842583/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae171. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae171. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842583/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842583</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae171>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae171</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842583</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Giuseppe Mancia</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Rita Facchetti</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Guido Grassi</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Risk prediction by ambulatory blood pressure monitoring in non-diabetic and diabetic patients: better than office measurements</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842583</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae171</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Harnessing dendritic cell metabolism for healthy ageing: reducing the risk of cardiovascular disease?</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842574/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae126. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae126. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842574/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842574</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae126>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae126</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842574</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Stefanie K Wculek</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Harnessing dendritic cell metabolism for healthy ageing: reducing the risk of cardiovascular disease?</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842574</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae126</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Motherhood penalty and the gender gap in STEM and medicine</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842568/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae262. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae262. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842568/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842568</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae262>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae262</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842568</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Belinda Di Bartolo</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Isabel L Torres</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Motherhood penalty and the gender gap in STEM and medicine</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842568</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae262</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Celebrating a journey of 75 years: highlights from the Cardiological Society of India's Annual Conference of 2023</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842553/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae259. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae259. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842553/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842553</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae259>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae259</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842553</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Debabrata Roy</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Dhurjati Prasad Sinha</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Mrinalkanti Das</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Pratap Chandra Rath</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Celebrating a journey of 75 years: highlights from the Cardiological Society of India's Annual Conference of 2023</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842553</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae259</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vago-splenic signal transduction of cardioprotection in humans</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842545/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>CONCLUSIONS: In humans, vagal innervation and the spleen as a relay organ are decisive for the cardioprotective signal transduction of RIC and ATS.</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae250. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae250. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>ABSTRACT</b></p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">BACKGROUND AND AIMS: The spleen serves as an important relay organ that releases cardioprotective factor(s) upon vagal activation during remote ischaemic conditioning (RIC) in rats and pigs. The translation of these findings to humans was attempted.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">METHODS: Remote ischaemic conditioning or electrical auricular tragus stimulation (ATS) were performed in 10 healthy young volunteers, 10 volunteers with splenectomy, and 20 matched controls. Venous blood samples were taken before and after RIC/ATS or placebo, and a plasma dialysate was infused into isolated perfused rat hearts subjected to global ischaemia/reperfusion.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">RESULTS: Neither left nor right RIC or ATS altered heart rate and heart rate variability in the study cohorts. With the plasma dialysate prepared before RIC or ATS, respectively, infarct size (% ventricular mass) in the recipient rat heart was 36 ± 6% (left RIC), 34 ± 3% (right RIC) or 31 ± 5% (left ATS), 35 ± 5% (right ATS), and decreased with the plasma dialysate from healthy volunteers after RIC or ATS to 20 ± 4% (left RIC), 23 ± 6% (right RIC) or to 19 ± 4% (left ATS), 26 ± 9% (right ATS); infarct size was still reduced with plasma dialysate 4 days after ATS and 9 days after RIC. In a subgroup of six healthy volunteers, such infarct size reduction was abrogated by intravenous atropine. Infarct size reduction by RIC or ATS was also abrogated in 10 volunteers with splenectomy, but not in their 20 matched controls.</p><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:p1="http://pubmed.gov/pub-one">CONCLUSIONS: In humans, vagal innervation and the spleen as a relay organ are decisive for the cardioprotective signal transduction of RIC and ATS.</p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842545/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842545</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae250>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae250</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842545</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Helmut Raphael Lieder</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Umut Paket</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andreas Skyschally</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Andreas D Rink</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Theodor Baars</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Markus Neuhäuser</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Petra Kleinbongard</dc:creator>
<dc:creator>Gerd Heusch</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Vago-splenic signal transduction of cardioprotection in humans</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842545</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae250</dc:identifier>
</item>
<item>
<title>Leaders in cardiology: Irene Lang</title>
<link/>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842542/?utm_source=Chrome&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pubmed-2&amp;utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&amp;fc=20230708114047&amp;ff=20240607060948&amp;v=2.18.0.post9+e462414
      <description>No abstract</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><p style="color: #4aa564;">Eur Heart J. 2024 Jun 6:ehae280. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehae280. Online ahead of print.</p><p><b>NO ABSTRACT</b></p><p style="color: lightgray">PMID:<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38842542/?utm_source=Chrome&utm_medium=rss&utm_campaign=pubmed-2&utm_content=1vUePJ4Z_tESAAXKwJxBoGOTaabXd6U-NVu8003KrCpq8yLQC-&fc=20230708114047&ff=20240607060948&v=2.18.0.post9+e462414">38842542</a> | DOI:<a href=https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae280>10.1093/eurheartj/ehae280</a></p></div>]]></content:encoded>
<guid ispermalink="false">pubmed:38842542</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Judith Ozkan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2024-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>European heart journal</dc:source>
<dc:title>Leaders in cardiology: Irene Lang</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>pmid:38842542</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>doi:10.1093/eurheartj/ehae280</dc:identifier>
</item>





























</channel>
</rss>